1
00:00:38,900 --> 00:00:40,900
翻译：薄荷小瑾

2
00:00:40,900 --> 00:00:42,900
翻译：x6324

3
00:00:42,900 --> 00:00:44,900
翻译：小英的小号

4
00:00:44,900 --> 00:00:46,900
翻译：L.C.

5
00:00:46,900 --> 00:00:48,900
校对：zhanginfo

6
00:00:48,900 --> 00:00:50,900
时间轴：aaaBao

7
00:00:50,900 --> 00:00:52,900
后期：泡沫城堡

8
00:00:12,680 --> 00:00:21,310
{\pos(184.533,115.485)}距离地球600公里处  温度波动在125℃至-100℃

9
00:00:21,640 --> 00:00:29,190
{\pos(246.933,144)}声音不能传播

10
00:00:24,150 --> 00:00:29,190
{\pos(238.933,158.257)}没有气压

11
00:00:25,940 --> 00:00:29,190
{\pos(238.933,172.515)}没有氧气

12
00:00:30,400 --> 00:00:33,950
{\pos(242.666,211.01)}太空中生命无法存活

13
00:00:35,530 --> 00:00:38,870
{\pos(192.533,195.327)}地        心        引        力

14
00:01:03,640 --> 00:01:06,100
请确认置换盖第一和第二部分
Please verify that the P-one ATA removal

15
00:01:06,100 --> 00:01:09,580
P1 ATA数据已删除
on replacement cap part one and two are complete.

16
00:01:09,930 --> 00:01:13,580
存储器中M1  M2  M3  M4均已删除
DMA M-one, M-two, M-three and M-four are complete.

17
00:01:13,580 --> 00:01:16,100
收到  探索者
Okay. Copy that, Explorer.

18
00:01:17,300 --> 00:01:18,260
斯通博士  这里是休斯敦
Dr. Stone, Houston.

19
00:01:18,260 --> 00:01:22,260
医护组担心你的心电数值
Medical is concerned about your ECG readings.

20
00:01:22,260 --> 00:01:24,110
我很好  休斯敦
I'm fine, Houston.

21
00:01:24,110 --> 00:01:26,100
医护组可不这么想  博士
Well, Medical doesn't agree, Doc.

22
00:01:26,100 --> 00:01:27,120
感到恶心吗
Are you feeling nauseous?

23
00:01:27,120 --> 00:01:30,020
和平时一样  休斯敦
Not any more than usual, Houston.

24
00:01:30,020 --> 00:01:31,650
体征检测正常
Diagnostics are green.

25
00:01:32,160 --> 00:01:35,000
联接通信卡  准备数据接收
Link to communications card ready for data reception.

26
00:01:36,380 --> 00:01:38,050
如果一切顺利  我明天回去
If this works, when we touch down tomorrow,

27
00:01:38,050 --> 00:01:40,160
请你们大家喝酒
I'll buying all you guys a round of drinks.

28
00:01:40,630 --> 00:01:42,180
说定了  博士
That's a date, Doctor.

29
00:01:42,230 --> 00:01:45,290
记住  休斯敦最爱玛格丽塔
Just remember, Houston's partial to margaritas.

30
00:01:46,720 --> 00:01:48,320
启动通信卡
Booting comms card now.

31
00:01:49,370 --> 00:01:50,600
请确认
Please confirm link.

32
00:01:51,620 --> 00:01:54,200
通信失败  我们没收到数据
That's a negative, we're not seeing any data.

33
00:01:55,280 --> 00:01:57,790
稍等  休斯敦  我重启一下通信卡
Standby, Houston, I'll gonna reboot the comms card.

34
00:01:57,960 --> 00:01:59,030
待命
Standing by.

35
00:01:59,580 --> 00:02:02,170
休斯敦  我对这次任务有种不祥的预感
Houston, I have a bad feeling about this mission.

36
00:02:02,330 --> 00:02:03,940
仔细说说
Please expand.

37
00:02:04,070 --> 00:02:05,710
好的  我给你讲个事
Okay, let me tell you a story.

38
00:02:05,990 --> 00:02:07,130
96年时候
It was ninety-six.

39
00:02:07,130 --> 00:02:09,600
我在太空已经待了42天
I'd been up here for forty-two days.

40
00:02:09,610 --> 00:02:12,590
每次路过德克萨斯  都会俯视地球
Every time I passed over Texas, I looked down

41
00:02:12,590 --> 00:02:16,520
以为我太太也在仰望我  思念我
knowing that Mrs. Kowalski was looking up, thinking of me.

42
00:02:16,940 --> 00:02:19,480
整整六周我都向那女人飞吻
Six weeks I was blowing kisses at that woman.

43
00:02:19,650 --> 00:02:21,220
等我回到爱德华兹基地却发现
Then we land at Edwards and I find out 

44
00:02:21,220 --> 00:02:23,240
她跟一个律师跑了
that she's run off with this lawyer.

45
00:02:23,290 --> 00:02:26,350
-我把行李装上车  去了...-提华纳
- So, I packed my car, and I headed to... - Tijuana.

46
00:02:23,290 --> 00:02:26,350
{\an8}墨西哥西北部城市

47
00:02:26,350 --> 00:02:28,250
这事你讲过了  库沃斯基
You've told this story, Kowalski.

48
00:02:28,250 --> 00:02:29,720
休斯敦记得
As Houston recalls,

49
00:02:29,730 --> 00:02:32,340
她还开走了你那辆74年的GTO
she, uh, took off in your seventy-four GTO.

50
00:02:32,570 --> 00:02:36,150
工程组询问喷气背包燃料状况
Engineering requests fuel status on the jetpack prototype.

51
00:02:36,150 --> 00:02:40,000
出舱5小时  显示消耗30%
Five hours off the reservation and I show thirty percent drain.

52
00:02:40,000 --> 00:02:41,610
请替我赞美工程组
Give my compliments to Engineering.

53
00:02:41,610 --> 00:02:44,490
除滚轴复位有点小故障外
Except for a slight malfunction in the nulling of the roll axis,

54
00:02:44,490 --> 00:02:47,430
这喷气背包还真给力
this jetpack is one prime piece of thrust.

55
00:02:48,090 --> 00:02:49,650
工程组说谢谢你
Engineering says thank you.

56
00:02:49,650 --> 00:02:50,930
告诉他们我还是更喜欢
Tell 'em I still prefer

57
00:02:50,930 --> 00:02:52,340
我那辆67年的克尔维特跑车
my sixty-seven Corvette, though.

58
00:02:52,690 --> 00:02:53,690
说到这个  我有没有讲过...
Speaking of which, did I ever tell you...

59
00:02:53,690 --> 00:02:55,710
大家都了解你跑车那事  马特
We know the Corvette story, Matt.

60
00:02:55,930 --> 00:02:57,470
工程组也了解吗
Even Engineering?

61
00:02:57,470 --> 00:02:59,190
他们最了解
Especially Engineering.

62
00:03:00,480 --> 00:03:01,880
我们会想念你的  马特
We're going to miss you, Matt.

63
00:03:02,410 --> 00:03:06,210
-通信卡正在重启  -谢谢你  博士
- Comms card reboot in progress. - Thank you, Doctor.

64
00:03:06,450 --> 00:03:08,110
谢里夫  你那怎么样
Shariff, what's your status?

65
00:03:08,580 --> 00:03:12,600
差不多了  正在更换电池组件A1和C
Nearly there. Replacing battery module A-one and C.

66
00:03:14,290 --> 00:03:16,080
能确定些吗
Could you be a little more specific?

67
00:03:16,080 --> 00:03:18,710
休斯敦最怕这种模糊估计
Indeterminate estimates make Houston anxious.

68
00:03:18,910 --> 00:03:21,650
休斯敦  请不用担心
No, no, no. Houston. Don't be anxious.

69
00:03:21,670 --> 00:03:23,700
焦虑对心脏不好
Anxiety's not good for the heart.

70
00:03:24,290 --> 00:03:26,310
系统已做好重启准备
System is ready to reactivate.

71
00:03:27,440 --> 00:03:30,700
哈勃望远镜已启动  完成升级
Hubble telescope engaged. Upgrade fully functional.

72
00:03:31,150 --> 00:03:33,690
掌声是送给你的  谢里夫
That applause you hear is for you, Shariff.

73
00:03:33,800 --> 00:03:35,270
恭喜你  放松一下
Congratulations. Kick back,

74
00:03:35,270 --> 00:03:37,050
今天可以好好休息了
take the rest of the day off.

75
00:03:41,810 --> 00:03:43,330
马特  你能看得到
Matt, do you have a visual on just

76
00:03:43,330 --> 00:03:46,200
任务专员谢里夫在搞什么吗
what Mission Specialist Shariff is doing up there?

77
00:03:46,680 --> 00:03:49,660
他好像在跳某种庆祝舞
He appears to be doing some form of the Macarena.

78
00:03:49,930 --> 00:03:53,470
我也只能猜出这些了
But that would be just a best-guess scenario on my part.

79
00:03:53,680 --> 00:03:55,350
斯通博士  这是休斯敦
Dr. Stone, Houston. 

80
00:03:55,690 --> 00:03:57,600
医护组发现你体温已降到35.9
Medical now have you with a temperature drop to

81
00:03:57,610 --> 00:04:00,720
心率升到70了
thirty-five-point-nine and a heart-rate rise to seventy.

82
00:04:01,930 --> 00:04:05,030
-你有什么感觉  -休斯敦  我很好
- How are you feeling? - Houston, I'm fine.

83
00:04:05,360 --> 00:04:06,420
只是零重力下
It's just keeping your lunch down 

84
00:04:06,420 --> 00:04:08,700
让午饭待在胃里可不容易
in zero-G is harder than it looks.

85
00:04:09,650 --> 00:04:13,630
斯通博士  医护组问你要不要回探索者号
Dr. Stone, Medical is asking if you want to return to Explorer.

86
00:04:13,630 --> 00:04:15,590
不用  我们都来一周了  休斯敦
Negative. We're been here a week, Houston. 

87
00:04:15,590 --> 00:04:16,930
赶快弄完吧
Let's just finish this.

88
00:04:17,270 --> 00:04:20,900
-通信卡已启动  -通信失败
- Card is up. - No, that's a negative.

89
00:04:20,910 --> 00:04:23,820
这边没有显示  博士
I'll afraid we're getting nothing on this end, Doctor.

90
00:04:25,020 --> 00:04:28,260
-重试  -还是没有
- Try again. - No, still nothing.

91
00:04:30,840 --> 00:04:32,880
休斯敦  能把音乐关掉吗
Houston, can you please turn that music off?

92
00:04:32,880 --> 00:04:34,130
库沃斯基
Kowalski.

93
00:04:34,820 --> 00:04:35,970
没问题
Not a problem.

94
00:04:36,420 --> 00:04:37,810
谢谢  库沃斯基
Thank you, Kowalski.

95
00:04:41,390 --> 00:04:44,230
-现在呢  -还是不行
- Now, Houston? - That's a negative.

96
00:04:45,000 --> 00:04:47,090
是不是休斯敦读取数据有误
Could Houston be misinterpreting the data?

97
00:04:47,850 --> 00:04:50,040
我们没有收到任何数据
Well, we're not receiving any data.

98
00:04:51,070 --> 00:04:54,720
工程组建议目测一下组件是否受损
Engineering is recommending a vis-check for component damage.

99
00:04:56,120 --> 00:04:57,600
我来看看
Let me see what's going on.

100
00:04:59,010 --> 00:05:00,210
怎么回事
What have we got?

101
00:05:08,450 --> 00:05:11,120
目测未发现组件受损
Visual examination doesn't reveal any damaged components.

102
00:05:11,120 --> 00:05:13,430
问题一定出在通信面板
The problem must be originating from the comms panel.

103
00:05:14,110 --> 00:05:16,070
是的  看来如此
Yeah, that seems to be the case.

104
00:05:16,450 --> 00:05:19,780
工程组承认你之前警告过这种可能
Engineering admits that you warned us that this could happen.

105
00:05:20,360 --> 00:05:22,930
就当作他们的道歉吧
That's as close to an apology as you're going to get from them.

106
00:05:22,930 --> 00:05:24,370
我们该听取你的意见  博士
We should have listened to you, Doc.

107
00:05:24,380 --> 00:05:27,650
-开始吧  -看来得临场发挥了
- Get working. - Well, looks like we're going to have to improvise.

108
00:05:27,650 --> 00:05:31,700
-在试了  -你觉得要多久
- I'm on it. - How long do you think it'll take you?

109
00:05:31,870 --> 00:05:35,220
-一小时  -很好
- One hour. - Outstanding.

110
00:05:35,220 --> 00:05:36,040
在哈勃望远镜里
Installing your system

111
00:05:36,040 --> 00:05:37,980
安装你的系统  是本次任务的目标
in the Hubble is the purpose of this mission

112
00:05:37,980 --> 00:05:40,620
感谢你的耐心工作  博士
and so we appreciate your patience, Doctor.

113
00:05:41,150 --> 00:05:44,280
库沃斯基  我们知道你不在意这个
Kowalski, we... we know you don't care about things like this,

114
00:05:44,280 --> 00:05:45,590
也就告诉你一声
but, uh, for your information,

115
00:05:45,590 --> 00:05:47,390
这次延迟还是不足以让你打破
this delay is not gonna be long enough

116
00:05:47,390 --> 00:05:50,490
阿纳托利·索洛维约夫的太空行走纪录
for you to break Anatoly Solovyev's spacewalking record.

117
00:05:50,490 --> 00:05:53,670
-看来还得有...-不就75分钟吗
- It seems like you're gonna be left... - Seventy-five minutes shy?

118
00:05:54,130 --> 00:05:55,850
谁稀罕这个啊
Never crossed my mind.

119
00:05:56,530 --> 00:05:59,820
马特  和你合作真好
Matt... it's been a privilege.

120
00:05:59,820 --> 00:06:02,150
彼此彼此  休斯敦
Right back at you, Houston.

121
00:06:02,730 --> 00:06:04,330
享受你最后一次太空行走吧
Enjoy your last walk.

122
00:06:05,130 --> 00:06:08,390
我可以帮助斯通博士拆下通信板吗
Am I a go to assist Dr. Stone in removing the panel?

123
00:06:08,500 --> 00:06:11,220
-感谢帮助  -准许
- Assistance appreciated. - Permission granted.

124
00:06:11,220 --> 00:06:12,630
谢谢  休斯敦
Thank you, Houston.

125
00:06:13,480 --> 00:06:15,930
-可以搭把手吗  -当然
- Mind if I join the fun? - Certainly.

126
00:06:16,010 --> 00:06:17,200
感觉怎么样
How you feeling?

127
00:06:18,730 --> 00:06:21,040
就像吉娃娃被丢进甩干桶
Like a Chihuahua that's being tumble-dried.

128
00:06:21,760 --> 00:06:23,410
很难熬的一周
Well, it's been a rough week.

129
00:06:24,540 --> 00:06:25,410
这么说你可能感觉好点
If it makes you feel any better,

130
00:06:25,410 --> 00:06:26,450
我第一次来太空时
I coughed up everything

131
00:06:26,450 --> 00:06:29,050
差点把肾都吐出来
but my kidneys on my first ride.

132
00:06:29,930 --> 00:06:30,900
糟糕
Shit.

133
00:06:37,260 --> 00:06:38,320
不好意思
Sorry.

134
00:06:39,780 --> 00:06:41,560
我更习惯在医院的地下实验室
I'll used to a basement lab in a hospital 

135
00:06:41,570 --> 00:06:44,760
东西都会掉在地上  谢谢
where things fall to the floor. Thank you.

136
00:06:45,440 --> 00:06:49,140
你可是这里的天才  我只是个开车的
Well, you're the genius up here. I only drive the bus.

137
00:06:49,140 --> 00:06:51,560
别急着叫我天才
Yeah, well, call me a genius

138
00:06:51,560 --> 00:06:54,030
先看我一小时能不能把面板初始化吧
if I can get this board initialized in the next hour.

139
00:06:54,030 --> 00:06:55,790
探索者  我是休斯敦
Explorer, this is Houston.

140
00:06:55,790 --> 00:06:57,430
请讲  休斯敦
Go ahead, Houston.

141
00:06:57,430 --> 00:06:58,570
北美防空司令部称
NORAD reports

142
00:06:58,570 --> 00:07:01,440
一颗俄罗斯卫星遭导弹攻击
a Russian satellite has incurred a missile strike.

143
00:07:01,440 --> 00:07:03,570
爆炸造成大量残片
The impact has created a cloud of debris

144
00:07:03,570 --> 00:07:06,900
正以时速两万英里运动
orbiting at twenty thousand miles per hour.

145
00:07:07,120 --> 00:07:10,610
目前残片与你方轨道无重叠
Current debris orbit does not overlap with your trajectory.

146
00:07:10,610 --> 00:07:12,260
有情况会及时通知
We'll keep you posted on any developments.

147
00:07:12,260 --> 00:07:14,360
收到  休斯敦
Copy that, Houston.

148
00:07:14,870 --> 00:07:16,960
我们...用担心吗
Should we... should we be worried?

149
00:07:16,960 --> 00:07:19,910
不用  让指挥中心担心去吧
No, let's let the boys down there worry for us.

150
00:07:21,420 --> 00:07:24,260
探索者  请将机械臂伸向酬载舱
Explorer, engage arm and pivot to cargo bay.

151
00:07:24,260 --> 00:07:25,970
机械臂已就绪
Stand by for arm maneuver.

152
00:07:27,150 --> 00:07:29,730
博士  给宇航局干活
So, doc, now that you work for NASA,

153
00:07:29,730 --> 00:07:30,790
觉得我们怎么样
how do you like us?

154
00:07:30,790 --> 00:07:32,830
是不是像中头彩了
Kind of like winning the lottery, huh?

155
00:07:33,130 --> 00:07:36,290
我只是庆幸他们没有削减我研究经费
I was just happy that they didn't cut the funding to my research.

156
00:07:36,290 --> 00:07:38,750
-你训练了多久  -六个月
- How long was your training? - Six months.

157
00:07:38,750 --> 00:07:39,970
包括假期吗
Including holidays? 

158
00:07:40,510 --> 00:07:43,680
这扫描系统做什么的
So, what is this scanning system?

159
00:07:43,680 --> 00:07:44,850
没大用  马特
Oh, nothing Matt.

160
00:07:44,850 --> 00:07:47,630
只是瞭望宇宙边缘的新眼睛
It's just a new set of eyes to scan the edge of the universe.

161
00:07:47,630 --> 00:07:51,050
本来医用的  但这是样机
It's designed for hospital use, but this one's a prototype.

162
00:07:51,500 --> 00:07:52,950
等待锁合
Stand by for locking.

163
00:07:53,170 --> 00:07:56,250
他们才不会为样机提供经费
Listen, they don't bankroll prototypes.

164
00:07:56,620 --> 00:07:58,750
哪怕你有湛蓝迷人的眼睛
Even for your pretty blue eyes.

165
00:07:59,710 --> 00:08:02,150
我眼睛棕色的
Well, my eyes are brown.

166
00:08:03,980 --> 00:08:06,010
现在你眼睛是血红色的
Right now, your eyes are bloodshot.

167
00:08:06,810 --> 00:08:07,940
库沃斯基
Kowalski!

168
00:08:08,230 --> 00:08:09,870
我厉害吧
Is this great, or what?

169
00:08:15,720 --> 00:08:17,450
就这还念过哈佛呢
And to think he went to Harvard.

170
00:08:20,200 --> 00:08:21,640
不得不承认
You gotta admit one thing:

171
00:08:23,310 --> 00:08:24,540
美轮美奂
can't beat the view.

172
00:08:29,020 --> 00:08:31,020
你喜欢这里的什么
So, what do you like about being up here?

173
00:08:33,310 --> 00:08:34,590
静谧
The silence.

174
00:08:36,480 --> 00:08:38,060
恐怕会喜欢上
I could get used to it.

175
00:08:59,330 --> 00:09:00,300
真美
Terrific.

176
00:09:00,420 --> 00:09:03,830
休斯敦  初步看来  通信板已损坏
Houston, from first inspection, comms panel appears to be dead.

177
00:09:03,830 --> 00:09:05,950
需要切换至辅助板吗
Am I a go to cut link to auxiliary?

178
00:09:06,640 --> 00:09:09,100
你是专家  博士  你定
You're the expert, doctor. It's your call.

179
00:09:09,100 --> 00:09:11,520
休斯敦  我对这次任务有种不祥的预感
Houston, I have a bad feeling about this mission.

180
00:09:12,060 --> 00:09:14,550
-详说  -感觉就像
- Please elaborate. - It's the same feeling

181
00:09:14,550 --> 00:09:17,040
1987年的狂欢节
I had about Mardi Gras in 1987.

182
00:09:18,320 --> 00:09:19,640
这个不错
That is affirmative.

183
00:09:19,640 --> 00:09:20,490
真没想到
Surprisingly,

184
00:09:20,490 --> 00:09:22,780
中心还没过你狂欢节的故事
control hasn't heard the Mardi Gras story.

185
00:09:23,270 --> 00:09:24,380
请继续
Please proceed.

186
00:09:24,610 --> 00:09:27,800
狂欢节第一天  我百转千回开到波旁大街
Well, it's day one, and I'm bumping my way down Bourbon Street

187
00:09:27,800 --> 00:09:30,230
寻找一个朋友的妹妹
looking for a sister of a friend of mine.

188
00:09:31,040 --> 00:09:32,110
街上人山人海
Streets are full of people.

189
00:09:32,110 --> 00:09:34,180
我想肯定找不到那女孩了
I'm thinking there's no way I'm  gonna find this girl.

190
00:09:34,180 --> 00:09:36,520
-开始手控  -突然间
- Proceeding to override. - Then all of the sudden,

191
00:09:36,520 --> 00:09:38,520
我一看  她就在那
I look up, and there she is,

192
00:09:38,520 --> 00:09:40,830
我正要喊她  就看见她
and I'm about to yell out, and I see she's holding hands

193
00:09:40,830 --> 00:09:42,220
手牵着一个毛茸茸的矮矬男
with some short, hairy guy

194
00:09:42,220 --> 00:09:44,520
还穿着沙滩裤和花衬衫
in board shorts and a Margaritaville shirt.

195
00:09:44,770 --> 00:09:48,150
然后我意识到那根本不是男的
And then I realize that this guy is not a guy.

196
00:09:48,220 --> 00:09:50,230
那女孩儿正牵着一个...
That my girl is holding hands with a...

197
00:09:50,230 --> 00:09:51,490
国际空间站  这是休斯敦
ISS, this is Houston.

198
00:09:51,490 --> 00:09:52,520
请讲  休斯敦
Proceed, Houston.

199
00:09:52,520 --> 00:09:53,790
探索者  这是休斯敦
Explorer, this is Houston.

200
00:09:53,790 --> 00:09:54,960
请讲  休斯敦
Go ahead, Houston.

201
00:09:54,960 --> 00:09:57,980
任务中止  重复  任务中止
Mission abort. Repeat. Mission abort.

202
00:09:57,980 --> 00:09:59,890
立即撤离哈勃
Initiate emergency disconnect from Hubble.

203
00:09:59,890 --> 00:10:01,670
开始返航
Begin reentry procedure.

204
00:10:01,670 --> 00:10:04,000
国际空间站  启动紧急撤离程序
ISS, initiate emergency evacuation.

205
00:10:04,000 --> 00:10:05,660
收到  休斯敦  马上行动
Copy all, Houston, and in work.

206
00:10:05,660 --> 00:10:07,430
马特  立即返回探索者
Matt, immediate return to Explorer.

207
00:10:07,430 --> 00:10:09,460
重复  立即回舱
Repeat, immediate return to Explorer.

208
00:10:09,460 --> 00:10:10,180
收到
Copy.

209
00:10:10,190 --> 00:10:11,720
探索者  准备开启气闸
Explorer, prep airlock.

210
00:10:11,730 --> 00:10:12,750
气闸就绪
Airlock engaged,

211
00:10:12,750 --> 00:10:14,590
-可以进入  -休斯敦  请明示
- ready to receive. - Houston, elaborate.

212
00:10:14,590 --> 00:10:17,530
导弹击中的残片引起连锁反应
Debris from the missile strike has caused a chain reaction,

213
00:10:17,530 --> 00:10:20,380
撞击到其他卫星  形成更多残片
hitting other satellites and creating new debris.

214
00:10:20,380 --> 00:10:22,470
正以超过子弹的速度
Traveling faster than a high-speed bullet

215
00:10:22,480 --> 00:10:24,090
向你们的轨道飞去
up towards your altitude.

216
00:10:24,090 --> 00:10:25,850
-是否收到  -收到
- All copy? - Copy all.

217
00:10:25,910 --> 00:10:28,670
-关闭  斯通博士  -不行
- Put a bow on it, Dr. Stone. - I can't.

218
00:10:28,980 --> 00:10:30,640
通信板正在初始化
The board is still initializing.

219
00:10:30,640 --> 00:10:32,480
别让我说第二遍
I'll not gonna ask you again.

220
00:10:32,480 --> 00:10:35,660
-稍等  -不能等  快
- One second. - Not one second. Now.

221
00:10:35,670 --> 00:10:36,870
关掉
Shut it down.

222
00:10:37,500 --> 00:10:38,380
这是命令
That's an order.

223
00:10:38,380 --> 00:10:41,000
对不起  真对不起
Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.

224
00:10:41,010 --> 00:10:42,030
好了  就好了
I'm done. I'm done.

225
00:10:42,030 --> 00:10:44,760
库沃斯基  请立即撤离哈勃
Kowalski, initiate emergency disconnect from the Hubble.

226
00:10:44,760 --> 00:10:46,240
好吧  谢里夫  我们走
All right, Shariff, let's do this.

227
00:10:46,240 --> 00:10:47,200
收到  马特
Roger, Matt.

228
00:10:47,370 --> 00:10:48,530
休斯敦  怎么样了
Houston, update.

229
00:10:48,530 --> 00:10:50,750
已引起强烈连锁反应
Well, we have a full-on chain reaction.

230
00:10:50,770 --> 00:10:53,440
经证实  俄罗斯击毁一枚己方卫星
It's been confirmed that it's the unintentional side effect

231
00:10:53,440 --> 00:10:56,080
引发了意外后果
of the Russians striking one of their own satellites.

232
00:10:56,080 --> 00:10:58,920
-他们打了自己的卫星  -人家自己事
- They shot down their own satellite? - Right of disposal.

233
00:10:58,920 --> 00:11:02,090
可能是弃用的间谍卫星  这下变开花弹了
Most likely a spy sat gone bad. Now it's shrapnel.

234
00:11:02,090 --> 00:11:04,040
探索者  准备脱离哈勃望远镜
Explorer, ready to disengage HST.

235
00:11:04,040 --> 00:11:07,270
解锁倒计时  3  2  1
Locks releasing in three... two... one. 

236
00:11:08,200 --> 00:11:10,230
探索者  有新数据
Explorer, new data coming through.

237
00:11:10,800 --> 00:11:13,490
-什么情况  休斯敦  -不太妙
- What's the blowback, Houston? - It's not good.

238
00:11:13,500 --> 00:11:15,250
大部分系统已瘫痪
Most of our systems are gone.

239
00:11:15,490 --> 00:11:19,090
残片连锁反应失控并飞速扩散
Debris chain reaction is out of control and rapidly expanding.

240
00:11:19,120 --> 00:11:21,990
多颗卫星受波及坠毁
Multiple satellites are down, and they keep on falling.

241
00:11:21,990 --> 00:11:25,100
-多颗是指几个  -基本都完了
- Define "Multiple satellites." - Most of them are gone.

242
00:11:25,120 --> 00:11:27,390
通信系统也已瘫痪
Telecommunication systems are dead.

243
00:11:27,400 --> 00:11:29,810
信号随时可能中断
Expect a communication blackout at any moment.

244
00:11:29,810 --> 00:11:31,950
库沃斯基  九点钟方向发现残片
Kowalski, visual of debris at nine o'clock.

245
00:11:31,950 --> 00:11:34,090
半个北美都上不去脸书了
Half of North America just lost their Facebook.

246
00:11:34,560 --> 00:11:37,530
探索者号  重复  通讯信号随时可能
Explorer, repeat, expect a communication blackout

247
00:11:37,530 --> 00:11:38,850
全面中断
at any moment.

248
00:11:39,070 --> 00:11:42,140
-收到  休斯顿  -探索者号  这里是库沃斯基
- Copy that, Houston. - Explorer, this is Kowalski,

249
00:11:42,140 --> 00:11:44,490
目击确认残片飞来
confirming visual contact with debris.

250
00:11:44,490 --> 00:11:46,550
-残片来自某广播卫星  -当心
- Debris is from a BSE sat. - Heads up!

251
00:11:46,550 --> 00:11:50,300
-重复  我看到...-斯通博士请求快速返舱
- To repeat, I have... - Dr. Stone requesting faster transport.

252
00:11:50,340 --> 00:11:51,980
我们得赶快撤离  快  快
We have to go. We have to go, go, go!

253
00:11:51,980 --> 00:11:55,360
肯尼迪中心报告气象条件不适宜返回地球
Kennedy reports meteorological conditions no-go for re-entry.

254
00:11:55,870 --> 00:11:57,700
休斯顿  这里是探索者号  请回复
Houston, Explorer. Copy.

255
00:11:57,700 --> 00:12:00,840
探索者号  斯通博士请求快速返舱
Explorer, Dr. Stone requesting faster transport to bay area.

256
00:12:00,840 --> 00:12:02,080
探索者号  听到吗
Explorer, do you copy?

257
00:12:02,080 --> 00:12:04,090
探索者号  请求带回斯通博士
Explorer, permission to retrieve Dr. Stone.

258
00:12:04,090 --> 00:12:05,370
批准执行  库沃斯基
You're a go, Kowalski.

259
00:12:06,070 --> 00:12:08,420
休斯顿  这里是探索者号  请回复
Houston, this is Explorer, copy.

260
00:12:08,840 --> 00:12:12,640
-我来了  -休斯顿失去联络  休斯顿失去联络
- All right. - We've lost Houston. We're lost Houston.

261
00:12:12,690 --> 00:12:15,850
-解开脐带  我们得马上撤离  -明白
- Unstrap. Look, we need to get the hell out of here. - All right.

262
00:12:15,850 --> 00:12:16,560
马特  要帮忙吗
Need some help there, Matt?

263
00:12:16,560 --> 00:12:18,710
-不  别等我们  -卡住了
- No, don't wait for us. - It's stuck!

264
00:12:19,240 --> 00:12:22,010
-人员伤亡  人员伤亡  -休斯顿  这里是探索者号  请回复
- Man down! Man down! - Houston, this is Explorer, copy. 

265
00:12:22,380 --> 00:12:26,280
休斯顿  这里是探索者号  请回复  库沃斯基  报...
Houston, this is Explorer, copy. Kowalski, repor...

266
00:12:28,210 --> 00:12:30,790
探索者号被撞击  探索者号  听到吗
Explorer's been hit! Explorer, do you read?

267
00:12:31,530 --> 00:12:33,750
探索者号  探索者
Explorer! Explorer!

268
00:12:35,870 --> 00:12:39,840
宇航员和机体脱离  斯通博士脱离
Astronaut is off structure! Dr. Stone is off structure!

269
00:12:39,840 --> 00:12:41,590
-斯通博士  解开搭扣  -不
- Dr. Stone, detach! - No! 

270
00:12:41,590 --> 00:12:42,700
你必须解开
You must detach!

271
00:12:42,700 --> 00:12:45,500
再不解开会被机械臂带走
If you don't detach, that arm's gonna carry you too far!

272
00:12:45,500 --> 00:12:47,880
听我说  集中精神
Listen to my voice! You need to focus!

273
00:12:47,880 --> 00:12:49,120
我快看不到你了
I'm losing visual of you.

274
00:12:49,120 --> 00:12:51,130
再过一会儿我就找不到你了
In a few seconds, I won't be able to track you.

275
00:12:51,130 --> 00:12:54,140
快解开搭扣  看不见你了
You need to detach! I can't see you anymore!

276
00:12:54,140 --> 00:12:58,280
-快动手  -我在弄  正在弄
- Do it now! - I'll trying! I'll trying! I'll trying!

277
00:12:58,290 --> 00:13:00,910
休斯顿  斯通博士脱离视野范围
Houston, I've lost visual of Dr. Stone.

278
00:13:02,300 --> 00:13:04,830
休斯顿  斯通博士脱离视野范围
Houston, I've lost visual of Dr. Stone.

279
00:13:13,020 --> 00:13:16,760
斯通博士  听到吗  重复  听到吗
Dr. Stone, do you copy? Repeat, do you copy?

280
00:13:16,760 --> 00:13:19,270
-能  能听到  我解开了  -报告位置
- Yes, yes, yes. I copy! I'm detached! - Give me your position.

281
00:13:19,270 --> 00:13:23,330
我不知道  不知道  我在旋转  没办法  没办...
I don't know! I don't know! I'll spinning! I can't... I can't...

282
00:13:23,330 --> 00:13:27,240
-报告位置  -GPS失灵  无法使用
- Report your position. - GPS is down. It's down, I can't...

283
00:13:27,550 --> 00:13:30,780
-报告视野  -跟你说了不知道  什么都看不见
- Give me a visual. - I told you, nothing. I see nothing!

284
00:13:30,780 --> 00:13:32,390
能看见探索者号吗
Do you have a visual of Explorer?

285
00:13:32,390 --> 00:13:34,900
-不能  -国际空间站呢  -看不见
- No. No. - Do you have a visual of ISS? - No.

286
00:13:34,900 --> 00:13:35,730
集中精神
You need to focus. 

287
00:13:35,730 --> 00:13:37,990
什么都行  太阳  地球  给我一个参照物
Anything, use the sun and the Earth, give me coordinates.

288
00:13:37,990 --> 00:13:40,870
-我喘不过气了  -快给我参照物
- I can't breathe! I can't breathe! - Give me coordinates! 

289
00:13:41,690 --> 00:13:43,590
斯通博士  听到吗
Dr. Stone, do you copy?

290
00:13:44,370 --> 00:13:45,620
重复  能听到吗
Repeat, do you copy?

291
00:13:46,850 --> 00:13:50,380
报告位置  快报告你的位置
Give me your position! Report your position.

292
00:13:51,080 --> 00:13:52,770
你能否看见探索者号
Do you have a visual of Explorer?

293
00:13:53,930 --> 00:13:55,540
或者国际空间站
Do you have a visual of ISS?

294
00:13:56,430 --> 00:13:58,080
请集中精神  任何参照物都行
I need you to focus. Anything.

295
00:13:58,650 --> 00:14:01,470
太阳或者地球  请报告参照物
Use the sun and the Earth, give me coordinates.

296
00:14:01,470 --> 00:14:02,740
报告参照物
Give me coordinates.

297
00:14:38,390 --> 00:14:40,510
库沃斯基  库沃斯基  听到吗
Kowalski? Kowalski, do you copy?

298
00:14:42,450 --> 00:14:45,870
库沃斯基  我...库沃斯基  我看到了
Kowalski... I have... have a vis... Kowalski, I have a visual.

299
00:14:46,400 --> 00:14:48,650
视野范围内...可见探索者号
I have... have a visual of Explorer.

300
00:14:49,350 --> 00:14:52,730
在我的北...正北方向
With north at... twelve o'clock

301
00:14:53,380 --> 00:14:56,540
太空舱位于我和探索者号的中点
and the shuttle is at the center of the dial.

302
00:14:58,900 --> 00:15:01,120
还能看到...中国空间站
I can see... I can see the Chinese station.

303
00:15:01,720 --> 00:15:04,570
不对  是国际空间站
No, it's the International Space Station.

304
00:15:05,550 --> 00:15:06,860
空间站位于
ISS is at...

305
00:15:08,450 --> 00:15:10,300
我七点钟方向
ISS is at seven o'clock.

306
00:15:18,860 --> 00:15:20,530
库沃斯基中尉  能听到吗
Lieutenant Kowalski, do you copy?

307
00:15:26,660 --> 00:15:28,740
探索者号  能...能听到吗
Explorer, do you... do you copy?

308
00:15:37,730 --> 00:15:39,470
休斯顿  能听到吗
Houston, do you copy?

309
00:15:44,300 --> 00:15:47,430
休斯顿  这里是任务专员莱恩·斯通
Houston, this is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone.

310
00:15:47,430 --> 00:15:49,890
我已脱离船体  正在飘浮
I am off structure and I am drifting.

311
00:15:49,900 --> 00:15:51,120
请回复
Do you copy?

312
00:15:57,780 --> 00:15:58,770
听到吗
Anyone?

313
00:16:03,360 --> 00:16:04,350
有人听到吗
Anybody?

314
00:16:07,280 --> 00:16:08,460
有人在吗
Do you copy?

315
00:16:12,870 --> 00:16:13,920
请求回复
Please copy.

316
00:16:16,740 --> 00:16:17,670
拜托了
Please.

317
00:16:37,830 --> 00:16:41,160
-斯通博士  听到吗  -能  库沃斯基中尉  听到了
- Dr. Stone, do you copy? - Yeah, Lieutenant Kowalski, yes.

318
00:16:41,160 --> 00:16:42,470
喂喂  库沃斯基中尉  我在这儿
Yes, Lieutenant Kowalski, I'm here,

319
00:16:42,470 --> 00:16:43,410
-在这儿  -重复  听到吗
- I'm here. - Repeat, do you copy?

320
00:16:43,410 --> 00:16:46,970
-听到  我在这儿  这儿啊  -快闪灯
- Yes, yes, I copy, I'm here! I'm here. - Flash your light.

321
00:16:47,540 --> 00:16:49,810
-灯  什么灯  -闪灯让我看到你
- My light... my light? - Flash it so I can see you.

322
00:16:50,170 --> 00:16:51,870
好的
Okay. Uh...

323
00:16:53,060 --> 00:16:53,910
我的灯
I...

324
00:16:53,920 --> 00:16:58,400
-闪了  我在闪  这里这里  -看到你了
- Okay, okay. Here, here! I'll here! - There you are.

325
00:16:58,420 --> 00:17:01,340
保持闪烁  报告状态
Hang on tight. Report your status.

326
00:17:01,830 --> 00:17:04,030
没事  没事  我很好
I'll fine, I'll fine. I'll all right.

327
00:17:04,030 --> 00:17:05,960
报告你的状态  体征数值
Your status. Give me your readings.

328
00:17:06,300 --> 00:17:09,850
{\an8}PSI指"磅/平方吋"  太空服健康内压应不大于4.3

329
00:17:06,300 --> 00:17:09,850
PSI数值是3...3.6
Three... three... three point six PSI.

330
00:17:10,690 --> 00:17:12,610
剩余氧量  氧量还有多少
Your O2, give me your O2.

331
00:17:12,890 --> 00:17:15,550
在下降  下降很快
Oxygen is going down. It's going down fast.

332
00:17:15,550 --> 00:17:16,690
非常快  9
It's going down fast. Nine...

333
00:17:17,570 --> 00:17:18,860
不  只有8%了
No. No, eight-eight percent.

334
00:17:18,860 --> 00:17:20,380
-你呼吸太急促  -8  降到8%了
- Okay, you're breathing too fast. - Eight... it's going down eight percent.

335
00:17:20,390 --> 00:17:22,810
你耗氧太快  得减缓
You're burning oxygen, and we don't want to do that.

336
00:17:22,810 --> 00:17:26,870
-放轻松明白吗  -抱歉  明白了
- We want to relax. Copy? - Okay, sorry. Yes, copy, copy.

337
00:17:26,870 --> 00:17:28,960
-离你很近了  -请快点
- All right. Nearly there. - Please hurry.

338
00:17:30,600 --> 00:17:34,690
-灯可以插好了  斯通博士  -抱歉  抱歉
- You can holster that torch, Dr. Stone. - Sorry. Sorry.

339
00:17:39,370 --> 00:17:43,450
抓住你了  好嘞  我得把你拴上
Gotcha. All right, now I'll gonna tether you to me.

340
00:17:45,670 --> 00:17:48,890
没发现我其实这么玉树临风潇洒帅气吧
I know, you never realized how devastatingly good-looking I am.

341
00:17:49,250 --> 00:17:52,710
别盯着我看了  搭把手让我把你拴起来
But I need you to stop staring and help me with the tether.

342
00:17:53,240 --> 00:17:56,220
-明白了吗  -明白  明白
- Okay? - Okay, okay.

343
00:17:57,340 --> 00:17:58,330
明白了
I got it.

344
00:17:59,250 --> 00:18:02,020
好  这就行了
All right, here we go. All right.

345
00:18:02,030 --> 00:18:03,560
为了避免你被气喷到
Now, to clear you from the jets...

346
00:18:03,560 --> 00:18:04,660
得把你推开一段距离
I'll gonna give you a little push.

347
00:18:04,660 --> 00:18:06,120
-别  不要  -我不使劲
- No, no, no, no. No, no, no. - Not a push.

348
00:18:06,120 --> 00:18:07,290
-别  别推  -轻轻一下
- No, no. - A nudge.

349
00:18:07,290 --> 00:18:10,580
别  别  不要啊  混蛋  别推  别推我
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no! Damn it, no! No!

350
00:18:18,320 --> 00:18:20,870
瞧  丢不了你吧
See? Where you go, I go.

351
00:18:26,640 --> 00:18:27,650
好多了
Better.

352
00:18:28,980 --> 00:18:30,070
撤离吧
Let's get outta here.

353
00:18:32,570 --> 00:18:34,980
-真是该死  -我理解你的心情
- Goddamn it. - I know what you mean.

354
00:18:35,880 --> 00:18:38,460
-该死  -你耗氧又快了
- Damn it. - You're burning oxygen.

355
00:18:39,370 --> 00:18:43,040
先返回太空舱如何  请回复
We're going back to the shuttle. How's that for a plan? Copy?

356
00:18:43,110 --> 00:18:45,850
-操  -好滴  收到
- Fuck! - Right. Copy that.

357
00:18:46,620 --> 00:18:48,390
休斯顿  能否通联  这里是库沃斯基
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.

358
00:18:48,400 --> 00:18:50,740
斯通博士和我准备返回基地
Dr. Stone and I are gonna make our way back to base.

359
00:18:50,740 --> 00:18:53,880
请求探索者号打开气闸  能听到吗
Can you get the Explorer to prepare the airlock for arrival? Copy?

360
00:18:55,320 --> 00:18:57,750
休斯顿  这里是库沃斯基  能否听到
Houston, this is... Kowalski. How do you copy?

361
00:18:58,920 --> 00:19:01,030
休斯顿  能否通联  这里是库沃斯基
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.

362
00:19:01,590 --> 00:19:03,420
-他们听不到的  -这可说不准
- They can't hear us. - We don't know that.

363
00:19:03,420 --> 00:19:04,930
所以要不断尝试
That's why we keep talking.

364
00:19:05,090 --> 00:19:07,990
万一有人收到信号  你就能得救
If somebody is listening, they might just save your life.

365
00:19:08,630 --> 00:19:12,550
-设置倒计时90分钟  -为什么是90
- Set your watch for ninety minutes. - Why ninety?

366
00:19:12,560 --> 00:19:13,640
休斯顿测出
Well, Houston clocked

367
00:19:13,640 --> 00:19:16,030
残片时速为5万英里
that debris at fifty thousand miles an hour.

368
00:19:16,220 --> 00:19:17,650
以我们现处的轨道计算
If you factor in our current orbit,

369
00:19:17,650 --> 00:19:19,450
大约再过90分钟
then I figure we got about ninety minutes

370
00:19:19,450 --> 00:19:21,420
就会再次遭到残片袭击
before we get our asses kicked again.

371
00:19:21,460 --> 00:19:25,270
-氧气含量降到6%了  -收到
- O2 down to six percent. - Okay.

372
00:19:25,430 --> 00:19:28,150
没了脐带飘在太空很吓人吧
Pretty scary shit being untethered up here, isn't it?

373
00:19:29,810 --> 00:19:34,150
-没错  吓到死  -你表现很出色
- Yeah, pretty scary shit. - Well, you did all right.

374
00:19:37,290 --> 00:19:39,090
其实你也不赖
Well, you weren't so bad yourself.

375
00:19:43,210 --> 00:19:45,500
休斯顿  能否通联  这里是库沃斯基
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.

376
00:19:45,850 --> 00:19:48,520
我们当前位置大约
Our current location is approximately

377
00:19:48,520 --> 00:19:51,310
距离探索者号900米
nine hundred meters out from the Explorer.

378
00:19:51,870 --> 00:19:53,020
斯通博士和我准备
Dr. Stone and I would like to

379
00:19:53,020 --> 00:19:56,410
搜寻任务专员谢里夫的遗体
retrieve the body of Mission Specialist Shariff

380
00:19:56,590 --> 00:20:00,230
带回太空舱  可以执行吗
and return it to the shuttle. Am I a go to retrieve?

381
00:20:03,060 --> 00:20:06,410
-收到  -他在哪儿
- Roger that. - Where is he? Where is he?

382
00:20:33,980 --> 00:20:35,710
天啊  天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.

383
00:20:40,530 --> 00:20:41,480
抓住他
Grab him!

384
00:20:44,990 --> 00:20:47,810
-快抓住他  -我在抓  在抓
- Grab him! - I'll trying, I'll trying!

385
00:20:52,830 --> 00:20:54,960
-你把我带开了  -抓...抓着他了
- You're pulling me away. - Got... I got him!

386
00:20:55,170 --> 00:20:56,430
像情人那样抱住他
Clutch him like he's your Valentine.

387
00:20:56,430 --> 00:20:57,370
抓住了  抓住他了
I got him. Okay. I got him.

388
00:20:57,380 --> 00:21:00,410
你们这么晃荡我没法推进
I can't engage my thrust with you two yo-yoing around.

389
00:21:30,950 --> 00:21:32,410
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.

390
00:21:33,280 --> 00:21:36,000
希望你们买够了保险  休斯顿
Here's hoping you have a hell of an insurance policy, Houston.

391
00:21:36,400 --> 00:21:40,640
探索者号毁坏十分严重
The damages to Explorer are catastrophic.

392
00:21:41,160 --> 00:21:42,980
准备搜寻幸存者
Will commence search for survivors.

393
00:21:42,980 --> 00:21:44,910
氧量降至5%
O2 down to five percent.

394
00:21:45,780 --> 00:21:47,610
要撞上了  当心舱沿
All right, here we go. Careful of the edges!

395
00:21:56,800 --> 00:21:58,110
抓住我
Here. Here!

396
00:22:50,140 --> 00:22:52,010
休斯顿  能否通联  请确认
Houston, in the blind. To confirm.

397
00:22:52,790 --> 00:22:54,620
任务专员斯通博士
Mission Specialist Dr. Stone 

398
00:22:54,620 --> 00:22:56,320
以及任务指挥官马修·库沃斯基
and Mission Commander Matthew Kowalski

399
00:22:56,320 --> 00:22:59,720
是STS-157仅有的幸存者
are the sole survivors of the STS-one-five-seven.

400
00:23:02,370 --> 00:23:04,010
之前没听你的很抱歉
I apologize for not complying.

401
00:23:04,010 --> 00:23:06,420
你下令时我就该放手的
I should're stopped working as soon as you instructed me to.

402
00:23:06,420 --> 00:23:08,240
我们终究躲不过残片撞击
We were gonna get hit no matter what.

403
00:23:08,440 --> 00:23:10,280
你怎么做都无济于事
There was nothing you could do to change that.

404
00:23:14,950 --> 00:23:15,470
嘿
Hey.

405
00:23:16,250 --> 00:23:17,370
怎么
Yes?

406
00:23:17,800 --> 00:23:21,600
我们得想办法去空间站
All right, we have to make our way to the Space Station.

407
00:23:23,080 --> 00:23:24,060
那边
Over there.

408
00:23:25,910 --> 00:23:29,220
这路有点远  但必须借助那边的逃生舱
It's a bit of a hike, but we need to use their escape pod,

409
00:23:29,220 --> 00:23:31,240
联盟号  才能返回地球
the Soyuz, to get back to Earth.

410
00:23:31,630 --> 00:23:32,620
可以吗
Agreed?

411
00:23:34,450 --> 00:23:37,460
斯通博士  行吗
Dr. Stone, agreed?

412
00:23:38,870 --> 00:23:42,830
-好的  -请吧
- Agreed. - All right. After you.

413
00:23:45,050 --> 00:23:46,040
天啊
Oh, God.

414
00:23:56,120 --> 00:23:58,300
休斯顿  能否通联  这里是库沃斯基
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.

415
00:23:58,810 --> 00:24:02,430
斯通博士和我决定前往国际空间站
Dr. Stone and I have determined to proceed to ISS

416
00:24:02,560 --> 00:24:05,420
利用联盟号飞船重返地球
and use one of their Soyuz for re-entry.

417
00:24:06,340 --> 00:24:08,290
空间站  能收到吗
ISS, if you hear us...

418
00:24:09,360 --> 00:24:11,080
我们亟需救援
we could sure use a rescue mission.

419
00:24:25,470 --> 00:24:29,120
-氧量2%了  -快到了
- O2 down to two percent. - We're getting there.

420
00:24:30,800 --> 00:24:32,230
很美  你觉得呢
Beautiful, don't you think?

421
00:24:33,980 --> 00:24:35,000
什么
What?

422
00:24:35,600 --> 00:24:36,770
日出
The sunrise.

423
00:24:38,740 --> 00:24:40,610
最怀念这个了
That's what I'll gonna miss the most.

424
00:24:45,930 --> 00:24:48,020
你哪儿的人  斯通博士
So where's home, Dr. Stone?

425
00:24:51,300 --> 00:24:53,180
莱恩  你家在哪儿
Ryan, where's home?

426
00:24:55,300 --> 00:24:56,300
家
Home?

427
00:24:57,460 --> 00:25:00,210
下面  地球那个家
Down there. Mother Earth.

428
00:25:01,320 --> 00:25:02,730
你住哪儿
Where do you pitch you tent?

429
00:25:06,270 --> 00:25:09,640
-苏黎世湖区  -那是什么地方
- Lake Zurich. - Where the hell is that?

430
00:25:13,060 --> 00:25:15,460
-伊利诺斯州  -伊州啊
- Illinois. - Illinois.

431
00:25:15,530 --> 00:25:16,900
中部时区
Central Time Zone.

432
00:25:18,350 --> 00:25:19,980
那就差不多是晚上
That would make it roughly...

433
00:25:21,020 --> 00:25:22,180
八点样子
eight PM.

434
00:25:22,710 --> 00:25:25,800
那边人们晚上八点都干嘛呢
What are the good people of Lake Zurich doing at eight o'clock?

435
00:25:27,410 --> 00:25:28,460
不知道
I don't know.

436
00:25:29,330 --> 00:25:31,610
我过不去了  会拖累你的
I'm not gonna make it. I'm slowing you down.

437
00:25:31,960 --> 00:25:33,280
你平时这会儿都干嘛
What would you be doing?

438
00:25:36,330 --> 00:25:39,870
跟我说说  莱恩  八点钟
Come on, Ryan. It's eight o'clock.

439
00:25:40,570 --> 00:25:43,540
是不是医院18小时的班终于结束了
You've just left the hospital after an eighteen-hour shift.

440
00:25:44,560 --> 00:25:45,790
开车回家
Driving home.

441
00:25:49,480 --> 00:25:50,460
广播
The radio.

442
00:25:52,740 --> 00:25:56,410
-我在听广播  -这就对了
- I listen to the radio. - There we go.

443
00:25:56,510 --> 00:25:57,480
我猜猜
Let me guess.

444
00:25:57,480 --> 00:26:01,840
听国广  古典音乐  还是爬行榜
NPR? Classical? Top forty?

445
00:26:05,420 --> 00:26:08,860
无所谓  只要主持人不废话  我只管开车
Anything. I don't care, as long as they don't talk. I just drive.

446
00:26:11,600 --> 00:26:13,270
开车去哪儿呢
And where are you driving to?

447
00:26:16,210 --> 00:26:20,080
-就是开车而已  -下面有你想念的东西吗
- I just drive. - What do you miss down there?

448
00:26:22,080 --> 00:26:23,560
结婚了吗
Is there a Mr. Stone?

449
00:26:25,470 --> 00:26:28,260
-没  -没特别的人吗
- No. - Nobody special?

450
00:26:31,640 --> 00:26:35,190
没人在地球上仰望天空  想着你吗
Somebody down there looking up, thinking about you?

451
00:26:37,970 --> 00:26:38,950
莱恩
Ryan?

452
00:26:46,280 --> 00:26:47,540
我曾有个女儿
I had a daughter.

453
00:26:58,680 --> 00:26:59,830
那年她四岁
She was four.

454
00:27:02,810 --> 00:27:04,890
在学校捉迷藏
She was at school playing tag.

455
00:27:04,890 --> 00:27:07,190
滑倒撞了头  就走了
Slipped, hit her head, and that was it.

456
00:27:10,030 --> 00:27:11,420
不堪回首
Stupidest thing.

457
00:27:18,120 --> 00:27:20,430
我开车时接的电话
I was driving when I got the call, so...

458
00:27:22,000 --> 00:27:24,020
从那以后  我就成这样了
Ever since then, that's what I do.

459
00:27:25,500 --> 00:27:26,390
起床
I wake up,

460
00:27:28,050 --> 00:27:29,100
上班
I go to work,

461
00:27:29,980 --> 00:27:31,340
开车
and I just drive.

462
00:27:58,820 --> 00:28:00,890
氧气降到1%了
O2 down to one percent.

463
00:28:13,320 --> 00:28:15,370
我有个好消息  有个坏消息
Well, I've got good news and bad news.

464
00:28:15,570 --> 00:28:18,120
好消息是五分钟就到空间站
The good news is, we're about five minutes from the ISS

465
00:28:18,120 --> 00:28:20,460
我还知道老俄的伏特加藏在哪里
and I know where the Russians stash their vodka.

466
00:28:20,790 --> 00:28:23,630
真好  我正缺杯酒提提神呢
And that is good, because I'm running on fumes here.

467
00:28:24,400 --> 00:28:25,670
坏消息是  我还差十分钟
The bad news is, I'm gonna be

468
00:28:25,670 --> 00:28:28,430
就打破阿纳托利的纪录了
about ten minutes short of breaking Anatoly's record,

469
00:28:25,670 --> 00:28:28,430
{\an8}俄太空行走纪录保持者

470
00:28:28,430 --> 00:28:29,580
而我
and I...

471
00:28:30,630 --> 00:28:32,670
-怎么了  -我这里报警了
- What? - I'm redlining.

472
00:28:32,670 --> 00:28:34,940
氧压不够
My O2 tank pressure is low.

473
00:28:34,990 --> 00:28:36,450
氧气罐里没有了
Your tank is out of oxygen

474
00:28:36,450 --> 00:28:38,690
-但太空服里还有  -好吧
- but you still have it in your suit. - Got it.

475
00:28:38,690 --> 00:28:40,350
慢慢呼吸  不要大口喘气
So you have to sip, not gulp.

476
00:28:40,130 --> 00:28:41,920
{\an8}氧气含量低

477
00:28:41,370 --> 00:28:42,770
当喝红酒  不是啤酒
Wine, not beer.

478
00:28:42,770 --> 00:28:44,830
慢慢抿  莱恩
Sip, Ryan.

479
00:28:45,720 --> 00:28:48,690
休斯敦  能否通联  我们已看到空间站
Houston, in the blind, we have a visual of the ISS.

480
00:28:48,690 --> 00:28:50,260
但人员肯定已撤离
The station must have been evacuated

481
00:28:50,260 --> 00:28:52,500
因为联盟一号不见了
because the first Soyuz is missing.

482
00:28:52,570 --> 00:28:55,020
联盟二号的表面严重受损
The second Soyuz exhibits surface damage,

483
00:28:55,020 --> 00:28:56,900
减速伞也打开了
and its chute has been deployed.

484
00:28:57,030 --> 00:29:01,100
无法用作返回逃生舱
Any use as an escape pod for re-entry is impossible.

485
00:29:01,100 --> 00:29:03,480
该变向了吧  又在漂了
Shouldn't we be turning? We're drifting again.

486
00:29:03,480 --> 00:29:06,430
还不行  推进气体我可没开玩笑
Not yet. I wasn't kidding about those fumes.

487
00:29:06,430 --> 00:29:08,870
这罐还够我们喷它一两次
This can has one or two good thrusts left...

488
00:29:09,140 --> 00:29:10,270
如果走运的话
if we're lucky.

489
00:29:23,100 --> 00:29:24,120
稳住
Steady.

490
00:29:34,050 --> 00:29:35,010
看准
Aim.

491
00:29:36,170 --> 00:29:37,100
喷射
Fire!

492
00:29:43,180 --> 00:29:46,920
-减速  快减速  -不行  气罐空了
Brake! Brake! You have to brake! - I can't, the can's empty.

493
00:29:47,170 --> 00:29:49,610
会狠狠撞上去  能抓什么就抓什么
We're gonna hit hard! Grab a hold of anything you can!

494
00:30:01,480 --> 00:30:05,030
怎么办  我该怎么办
What do I do? What do I do?!

495
00:30:14,700 --> 00:30:15,620
莱恩
Ryan!

496
00:30:20,470 --> 00:30:24,150
连接索断裂  我脱离了  脱离了
The tether broke, I'm detached! I'm detached!

497
00:30:24,150 --> 00:30:25,270
快抓东西
Grab a hold!

498
00:30:27,980 --> 00:30:28,970
随便抓个东西
Grab anything!

499
00:30:45,380 --> 00:30:46,280
莱恩
Ryan!

500
00:30:48,490 --> 00:30:51,110
-伸手  -会抓住你的
- Give me five! - I've got you.

501
00:30:51,140 --> 00:30:52,950
一定能抓住  这里  这边啊
I've got you. Right here, right here.

502
00:30:56,620 --> 00:31:00,350
-妈的  -不  不要
- Shit! - No. No, no, no

503
00:31:01,810 --> 00:31:02,750
抓到了
Got ya.

504
00:31:12,010 --> 00:31:12,860
谢天谢地
Got ya.

505
00:31:16,150 --> 00:31:18,860
坚持住  我拉你过来
You just... hold on and I'm gonna start pulling you in. 

506
00:31:19,300 --> 00:31:20,110
-我要拉了  -博士
- I'm gonna start... - Hey, Doc. 

507
00:31:20,110 --> 00:31:22,870
坚持住  坚持  我会拉你回来的
Just hold on. Hang on. I am gonna pull you in.

508
00:31:22,870 --> 00:31:24,440
-莱恩  听我说  -我要拉了
- Ryan, listen. - I'll gonna pull you in.

509
00:31:24,620 --> 00:31:25,990
你必须放手
You have to let me go.

510
00:31:26,000 --> 00:31:28,660
绳子不行  会把你带过来的
The ropes are too loose. I'll pulling you with me.

511
00:31:28,660 --> 00:31:30,680
你必须松手  不然我们都会死
You have to let me go, or we both die.

512
00:31:30,680 --> 00:31:34,160
我不会放开你的  我们可以
I'll not letting you go! We're fine!

513
00:31:39,770 --> 00:31:42,500
莱恩  放开我吧
Ryan, let me go.

514
00:31:42,960 --> 00:31:45,760
你哪里也不能去  哪里都不能去
You're not going anywhere. You're not going anywhere.

515
00:31:45,760 --> 00:31:49,910
-你说了不算  -不  不要  别这样
- It's not up to you. - No, no, no, no... Please don't do this.

516
00:31:50,490 --> 00:31:52,590
求你了  拜托你  不要这样做
Please, please, please, please don't do this.

517
00:31:52,590 --> 00:31:54,600
求你别这样啊  不  不要啊
Please don't do this. No, no, no.

518
00:31:55,130 --> 00:31:57,170
别这样  马特  不要这样做
Please don't, Matt. Please don't do this.

519
00:32:00,190 --> 00:32:01,450
你会回去的  莱恩
You're gonna make it, Ryan.

520
00:32:03,190 --> 00:32:03,650
不要啊
No.

521
00:32:25,730 --> 00:32:29,060
我都抓住你了  都抓住了啊
I had you. I had you! I had you.

522
00:32:44,840 --> 00:32:46,190
莱恩  能听到吗
Ryan, do you hear me?

523
00:32:49,290 --> 00:32:53,050
-收到请回  -我的二氧化碳报警了
- Do you copy? - My CO2 alarm went off.

524
00:32:53,100 --> 00:32:54,710
二氧化碳浓度报警
My CO2 alarm went off.

525
00:32:54,710 --> 00:32:56,620
听着  你要进入空间站
Look, you need to board the station.

526
00:32:57,460 --> 00:32:58,790
看到气闸了吗
Do you see the airlock?

527
00:33:08,380 --> 00:33:11,600
莱恩  收到吗
Hey, Ryan, you copy?

528
00:33:13,810 --> 00:33:15,110
先找到气闸
Look for the airlock.

529
00:33:18,330 --> 00:33:20,750
在你上方  曙光舱旁边
It's above you, next to the Zarya module.

530
00:33:18,330 --> 00:33:20,750
{\an8}国际空间站一功能舱

531
00:33:24,560 --> 00:33:25,870
看到了吗
You see it?

532
00:33:25,870 --> 00:33:28,850
我看到了  看到了  
Yes, yes, I see it. I see it. 

533
00:33:29,740 --> 00:33:32,140
很好  你就是要去那里
Good. That's where you want to go.

534
00:33:33,000 --> 00:33:34,790
感觉现在有点头晕吧
Now you're getting lightheaded, right?

535
00:33:35,270 --> 00:33:39,600
-对  -因为你在吸入二氧化碳
- Yes. - That's because you're breathing CO2.

536
00:33:39,600 --> 00:33:41,430
正在失去意识
You're losing consciousness.

537
00:33:41,490 --> 00:33:44,210
现在必须进入空间站
You need to board the station.

538
00:33:45,180 --> 00:33:48,030
联盟二号受损严重  无法返回地球
That second Soyuz is too damaged for re-entry,

539
00:33:48,030 --> 00:33:50,890
不过开着玩玩很不错
but it's perfectly fine for a little Sunday drive.

540
00:33:51,180 --> 00:33:52,400
开着玩玩
Sunday drive?

541
00:33:53,210 --> 00:33:58,000
往西边看  看到远处那个亮点了吗
Look to the west. You see that dot in the distance?

542
00:33:58,350 --> 00:34:00,990
-看到了  -那是中国空间站
- Yes. - That's a Chinese station.

543
00:34:00,990 --> 00:34:03,790
你要开着联盟号溜达到那里
You're gonna take the Soyuz, and you're gonna cruise over there.

544
00:34:05,360 --> 00:34:07,590
中方救生舱叫神舟
Chinese lifeboat is a Shenzhou.

545
00:34:08,530 --> 00:34:11,310
-我可没碰过神舟  -没关系
- I've never flown a Shenzhou. - It doesn't matter.

546
00:34:11,580 --> 00:34:14,470
返地规程和联盟号一样
Its re-entry protocol is identical to the Soyuz.

547
00:34:19,010 --> 00:34:23,020
-联盟号也没开过吗  -就上过模拟器
- You never flown the Soyuz either? - Only a simulator.

548
00:34:23,840 --> 00:34:25,260
那就行  
Well, then you know. 

549
00:34:27,980 --> 00:34:29,160
可我坠毁了
But I crashed it.

550
00:34:29,540 --> 00:34:32,020
模拟器可不就用来撞毁嘛
It's a simulator, that's what it's designed for.

551
00:34:35,170 --> 00:34:38,430
可是  我每次都坠毁
Every time. I crashed it every time.

552
00:34:38,620 --> 00:34:40,230
把那玩意对准地球就行了
You point the damn thing at Earth.

553
00:34:40,230 --> 00:34:41,780
一点不复杂
It's not rocket science.

554
00:34:42,960 --> 00:34:43,880
明天这个时候
And by this time tomorrow,

555
00:34:43,880 --> 00:34:45,120
你就能回到苏黎世湖
you're gonna be back in Lake Zurich

556
00:34:45,120 --> 00:34:46,800
跟他们讲这番惊心动魄了
with a hell of a story to tell.

557
00:34:47,940 --> 00:34:48,950
能收到吗
You copy?

558
00:34:50,970 --> 00:34:52,250
莱恩  收到吗  
Ryan, you copy? 

559
00:34:52,930 --> 00:34:54,840
我要驾驶联盟号去找你
I'm gonna take the Soyuz and come get you.

560
00:34:54,850 --> 00:34:56,810
-不行  -我要去接你
- No, you're not. - I'm coming to get you.

561
00:34:56,810 --> 00:34:58,280
我已经离你太远了
No, I've got too much of a head start on you.

562
00:34:58,280 --> 00:34:59,260
我会去救你的
I'm coming to get you.

563
00:34:59,260 --> 00:35:01,420
你这趟车我真赶不上了
I'm afraid that ship already sailed.

564
00:35:02,810 --> 00:35:05,110
莱恩  你要学会放手
Ryan, you're gonna have to learn to let go.

565
00:35:06,250 --> 00:35:08,390
-但我...-我想听你说  你可以回去
- But I... - I want to hear you say you're gonna make it...

566
00:35:10,940 --> 00:35:12,540
快  莱恩  说给我听
Come on, Ryan, say it.

567
00:35:14,540 --> 00:35:18,030
-我可以回去  -真乖  继续前行
- I'm gonna make it. - All right. Keep going.

568
00:35:19,340 --> 00:35:22,260
女孩子家怎么叫莱恩呢
What kind of name is Ryan for a girl?

569
00:35:23,910 --> 00:35:25,550
我爸爸想要个男孩
Dad wanted a boy. 

570
00:35:25,550 --> 00:35:27,460
到气闸了吗
Are you close to the airlock?

571
00:35:29,000 --> 00:35:31,330
-还没  -那继续
- Not yet. - Keep going.

572
00:35:32,210 --> 00:35:34,670
现在你我也算保持了一定距离
So now that we have some distance between us.

573
00:35:35,100 --> 00:35:37,930
-你喜欢我对吧  -什么
- You're attracted to me, right? - What?

574
00:35:37,930 --> 00:35:41,520
大家都说我有双迷人的蓝眼睛
Well, people say I have beautiful blue eyes.

575
00:35:45,900 --> 00:35:49,740
你的确有一双...迷人的蓝眼睛
You have beautiful... you have beautiful blue eyes.

576
00:35:49,870 --> 00:35:51,230
我眼睛是棕色的
I have brown eyes.

577
00:35:54,850 --> 00:35:57,790
-想听好消息吗  -什么
- You want to know the good news? - What?

578
00:35:57,790 --> 00:35:59,770
我要打破阿纳托利的纪录了
I'm gonna break Anatoly's record,

579
00:35:59,810 --> 00:36:02,230
而且这纪录可能得保持很久
and I think mine's gonna stand for a long, long time.

580
00:36:02,230 --> 00:36:04,950
不  我会去救你
No. I'm coming to get you.

581
00:36:08,090 --> 00:36:11,150
-天啊  -怎么了
- Oh, my God. - What? What?

582
00:36:14,280 --> 00:36:16,810
-莱恩  -什么
- Hey, Ryan? - Yeah?

583
00:36:17,280 --> 00:36:19,410
你该看看阳光洒在恒河的美景
You should see the sun on the Ganges.

584
00:36:22,220 --> 00:36:23,270
太震撼了
It's amazing.

585
00:40:49,770 --> 00:40:51,540
在哪呢  到底在哪里
Where are you? Where are you?

586
00:40:51,540 --> 00:40:54,160
通信室  通信室  终于找到你了
Comms. Comms. There you are. Okay. 

587
00:41:05,370 --> 00:41:07,050
马特  我是莱恩  收到回话
Matt, this is Ryan, copy.

588
00:41:10,240 --> 00:41:12,560
马特  我是莱恩  收到请回
Matt, this is Ryan, copy.

589
00:41:15,910 --> 00:41:19,400
马特  我到空间站了  能收到吗
Matt, I made it, I'm here, I'm on the station. Do you copy?

590
00:41:25,710 --> 00:41:27,300
马特  快回答我
Come on, Matt, talk to me.

591
00:41:28,020 --> 00:41:30,250
你在哪里  报告你的位置
Tell me where you are, give me your position.

592
00:41:31,590 --> 00:41:34,930
你在哪里  视野  报告你的视野
Where are you? Give me a visual. Just tell me what you see.

593
00:41:40,030 --> 00:41:42,840
离开卡纳维拉尔角后  你不是话很多吗
Come on. You've been yammering since we left Cape Canaveral,

594
00:41:42,840 --> 00:41:44,140
现在怎么不出声了
and now you decide to shut up?

595
00:41:44,140 --> 00:41:47,990
快说句话  什么都可以  什么都行
Talk to me. Just say something, say anything! I don't care!

596
00:41:54,170 --> 00:41:58,300
跟我说说狂欢节的事
Hey, tell me about, uh, Mardi Gras.

597
00:41:58,300 --> 00:42:00,650
跟我说说那个毛茸茸的矬男
Tell me about the hairy guy. Huh?

598
00:42:00,650 --> 00:42:01,900
给我讲讲下文
Tell me what happened.

599
00:42:02,510 --> 00:42:04,410
那毛茸矬男最后怎么了
What happened to the hairy guy?

600
00:42:10,890 --> 00:42:12,220
快回答我啊
Please talk to me.

601
00:42:17,080 --> 00:42:18,070
求你了
Please.

602
00:42:34,210 --> 00:42:35,610
休斯敦  能否通联
Houston, in the blind...

603
00:42:38,240 --> 00:42:39,990
这里是任务专员莱恩·斯通
this is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone

604
00:42:39,990 --> 00:42:42,150
从国际空间站呼叫
reporting from the ISS.

605
00:42:44,180 --> 00:42:47,120
与任务指挥官马修·库沃斯基
All communications with Mission Commander Matthew Kowalski

606
00:42:47,120 --> 00:42:48,400
通信彻底中断
have been lost.

607
00:42:51,890 --> 00:42:53,920
无线电通信已中断
Radio transmission absent.

608
00:42:56,200 --> 00:42:57,810
视野范围均不可见
Visuals nonexistent.

609
00:43:00,620 --> 00:43:02,000
请求确认
To confirm,

610
00:43:02,210 --> 00:43:05,740
本人莱恩·斯通
I, Ryan Stone, am the sole survivor

611
00:43:06,210 --> 00:43:08,550
STS-157唯一幸存者
of STS-one-five-seven.

612
00:43:22,200 --> 00:43:23,190
又怎么了
What now?

613
00:43:33,060 --> 00:43:37,320
{\an8}火警

614
00:45:04,130 --> 00:45:07,070
在哪呢  动力开关在哪呢
Okay. Where is it, where is it? Where is the power?

615
00:45:07,070 --> 00:45:08,030
是这个了
Here you are.

616
00:45:11,670 --> 00:45:15,800
很好  像训练时那样  分离船舱
Great, just like training. Undocking, undocking.

617
00:45:16,330 --> 00:45:19,460
离舱手册  红色
Undocking. Red.

618
00:45:28,510 --> 00:45:31,560
在哪呢  在哪呢
Okay, where is it? Where is it?

619
00:45:32,270 --> 00:45:33,230
快啊
Come on.

620
00:45:38,900 --> 00:45:41,220
很好  这个我记得  我记得
Okay, I remember this, I remember this.

621
00:45:55,950 --> 00:45:57,010
不够四分钟了
You don't have four minutes.

622
00:45:57,010 --> 00:45:58,050
得人工操作
We're going manual.

623
00:46:00,130 --> 00:46:01,070
快啊
Come on.

624
00:46:01,710 --> 00:46:06,680
有了  激活  脱离
Okay. Active-Activate, undock.

625
00:46:34,790 --> 00:46:36,760
七分钟逃离这里
Seven minutes to get out of here.

626
00:46:43,580 --> 00:46:45,210
好了  开始吧
All right, okay.

627
00:47:01,460 --> 00:47:02,740
这又怎么了
What... what?

628
00:47:12,630 --> 00:47:14,490
不  不要  不要啊
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!

629
00:47:44,200 --> 00:47:45,740
停  停  停下来
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!

630
00:48:02,390 --> 00:48:02,900
这就对了
That's right, that's right.

631
00:48:02,910 --> 00:48:04,140
慢慢来  慢慢来
Come on, Come on, Come on.

632
00:48:04,580 --> 00:48:07,100
对  这就对了
That's right, that's right, that's right.

633
00:48:10,210 --> 00:48:11,110
来吧
Come on.

634
00:48:47,140 --> 00:48:48,110
这下好了
Great.

635
00:49:34,320 --> 00:49:37,410
晴空万里  有可能碰上卫星残片
Clear skies with a chance of satellite debris.

636
00:50:50,960 --> 00:50:54,590
先弄开  然后回家  小菜一碟
Okay, we detach this, and we go home. Piece of cake.

637
00:51:26,160 --> 00:51:27,450
怎么做呢
Okay, what do we have?

638
00:51:28,390 --> 00:51:29,680
就它了
Okay, all right.

639
00:51:40,720 --> 00:51:41,790
该死
Shit.

640
00:51:50,000 --> 00:51:51,090
得赶紧了
Okay, come on.

641
00:51:51,510 --> 00:51:52,560
快  快
Come on, come on.

642
00:51:53,180 --> 00:51:54,150
好了
All right.

643
00:53:25,360 --> 00:53:26,550
我讨厌太空
I hate space.

644
00:53:47,020 --> 00:53:48,110
别叫了
Shut up.

645
00:54:07,860 --> 00:54:08,830
终于好了
That's good.

646
00:54:13,440 --> 00:54:15,050
要稳住啊
Let's stabilize you.

647
00:54:30,700 --> 00:54:31,030
不错
Okay.

648
00:54:33,300 --> 00:54:35,530
咱们去逛逛中国站
Let's go visit the Chinese station.

649
00:54:37,020 --> 00:54:38,360
休斯敦  能否通联
Houston, in the blind,

650
00:54:38,570 --> 00:54:44,400
天宫一号位于西侧100公里附近
Tiangong is approximately one hundred kilometers to the west,

651
00:54:44,630 --> 00:54:50,040
我偏离了约13度
and I am off its course by about thirteen degrees.

652
00:54:50,040 --> 00:54:51,980
即将修正轨道
I will correct trajectory.

653
00:55:18,110 --> 00:55:19,030
好了
Okay.

654
00:55:21,060 --> 00:55:22,990
准备与SKD对接
I will engage S-Ka-Dae in

655
00:55:22,990 --> 00:55:27,130
5  4  3  2  1
five... four... three... two... one.

656
00:55:41,940 --> 00:55:44,060
又发生什么事了  
What's happening, what's happening? Come on, come on.

657
00:55:47,230 --> 00:55:48,250
1
One.

658
00:56:02,450 --> 00:56:04,040
启动啊  启动啊
Come on, come on.

659
00:56:08,840 --> 00:56:10,160
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.

660
00:56:11,050 --> 00:56:12,890
不要开玩笑啊
You gotta be kidding me!

661
00:56:17,370 --> 00:56:19,610
你去死吧
No! Don't you fuck...

662
00:56:29,240 --> 00:56:30,690
休斯顿  能否通联
Houston, in the blind.

663
00:56:31,380 --> 00:56:33,960
休斯顿  能否通联  这里莱恩·斯通博士
Houston, in the blind, this is Dr. Ryan Stone.

664
00:56:34,430 --> 00:56:38,250
从联盟TMA-14M号呼叫
I'm calling from the Soyuz TMA-one-four-M.

665
00:56:38,850 --> 00:56:41,810
飞船燃料耗尽  飘浮中  收到吗
I'm currently out of fuel and adrift, do you copy?

666
00:56:44,620 --> 00:56:48,190
休斯顿  我是莱恩·斯通博士
Houston. This is Dr. Ryan Stone.

667
00:56:48,990 --> 00:56:50,060
收到吗
Do you copy?

668
00:56:54,630 --> 00:56:59,920
休斯顿  我是莱恩·斯通  收到吗
Houston. This is Ryan Stone. Do you copy?

669
00:57:02,770 --> 00:57:04,350
休斯顿  我是...
Houston, this is Mission...

670
00:57:04,620 --> 00:57:07,080
我是航天任务专员莱恩·斯通  收到吗
Mission Specialist Ryan Stone, do you copy?

671
00:57:09,200 --> 00:57:12,340
休斯顿  休斯顿  请确认身份
Houston, Houston, please confirm identity.

672
00:57:12,550 --> 00:57:15,890
休斯顿  调幅波段收到你的回应  请讲话
Houston, you're coming in over an AM Frequency. Copy.

673
00:57:17,560 --> 00:57:18,560
收到吗
Do you copy?

674
00:57:19,390 --> 00:57:22,770
你是中国站天宫一号吗  完毕
Is this the Chinese station? Is this Tiangong? Copy.

675
00:57:24,420 --> 00:57:29,110
求救  收到吗  求救  紧急求救
Mayday, can you copy? Mayday, mayday, mayday.

676
00:57:30,070 --> 00:57:34,780
是的  求救  求救
Yes, yes. Mayday, mayday. Mayday, mayday.

677
00:57:35,930 --> 00:57:38,050
安宁刚
Aningaaq.

678
00:57:40,610 --> 00:57:43,800
那是...是你的名字吗
Is that... is that your... is that your name?

679
00:57:43,800 --> 00:57:46,500
安宁刚是你的名字吗  你叫这个吗
Aningaaq is your... is your name? Is that your name?

680
00:57:48,100 --> 00:57:49,660
梅迪
Mayday!

681
00:57:49,660 --> 00:57:52,960
不  不  我不叫梅迪  我叫斯通
No, no, no. No, my name is not Mayday. I'm Stone.

682
00:57:52,960 --> 00:57:56,870
我是莱恩·斯通博士  需要救援
Dr. Ryan Stone, I need help. I am...

683
00:58:00,190 --> 00:58:01,330
狗叫声
Those are dogs.

684
00:58:03,060 --> 00:58:04,380
地球信号
They're calling from Earth.

685
00:58:07,860 --> 00:58:09,180
是地球的信号
They're calling from Earth.

686
00:58:22,510 --> 00:58:27,480
安宁刚  能让狗狗再叫几声吗  可以吗
Aningaaq, make your dogs bark again for me, would you please?

687
00:58:29,460 --> 00:58:34,510
狗狗  狗叫声  汪汪  狗狗
Your dogs. Dogs, you know. Woof, woof. Dogs.

688
00:59:18,360 --> 00:59:20,430
我快要死了  安宁刚
Oh, I'm gonna die, Aningaaq.

689
00:59:23,280 --> 00:59:26,400
大家知道  人总有一死
I know, we're all gonna die. Everybody knows that.

690
00:59:27,180 --> 00:59:29,090
但我今天就要死了
But I'm gonna die today.

691
00:59:32,040 --> 00:59:35,050
挺搞笑吧  但...
Funny, that. You know, to know...

692
00:59:38,510 --> 00:59:41,030
但我很害怕
but the thing is, it's that I'm still scared.

693
00:59:42,080 --> 00:59:43,450
非常非常怕
I'm really scared.

694
00:59:46,550 --> 00:59:48,060
没人会悼念我
Nobody will mourn for me,

695
00:59:48,060 --> 00:59:49,930
没人会为我祈祷了
no one will pray for my soul.

696
00:59:53,350 --> 00:59:54,650
你会吗
Will you mourn for me?

697
00:59:56,640 --> 00:59:58,100
你会为我祈祷吗
Will you say a prayer for me?

698
00:59:59,310 --> 01:00:00,580
会不会太晚了
Or is it too late?

699
01:00:05,500 --> 01:00:08,490
我想为自己祈祷  但从没祈祷过
I mean, I'd say one for myself, but I'm never prayed in my life,

700
01:00:08,490 --> 01:00:09,440
而且
so...

701
01:00:10,730 --> 01:00:12,320
从来没人教过我如何祈祷
Nobody ever taught me how.

702
01:00:16,950 --> 01:00:18,360
从来没人教过我如何祈祷
Nobody ever taught me how.

703
01:00:30,330 --> 01:00:31,410
是宝宝
A baby.

704
01:00:44,510 --> 01:00:46,500
你抱着宝宝  是吗
There's a baby with you, huh?

705
01:00:49,420 --> 01:00:51,080
你在唱摇篮曲吗
Is that a lullaby you're singing?

706
01:00:54,490 --> 01:00:55,660
好温馨啊
That's so sweet.

707
01:00:58,550 --> 01:01:00,240
我以前也常唱给宝宝听
I used to sing to my baby.

708
01:01:04,520 --> 01:01:06,160
马上就能见到她了
I hope I see her soon.

709
01:02:04,740 --> 01:02:13,840
{\an8}氧气

710
01:02:16,840 --> 01:02:19,870
很好听  安宁刚  别停  唱下去
That's nice, Aningaaq. Keep singing, just like that.

711
01:02:21,900 --> 01:02:23,980
唱到我睡着  让我睡去吧
Sing me to sleep, and I'll sleep.

712
01:02:26,220 --> 01:02:29,450
别停  继续  继续
Keep singing. And sing, and sing.

713
01:03:00,130 --> 01:03:01,310
不  不要
No, no, don't!

714
01:03:44,760 --> 01:03:47,610
看看表  13小时11分钟
Check your watch. Thirteen hours and eleven minutes.

715
01:03:47,610 --> 01:03:50,130
告诉阿纳托利  我破他纪录了
Call Anatoly and tell him he's been bumped.

716
01:03:50,730 --> 01:03:53,050
-这里挺暗的  -你怎么...
- It's a little gloomy in here, isn't it? - How did you...?

717
01:03:53,050 --> 01:03:55,600
-相信我  一言难尽  -你怎么...
- Trust me, it's a hell of a story. - But how did...?

718
01:03:58,460 --> 01:03:59,480
这样好多了
That's better.

719
01:04:00,530 --> 01:04:03,980
我找到一块备用电池
I found a little extra... a little extra battery power.

720
01:04:04,200 --> 01:04:06,600
还好你没在边上分散我注意力
It helps that I didn't have you around to distract me.

721
01:04:06,920 --> 01:04:09,700
不得不说  很高兴再见到你
I have to say, I'm glad to see ya.

722
01:04:09,700 --> 01:04:11,090
我以为你早去天堂了呢
I didn't think you were gonna make it.

723
01:04:11,570 --> 01:04:14,330
-找到伏特加了吗  -你...
- Did you find the vodka? - You...

724
01:04:14,650 --> 01:04:17,710
你没有告诉我藏哪了
You never told me where... where it was, so...

725
01:04:23,460 --> 01:04:26,750
敬阿纳托利  干杯[波兰语]
To Anatoly. Na zdorovje.

726
01:04:32,390 --> 01:04:34,300
-不了  -不吗  那算了
- No. - No? All right.

727
01:04:35,400 --> 01:04:36,540
我们离开这鬼地方吧
Let's get out of here.

728
01:04:38,740 --> 01:04:40,820
中国站离着大约100英里
The Chinese station's about a hundred miles.

729
01:04:40,860 --> 01:04:43,210
咱们来个阳光之旅吧
Just a little Sunday drive.

730
01:04:43,470 --> 01:04:45,060
-飞不了了  -飞的了
- We can't. - Sure we can.

731
01:04:45,210 --> 01:04:46,800
没燃料了  都试过了
There's no fuel, I tried everything.

732
01:04:46,800 --> 01:04:50,480
-总有能派上用场的  -什么都用不了
- Well, there's always something we can do. - I tried everything.

733
01:04:50,480 --> 01:04:52,450
软着陆推进你没试吧
Did you try the soft landing jets?

734
01:04:52,450 --> 01:04:54,750
-那个着陆才用的到  -着陆也要推进呢
- They're for landing. So... - Well, landing is launching.

735
01:04:54,750 --> 01:04:57,100
反正都一样  训练课没教吗
It's the same thing. Didn't you learn about that in training?

736
01:04:57,110 --> 01:04:59,150
都告诉过你  模拟器我都没成功着陆过
I never got to land the simulator. I told you that.

737
01:04:59,150 --> 01:05:01,190
-但你知道操作  -我每次都坠毁
- But you know about it. - And I crashed it every time.

738
01:05:01,190 --> 01:05:03,890
那你是想回家还是想待在这
Listen, do you want to go back, or do you want to stay here?

739
01:05:07,270 --> 01:05:08,800
我懂了  太空很漂亮
I get it, it's nice up here.

740
01:05:12,560 --> 01:05:16,460
你可以关掉所有系统
You can just shut down all the systems,

741
01:05:17,430 --> 01:05:18,790
关掉所有灯光
turn out all the lights...

742
01:05:20,230 --> 01:05:22,530
闭上眼睛  忽略世人
and just close your eyes and tune out everybody.

743
01:05:23,570 --> 01:05:25,190
在太空没人可以伤害你
There's nobody up here that can hurt you.

744
01:05:26,240 --> 01:05:27,250
很安全
It's safe.

745
01:05:31,010 --> 01:05:33,290
为什么要坚持  为什么要活下去
I mean, what's the point of going on? What's the point of living?

746
01:05:38,460 --> 01:05:41,930
有什么能比孩子的死还痛呢
Your kid died. Doesn't get any rougher than that.

747
01:05:44,760 --> 01:05:46,800
关键看你现在怎么做
But still, it's a matter of what you do now.

748
01:05:48,790 --> 01:05:51,840
若决定回去  那就行动起来
If you decide to go, then you gotta just get on with it.

749
01:05:52,980 --> 01:05:55,020
坐稳扶好  享受旅程
Sit back, enjoy the ride.

750
01:05:56,020 --> 01:05:58,190
你要站在地球上
You gotta plant both your feet on the ground

751
01:05:58,190 --> 01:05:59,510
开始新生活
and start livin' life.

752
01:05:59,520 --> 01:06:03,150
-你怎么回来的  -说过了  一言难尽
- How did you get here? - I'll telling you, it's a hell of a story.

753
01:06:04,010 --> 01:06:06,360
-莱恩  -怎么了
- Hey, Ryan? - What?

754
01:06:07,080 --> 01:06:08,470
该回家了
It's time to go home.

755
01:06:31,070 --> 01:06:39,490
{\an8}氧气

756
01:06:52,480 --> 01:06:53,530
着陆
Landing...

757
01:06:56,150 --> 01:06:58,940
着陆  着陆也可以推进
Landing... landing is launching.

758
01:07:00,760 --> 01:07:01,770
我还说...
I said...

759
01:07:15,900 --> 01:07:19,030
对  着陆  着陆手册是绿色的
Okay, landing, landing. Landing is green.

760
01:07:33,090 --> 01:07:35,960
没错  就这本
Okay, landing. All right.

761
01:07:37,020 --> 01:07:39,040
软着陆推进器开关
Okay. Soft landing jets trigger

762
01:07:39,050 --> 01:07:41,840
会在距地面三米自动开启
automatically at three meters before landing, so...

763
01:07:44,970 --> 01:07:46,850
马特  你他妈可真聪明
You're a clever son of a bitch, Matt.

764
01:07:47,110 --> 01:07:51,010
我需要...需要让轨道舱
I need to... I need to get rid of the B.O...

765
01:07:51,010 --> 01:07:53,110
与推进器分离
and the engine module.

766
01:07:54,710 --> 01:07:56,040
对  没错
Right. Okay.

767
01:07:57,010 --> 01:07:57,910
来吧
Okay.

768
01:08:03,940 --> 01:08:05,650
三舱分离
Tri-module separation.

769
01:08:07,030 --> 01:08:07,950
启动
Go.

770
01:08:22,470 --> 01:08:23,540
好了
Okay.

771
01:08:24,790 --> 01:08:26,560
休斯顿  到最棘手的部分了
Houston, here's the tricky part.

772
01:08:27,430 --> 01:08:29,040
得让联盟号认为
Soyuz has to think

773
01:08:29,660 --> 01:08:33,050
我们距地面已是三米
we are three meters off the Earth.

774
01:08:34,370 --> 01:08:37,060
好吧
All right. Okay.

775
01:08:37,090 --> 01:08:39,720
马特  看在这周
Hey, Matt? Since I had to listen

776
01:08:39,720 --> 01:08:42,510
听你唠叨的份上
to endless hours of your storytelling this week,

777
01:08:42,960 --> 01:08:44,650
给你个机会帮帮我
I need for you to do me a favor.

778
01:08:46,030 --> 01:08:48,820
你将会看到一个棕发女孩
You are gonna see a little girl with brown hair,

779
01:08:49,190 --> 01:08:51,380
头发像个鸟窝
very messy, lots of knots.

780
01:08:52,120 --> 01:08:55,690
她不喜欢梳头  没关系的
She doesn't like to brush it. That's okay.

781
01:08:56,510 --> 01:08:57,740
她叫萨拉
Her name is Sarah.

782
01:08:58,890 --> 01:09:00,630
能拜托你转告她吗
Can you please tell her

783
01:09:01,630 --> 01:09:03,550
告诉她  妈妈找到她红鞋子了
that Mama found her red shoe?

784
01:09:04,790 --> 01:09:07,070
马特  她总是惦记那只鞋子
She was so worried about that shoe, Matt.

785
01:09:07,910 --> 01:09:09,520
其实就在床底下
But it was just right under the bed.

786
01:09:14,220 --> 01:09:16,270
替我好好抱抱她  亲亲她
Give her a big hug and a big kiss for me,

787
01:09:16,270 --> 01:09:17,890
告诉她我想死她了
and tell her that Mama misses her.

788
01:09:18,880 --> 01:09:20,960
她是我的心肝宝贝
You tell her that she is my angel.

789
01:09:22,020 --> 01:09:25,360
她让我骄傲  特骄傲
And she makes me so proud. So, so proud.

790
01:09:30,470 --> 01:09:32,290
告诉她我没有放弃
And you tell her that I'm not quitting.

791
01:09:39,920 --> 01:09:41,660
告诉她我很爱她
You tell her that I love her, Matt.

792
01:09:43,050 --> 01:09:45,160
告诉她我很爱很爱她
You tell her that I love her so much.

793
01:09:47,890 --> 01:09:49,210
这个忙能帮我吗
Can you do that for me?

794
01:09:52,440 --> 01:09:53,470
收到
Roger that.

795
01:09:56,010 --> 01:09:57,000
启程
Here we go.

796
01:10:34,180 --> 01:10:36,060
天宫  你也在下降啊
You're losing altitude, Tiangong.

797
01:10:39,480 --> 01:10:42,350
这么下降就要和气层激情四射了
You keep dropping and you're gonna kiss the atmosphere.

798
01:10:43,560 --> 01:10:46,360
你是最后一班车  别丢下我
But not without me, because you're my last ride.

799
01:10:47,900 --> 01:10:48,850
好吧
Okay.

800
01:10:50,160 --> 01:10:51,030
等等
Wait.

801
01:10:58,740 --> 01:10:59,660
5
Five...

802
01:11:01,200 --> 01:11:02,130
4
Four...

803
01:11:03,500 --> 01:11:04,440
3
Three...

804
01:11:05,770 --> 01:11:07,100
不就开车嘛
No more just driving.

805
01:11:09,060 --> 01:11:10,300
回家吧
Let's go home.

806
01:11:15,330 --> 01:11:18,410
稳住  别晃  别晃
Steady. Okay, come on, come on.

807
01:11:19,530 --> 01:11:20,550
稳住  稳住
Steady, steady.

808
01:11:21,550 --> 01:11:23,450
别晃  别晃
Come on. Come on.

809
01:11:27,890 --> 01:11:29,600
在哪呢  你在哪呢  四十五度
Where are you? Where are you? Forty-five,

810
01:11:29,600 --> 01:11:31,950
九十度  背后  在背后
ninety, one-eighty, one-eighty.

811
01:11:39,970 --> 01:11:40,930
加油
Come on.

812
01:11:50,710 --> 01:11:51,650
就这样
Okay.

813
01:12:04,120 --> 01:12:05,020
就到了
All right.

814
01:12:09,020 --> 01:12:09,930
妈的
Damn it.

815
01:12:11,970 --> 01:12:16,590
近点  近点  妈妈抱
Down, down, down. Come to Mama.

816
01:13:38,770 --> 01:13:39,770
妈的
Shit!

817
01:13:49,650 --> 01:13:53,140
到了  神舟呢  神舟呢
Come on. Shenzhou, come on. Shenzhou. Shenzhou.

818
01:13:54,050 --> 01:13:58,050
妈的  是这边  神舟我来了
Fuck! Okay, this way. Shenzhou.

819
01:14:08,200 --> 01:14:09,200
这是什么
What's this?

820
01:14:56,840 --> 01:15:00,040
联盟号的动力开关在这里
In the Soyuz, the power button is here.

821
01:15:03,310 --> 01:15:05,620
好的  要脱离对接  脱离对接
Okay, undocking, undocking.

822
01:15:07,330 --> 01:15:08,400
"咦呢  咪呢"
Eeni, meeni...

823
01:15:09,430 --> 01:15:14,160
对  就是这个声音 "麦呢  嚜"
Okay, that doesn't sound good. Miny... moe.

824
01:15:15,820 --> 01:15:17,010
听不懂中文
No hablo chino.

825
01:15:18,780 --> 01:15:20,810
"麦呢  嚜"
Miny... moe.

826
01:15:22,700 --> 01:15:24,610
对了  对了  太棒了
Okay. Okay, good.

827
01:15:33,570 --> 01:15:35,360
休斯顿  休斯顿  能否通联
Houston. Houston, in the blind.

828
01:15:35,730 --> 01:15:37,880
我是航天任务专员莱恩·斯通
This is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone

829
01:15:37,880 --> 01:15:39,600
正从神舟上呼叫你
reporting from the Shenzhou.

830
01:15:39,610 --> 01:15:41,980
我马上要脱开天宫一号了
I'll about to undock from Tiangong...

831
01:15:46,530 --> 01:15:48,830
我对这次任务有不祥的预感
And I have a bad feeling about this mission.

832
01:15:51,720 --> 01:15:53,580
让我想起一个故事  休斯顿...
Reminds me of a story, Houston...

833
01:15:56,260 --> 01:16:00,470
算了  休斯顿  不说了
Never... Never mind the story, Houston. Never mind the story.

834
01:16:02,750 --> 01:16:05,910
这里越来越热了  会没事的
It's getting hot in here. Okay. All right.

835
01:16:08,720 --> 01:16:12,750
依我看来  只有两个结果
All right, the way I see it, there's only two possible outcomes.

836
01:16:13,020 --> 01:16:15,330
要么安全降落
Either I make it down there in one piece

837
01:16:15,330 --> 01:16:17,400
带回一段传奇经历
and I have one hell of a story to tell,

838
01:16:18,180 --> 01:16:20,300
要么在十分钟内化为灰烬
or I burn up in the next ten minutes.

839
01:16:22,240 --> 01:16:26,270
管他哪种结果  一切随缘
Either way, whichever way... no harm, no foul!

840
01:16:34,120 --> 01:16:35,280
因为不管哪种结果
Because either way...

841
01:16:37,980 --> 01:16:39,720
这段旅程都充满意义
it'll be one hell of a ride.

842
01:16:42,650 --> 01:16:43,600
我准备好了
I'm ready.

843
01:18:50,490 --> 01:18:54,060
神舟  能否通联  这里是休斯顿
Shenzhou, in the blind, this is Houston.

844
01:18:54,060 --> 01:18:55,490
请告知调频波段
Indicate FM frequency.

845
01:18:57,070 --> 01:18:59,700
雷达监测你处于返回轨道
Our radars detect you on a re-entry trajectory.

846
01:18:59,700 --> 01:19:02,280
若能收到  请确认身份
If you copy, please confirm identity.

847
01:19:23,060 --> 01:19:28,100
这里是休斯顿[伴无线电干扰]
This is Houston.

848
01:19:28,970 --> 01:19:30,700
没钱
No money down!

849
01:19:31,470 --> 01:19:34,660
-一切安好...-请立即表明身份
- ...messages, we'll be right... - Please confirm identity.

850
01:19:34,660 --> 01:19:36,510
中西部天气晴朗无云
Skies over the Midwest are completely clear...

851
01:19:36,510 --> 01:19:38,930
已部署救援队前去搜救
We're deployed a rescue mission to retrieve you.

852
01:19:39,470 --> 01:19:41,540
救援队在途中
Rescue mission is on the way.

853
01:19:45,650 --> 01:19:47,880
神舟  能否通联  这里是休斯顿
Shenzhou, in the blind, this is Houston.

854
01:19:50,030 --> 01:19:53,390
已部署救援队前去搜救
We're deployed a rescue mission to retrieve you.

855
01:22:43,810 --> 01:22:44,830
谢谢你
Thank you.

856
01:22:52,830 --> 01:22:53,740
没事的
No.

857
01:23:49,520 --> 01:23:52,730
{\pos(192.533,195.327)}地        心        引        力

