2
00:00:01,000 --> 00:00:27,000
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0

3
00:00:01,000 --> 00:00:27,000
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35

4
00:00:01,000 --> 00:00:27,000
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60

5
00:00:01,000 --> 00:00:11,000
{\pos(90,248)}m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172

6
00:00:01,000 --> 00:00:11,000
{\pos(100,254)}人人影视
YYeTs.com

7
00:00:02,000 --> 00:00:11,000
{\pos(105,265)}原创翻译 双语字幕

9
00:00:02,000 --> 00:00:11,000
{\pos(237,265)}仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com

10
00:00:11,000 --> 00:00:16,000
{\an5}翻译：  Cesc.Dexter   somehacker   paul34

12
00:00:16,000 --> 00:00:21,000
{\an5}校对：Cesc.Dexter   总监：cheeseflower

13
00:00:21,000 --> 00:00:26,000
{\an5}后期：L.C.   特效：8T

15
02:18:00,160 --> 02:18:05,130
{\pos(192,261)}007五十周年纪念  敬请期待詹姆斯·邦德再度回归

16
02:09:55,010 --> 02:10:00,770
谨以悼念

17
02:09:55,010 --> 02:10:00,770
安德鲁·邦德

18
02:09:55,010 --> 02:10:00,770
和

19
02:09:55,010 --> 02:10:00,770
莫妮卡·德拉克洛瓦·邦德

20
00:17:03,160 --> 00:17:13,220
皇家海军中校 詹姆斯·邦德
讣告

21
01:47:35,300 --> 01:47:37,260
{\an8}天幕庄园

22
01:45:51,820 --> 01:45:54,700
{\an8}苏格兰

23
01:34:36,730 --> 01:34:37,770
威斯敏斯特
英国议会所在地

24
01:29:27,290 --> 01:29:28,420
{\an8}你没我想的那么聪明

25
01:29:19,410 --> 01:29:22,080
{\an8}{\pos(191,80)}系统被入侵

26
01:28:48,460 --> 01:28:49,880
{\an8}格兰伯格

27
01:28:49,880 --> 01:28:50,670
{\an8}格兰伯格

28
00:51:40,070 --> 00:51:43,320
{\an8}{\pos(194,221)}澳门

29
00:51:32,110 --> 00:51:35,020
{\an8}{\pos(163,155)}想想你的罪孽

30
00:51:28,180 --> 00:51:31,490
{\an8}{\pos(142,153)}每过一周会增加五个

31
00:50:43,470 --> 00:50:45,270
{\an8}{\pos(188,14)}澳门

32
00:42:21,050 --> 00:42:23,930
{\an8}{\pos(185,186)}航班号 EWA226
晚上九点

33
00:41:26,620 --> 00:41:29,640
{\an8}{\pos(194,211)}上海

36
00:24:21,060 --> 00:24:26,020
{\an8}{\pos(160,37)}重大新闻

37
00:24:21,060 --> 00:24:26,020
{\an8}{\pos(186,50)}针对军情六处的恐怖袭击

38
00:20:58,060 --> 00:21:00,940
{\an8}{\pos(193,164)}想想你的罪孽

39
00:16:50,150 --> 00:16:55,200
{\an8}{\pos(194,225)}军情六处

40
00:16:50,150 --> 00:16:55,200
{\an8}{\pos(196,184)}伦敦

41
00:13:23,190 --> 00:13:26,490
{\an8}{\pos(193,152)}天幕危机

43
00:31:46,170 --> 00:31:47,500
{\an8}Agent  Provocateur是内奸之意

44
00:31:48,740 --> 00:31:49,790
{\an8}意义同上  意为女性内奸

45
01:28:36,150 --> 01:28:38,370
{\an8}伦敦地铁线  世界上最早的一条地铁路线

46
01:40:16,520 --> 01:40:17,960
{\an8}英国维多利亚时代的诗人  以下选自他的诗《尤利西斯》

47
01:51:41,810 --> 01:51:42,940
{\an8}为牧师做弥撒准备的私密场所

48
00:01:25,810 --> 00:01:27,870
隆森受伤了
Ronson's down.

49
00:01:28,080 --> 00:01:29,550
他需要急救
He needs medical evac.

50
00:01:29,680 --> 00:01:31,410
东西在哪  还在吗
Where is it? Is it there?

51
00:01:31,520 --> 00:01:32,490
硬盘不见了
Hard drive's gone.

52
00:01:33,150 --> 00:01:34,450
你确定吗
Are you sure?

53
00:01:38,060 --> 00:01:39,420
不见了  等我一下
It's gone. Give me a minute.

54
00:01:39,590 --> 00:01:41,460
一定是他们拿走了  赶紧追上去
They must have it. Get after them.

55
00:01:46,400 --> 00:01:47,490
我在抢救隆森
I'm stabilizing Ronson.

56
00:01:47,670 --> 00:01:48,800
我们没时间了
We don 't have the time.

57
00:01:48,970 --> 00:01:50,490
我必须帮他止血
I have to stop the bleeding!

58
00:01:51,010 --> 00:01:52,560
别管他了
Leave him!

59
00:02:27,180 --> 00:02:28,610
你找到他了吗
Have you got him?

60
00:02:29,110 --> 00:02:30,580
在那辆黑色奥迪上
He's in the black Audi.

61
00:02:31,480 --> 00:02:32,470
隆森呢
What about Ronson?

62
00:02:32,650 --> 00:02:33,640
他中枪了
He's been hit.

63
00:02:34,080 --> 00:02:35,850
我们派了一支急救小组过去
We're sending an emergency evacuation squad.

64
00:02:35,980 --> 00:02:37,580
那就他妈的来不及了
They'll be too bloody late!

65
00:02:39,050 --> 00:02:40,250
他发现我们了
He's seen us.

66
00:02:40,820 --> 00:02:42,790
急救小组还有5分钟赶到
Medical evac for Ronson five minutes away.

67
00:02:49,330 --> 00:02:51,130
无所谓  反正你也用不着
That's all right. You weren't using it.

68
00:02:53,570 --> 00:02:55,540
另一个我也用不着了
I wasn't using that one, either.

69
00:03:40,980 --> 00:03:42,280
卧倒
Keep your head down.

70
00:04:17,320 --> 00:04:18,410
闪开
Just get clear!

71
00:04:20,420 --> 00:04:22,010
哪一边  谭纳
Tanner, which way?

72
00:04:22,190 --> 00:04:23,820
往前开  我能引导你过去
Keep going. I can direct you from here.

73
00:04:23,960 --> 00:04:25,450
你们都知道这利害攸关
You both know what's at stake here.

74
00:04:25,630 --> 00:04:27,120
我们不能失去那份名单
We can't afford to lose that list.

75
00:04:27,300 --> 00:04:28,260
是  长官
Yes, ma'am.

76
00:04:58,230 --> 00:04:59,420
他们现在哪里
Where are they now?

77
00:04:59,530 --> 00:05:01,960
他们在大集市顶上
They appear to be on the rooftops of the Grand Bazaar.

78
00:05:54,050 --> 00:05:56,240
往左拐  你能在桥上截住他
Take a left. There's a bridge. You can cut him off.

79
00:06:48,540 --> 00:06:50,370
-怎么回事  -他们刚上了火车  长官
- What happened? - They're on the train, ma'am.

80
00:06:50,470 --> 00:06:51,670
上了火车是什么意思
What do you mean on the train?

81
00:06:51,840 --> 00:06:53,030
我是说他们刚跳到了火车顶上
I mean, they're on top of a train.

82
00:06:53,210 --> 00:06:54,570
看在上帝的份上  快追上去
Well, get after them, for God's sake!

83
00:07:25,170 --> 00:07:26,470
她要跑出监控范围了
She's going out of range.

84
00:07:26,640 --> 00:07:27,940
我们没信号了  什么都看不到
We've lost tracking. We're blind here.

85
00:07:28,110 --> 00:07:29,940
-现在什么情况  -我还追着他们
- What's going on? - I'm still with them.

86
00:07:30,110 --> 00:07:32,140
给我转卫星监控  什么都好
Get me CCTV, satellite, anything!

87
00:08:22,160 --> 00:08:23,460
那是什么
What was that?

88
00:08:24,070 --> 00:08:26,690
甲壳虫吧
VW Beetles. I think.

89
00:08:51,760 --> 00:08:54,320
邦德  他在分解车厢
Bond! He's uncoupling the cars.

90
00:09:32,730 --> 00:09:34,100
007  你没事吧
007, are you all right?

91
00:09:34,640 --> 00:09:36,260
换了个车厢而已
Just changing carriages.

92
00:09:38,210 --> 00:09:39,870
情况怎样  快报告
What's going on? Report!

93
00:09:40,040 --> 00:09:41,700
很难解释清楚  长官
It's rather hard to explain, ma'am.

94
00:09:41,980 --> 00:09:43,500
007追上去了
007's still in pursuit.

95
00:10:48,210 --> 00:10:50,110
这边快没路了
Looks like there isn't much more road.

96
00:10:50,280 --> 00:10:52,180
我觉得我没法继续跟上去
I don't think I can go any further.

97
00:11:26,750 --> 00:11:28,210
我也许可以开枪
I may have a shot.

98
00:11:35,420 --> 00:11:36,550
目标不清晰
It's not clean.

99
00:11:36,860 --> 00:11:38,320
重复  我无法瞄准
Repeat, I do not have a clean shot.

100
00:11:45,770 --> 00:11:47,790
前面又有隧道  我会跟丢他们
There's a tunnel ahead. I'm gonna lose them.

101
00:11:48,070 --> 00:11:49,590
你能换个更好的位置吗
Can you get into a better position?

102
00:11:49,770 --> 00:11:51,290
不行  没时间了
Negative. There's no time.

103
00:11:53,410 --> 00:11:54,400
开枪
Take the shot.

104
00:11:56,410 --> 00:11:57,710
我说了  开枪
I said take the shot.

105
00:11:59,380 --> 00:12:00,750
不行  我会打到邦德
I can't! I may hit Bond.

106
00:12:00,980 --> 00:12:02,110
该死的快开枪
Take the bloody shot!

107
00:12:25,370 --> 00:12:26,840
特工受伤
Agent down.

108
00:17:45,860 --> 00:17:48,190
感觉就像是被校长叫去办公室一样
It's like being summoned to the headmaster's study.

109
00:17:48,360 --> 00:17:50,690
他是新主席  这只是标准程序
It's a new Chairman. Just standard procedure.

110
00:17:50,860 --> 00:17:52,920
要我说的话  这简直就是浪费时间
Bloody waste of my time is what I call it.

111
00:17:53,170 --> 00:17:55,100
很抱歉  我们第一次见面
I'm sorry to have to deal with such

112
00:17:55,270 --> 00:17:57,200
就不得不处理这种微妙问题
a delicate subject at our first encounter.

113
00:17:59,970 --> 00:18:01,270
但是
But, um...

114
00:18:01,880 --> 00:18:03,640
我必须对你坦白
I have to be frank with you.

115
00:18:03,840 --> 00:18:05,810
这个主意不错
I think that would be a good idea.

116
00:18:08,880 --> 00:18:10,850
首相非常担心
The Prime Minister's concerned.

117
00:18:11,690 --> 00:18:14,480
你可以告诉他  我的特工在全力追查
Well, you can tell him my operatives are pursuing every avenue.

118
00:18:14,660 --> 00:18:16,620
你有考虑过撤回那些特工吗
Have you considered pulling out the agents?

119
00:18:16,760 --> 00:18:18,120
我考虑过所有办法
I've considered every option.

120
00:18:18,260 --> 00:18:20,560
不好意思  但这听起来像个借口
Forgive me, that sounds like an evasion.

121
00:18:20,760 --> 00:18:22,660
不好意思  你到底为什么叫我来
Forgive me, but why am I here?

122
00:18:23,900 --> 00:18:24,870
三个月前
Three months ago,

123
00:18:24,870 --> 00:18:27,730
你丢失了那个电脑硬盘
you lost the computer drive containing the identity

124
00:18:27,900 --> 00:18:30,300
里面有着几乎所有在全球恐怖组织内
of almost every NATO agent embedded in

125
00:18:30,470 --> 00:18:32,870
卧底的北约特工的身份名单
terrorist organizations across the globe.

126
00:18:33,510 --> 00:18:34,330
这份名单
A list which,

127
00:18:34,330 --> 00:18:36,370
在我们的盟友看来  是不存在的
in the eyes of our allies, never existed.

128
00:18:36,740 --> 00:18:37,950
所以恕我直言
So if you'll forgive me,

129
00:18:37,950 --> 00:18:40,370
你应该知道我为什么叫你来
I think you know why you're here.

130
00:18:40,580 --> 00:18:42,310
所以这是民间监督吗
Are we to call this "Civilian oversight"?

131
00:18:42,580 --> 00:18:46,020
不  这是退休计划
No, we're to call this "Retirement planning."

132
00:18:47,750 --> 00:18:49,720
对于你多年来的贡献
Your country has only the highest respect for you

133
00:18:49,890 --> 00:18:51,860
国家给予你最高的敬意
and your many years of service.

134
00:18:52,190 --> 00:18:53,780
你手头的工作完成之后
When your current posting is completed,

135
00:18:53,890 --> 00:18:57,020
你将被授予勋爵爵位  光荣退休
you'll be awarded GCMG with full honors.

136
00:18:58,570 --> 00:19:00,190
祝贺你
Congratulations.

137
00:19:01,070 --> 00:19:02,060
你是要解雇我吗
You're firing me.

138
00:19:02,270 --> 00:19:04,600
不  夫人  我只是来监督过渡阶段
No, ma'am, I'm here to oversee the transition period

139
00:19:04,770 --> 00:19:07,430
好让你在两个月内顺利自愿退休
leading to your voluntary retirement in two months' time.

140
00:19:07,910 --> 00:19:10,380
你的继任者还未任命  所以我们要你...
Your successor has yet to be appointed, so we'll be asking you...

141
00:19:10,540 --> 00:19:12,240
我不蠢  马洛瑞
I'm not an idiot, Mallory.

142
00:19:12,950 --> 00:19:15,010
我知道我不能干一辈子
I know I can't do this job forever

143
00:19:15,380 --> 00:19:17,320
但我绝不会在这个部门
but I'll be damned if I'm going to leave the department

144
00:19:17,480 --> 00:19:19,450
最困难的时期离开
in worse shape than I found it.

145
00:19:19,650 --> 00:19:22,120
M  你干得很好
M, you've had a great run.

146
00:19:22,820 --> 00:19:24,260
你该体面地离开
You should leave with dignity.

147
00:19:24,420 --> 00:19:27,520
去他的体面  任务完成后我才会走
Oh, to hell with dignity. I'll leave when the job's done.

148
00:19:46,650 --> 00:19:47,770
喂
Yes?

149
00:19:49,450 --> 00:19:50,440
现在吗
Now?

150
00:19:52,450 --> 00:19:53,830
夫人  军需部发来警报
Ma'am, alert from Q-Branch.

151
00:19:53,830 --> 00:19:56,390
有人在试图解密那块硬盘
Someone's trying to decrypt the stolen hard drive.

152
00:19:56,860 --> 00:19:58,880
他们在追踪渗入信息
We're tracing the encryption signal.

153
00:19:59,490 --> 00:20:00,550
正在定位
Localizing now.

154
00:20:03,700 --> 00:20:05,100
是从英国发出的
Centering in the UK.

155
00:20:07,300 --> 00:20:08,500
在伦敦
London.

156
00:20:08,870 --> 00:20:10,560
尽快赶回总部
Get us back to base as soon as possible.

157
00:20:17,980 --> 00:20:19,100
是从军情六处发出的
It's coming from MI6.

158
00:20:19,280 --> 00:20:20,440
什么
What?

159
00:20:20,550 --> 00:20:22,710
数据库接入了我们的网络
The data packet is linking to our network.

160
00:20:23,450 --> 00:20:25,440
不  它侵入了我们的防火墙
Correction. This is behind our firewall.

161
00:20:26,120 --> 00:20:27,110
我们该关掉
We should shut down.

162
00:20:27,220 --> 00:20:28,190
不  追踪它
No, track it.

163
00:20:28,620 --> 00:20:30,350
我们要查出来源
We have to know where it's coming from.

164
00:20:30,820 --> 00:20:32,290
追踪来源
Strip the headers. Trace the source.

165
00:20:32,630 --> 00:20:34,320
他们到底怎么进的我们的系统
How the hell did they get into our system?

166
00:20:34,960 --> 00:20:36,260
开始追踪
Getting trace back now.

167
00:20:41,240 --> 00:20:42,460
看起来
It appears...

168
00:20:44,000 --> 00:20:45,530
看起来是你的电脑  夫人
It appears to be your computer, ma'am.

169
00:20:46,210 --> 00:20:47,300
关掉它
Shut it down.

170
00:20:53,380 --> 00:20:54,470
这是什么
What is this?

171
00:21:15,740 --> 00:21:17,800
老天啊
For God's sake!

172
00:21:19,910 --> 00:21:21,370
快让开
Just get out of the way!

173
00:21:22,280 --> 00:21:23,970
-你不认识这辆车吗  -女士
-Don't you recognize the car? -Madam.

174
00:23:54,590 --> 00:23:57,320
CNN重大新闻
This is CNN Breaking News.

175
00:23:57,700 --> 00:24:00,000
应急小组还在评估事故损伤
Emergency crews are still attempting to assess

176
00:24:00,170 --> 00:24:02,470
调查人员已经介入调查
the damage as investigators hunt for leads

177
00:24:02,670 --> 00:24:04,690
这起发生在伦敦市中心的
in what now appears to be a major

178
00:24:04,870 --> 00:24:06,900
重大恐怖袭击事件
terrorist attack in the heart of London.

179
00:24:08,580 --> 00:24:09,650
目前为止还未有人
No-one has yet claimed

180
00:24:09,650 --> 00:24:11,740
声称对这起据说是
responsibility for what sources are calling

181
00:24:11,950 --> 00:24:13,680
针对英国情报部门的
a possible "Cyber-terrorist

182
00:24:13,680 --> 00:24:16,180
网络恐怖袭击负责
assault" On the British Secret Service.

183
00:24:16,380 --> 00:24:18,540
从现场发来的早期报告称
Early reports from the scene indicate

184
00:24:18,720 --> 00:24:20,880
至少六人死亡  多人受伤
at least six dead, many more injured,

185
00:24:21,120 --> 00:24:23,990
爆炸发生后
with victims being evacuated to local hospitals

186
00:24:24,120 --> 00:24:25,920
被害人立即被送往当地医院急救
within minutes of the explosion.

187
00:24:44,380 --> 00:24:46,110
该走了  夫人
It's time to go, ma'am.

188
00:24:49,120 --> 00:24:51,380
我一定要查出罪魁祸首
I'm going to find whoever did this.

189
00:25:40,600 --> 00:25:42,330
你死到哪里去了
Where the hell have you been?

190
00:25:43,170 --> 00:25:45,100
享受"死"的时光
Enjoying death.

191
00:25:46,470 --> 00:25:49,000
007特工报道
007 reporting for duty.

192
00:25:56,480 --> 00:25:57,970
你为什么不打电话来
Why didn't you call?

193
00:25:58,490 --> 00:26:00,450
你没收到明信片吗
You didn't get the postcard?

194
00:26:00,890 --> 00:26:02,680
你该试试看  远离世俗
You should try it some time. Get away from it all.

195
00:26:02,860 --> 00:26:04,650
这能扩大你的眼界
It really lends perspective.

196
00:26:05,290 --> 00:26:07,120
你把那个地方的酒都喝光了吧
Ran out of drink where you were, did they?

197
00:26:07,360 --> 00:26:08,950
你当时怎么说来着
What was it you said?

198
00:26:09,400 --> 00:26:11,420
该死的快开枪
"Take the bloody shot."

199
00:26:11,670 --> 00:26:13,000
我是当机立断
I made a judgment call.

200
00:26:13,200 --> 00:26:15,600
你该相信我可以完成任务
You should have trusted me to finish the job.

201
00:26:15,840 --> 00:26:17,630
当时的情况是  要么可能失去你
It was the possibility of losing you

202
00:26:17,800 --> 00:26:20,300
要么肯定失去所有其他特工
or the certainty of losing all those other agents.

203
00:26:20,570 --> 00:26:23,300
我只能这么决定  你也知道
I made the only decision I could and you know it.

204
00:26:24,380 --> 00:26:25,640
我觉得你失去了胆量
I think you lost your nerve.

205
00:26:25,850 --> 00:26:28,210
那你想要怎样  我给你道歉吗
What do you expect, a bloody apology?

206
00:26:28,650 --> 00:26:29,980
你知道游戏规则
You know the rules of the game.

207
00:26:30,080 --> 00:26:31,570
你干这行这么久了
You've been playing it long enough.

208
00:26:31,690 --> 00:26:32,670
我们都是
We both have.

209
00:26:33,690 --> 00:26:34,880
也许太久了
Maybe too long.

210
00:26:35,760 --> 00:26:37,220
这话对你自己说吧
Speak for yourself.

211
00:26:39,890 --> 00:26:41,790
隆森死了吧
Ronson didn't make it, did he?

212
00:26:42,930 --> 00:26:43,990
是的
No.

213
00:26:47,370 --> 00:26:48,830
所以就这样了
So this is it.

214
00:26:49,270 --> 00:26:51,240
我们都没用了
We're both played out.

215
00:26:52,210 --> 00:26:54,370
如果你这么想  为什么要回来
Well, if you believe that, why did you come back?

216
00:26:54,840 --> 00:26:56,170
问得好
Good question.

217
00:26:57,940 --> 00:26:59,740
因为我们被袭击了
Because we're under attack.

218
00:27:01,680 --> 00:27:03,740
而你知道我们需要你
And you know we need you.

219
00:27:08,020 --> 00:27:09,250
我回来了
Well, I'm here.

220
00:27:11,020 --> 00:27:14,590
你会接受报告  重新评估你的服役状态
You'll have to be debriefed and declared fit for active service.

221
00:27:15,200 --> 00:27:17,530
只有通过测试你才能回归
You can only return to duty when you've passed the tests,

222
00:27:17,700 --> 00:27:20,030
所以严肃对待
so take them seriously.

223
00:27:20,470 --> 00:27:22,590
你也许可以先洗个澡
And a shower might be in order.

224
00:27:23,400 --> 00:27:24,870
我回家换身衣服
I'll go home and change.

225
00:27:25,470 --> 00:27:27,340
我们把你的公寓卖了
Oh, we've sold your flat,

226
00:27:27,340 --> 00:27:29,030
你的东西被收进了仓库
put your things into storage.

227
00:27:30,110 --> 00:27:33,170
对一个没有亲属的死亡特工
Standard procedure on the death of an unmarried employee

228
00:27:33,310 --> 00:27:35,580
这是标准程序
with no next of kin.

229
00:27:35,720 --> 00:27:37,380
你该打个电话
You should have called.

230
00:27:37,550 --> 00:27:39,250
我住酒店
I'll find a hotel.

231
00:27:39,590 --> 00:27:41,880
反正你不能睡在这里
Well, you're bloody well not sleeping here.

232
00:28:09,820 --> 00:28:12,380
袭击者入侵了环境控制系统
The assailant hacked into the environmental control system,

233
00:28:12,520 --> 00:28:15,360
隔离了安全协议  释放了瓦斯
locked out the safety protocols and turned on the gas,

234
00:28:15,360 --> 00:28:17,590
而这本该是不可能的
all of which should have been impossible.

235
00:28:17,960 --> 00:28:20,080
另外  他们黑进了她的电脑
On top of that, they hacked into her files.

236
00:28:20,660 --> 00:28:22,210
他们知道她的日程安排
They knew her appointments,

237
00:28:22,210 --> 00:28:23,490
他们知道她不在大楼里
knew she'd be out of the building.

238
00:28:23,660 --> 00:28:25,430
他们不是要杀她
They weren't targeting her.

239
00:28:26,170 --> 00:28:28,000
而是要给她颜色看
They wanted her to see it.

240
00:28:29,440 --> 00:28:30,700
我们在哪里  谭纳
Where are we, Tanner?

241
00:28:30,870 --> 00:28:32,130
新总部
New digs.

242
00:28:40,050 --> 00:28:43,170
旧总部被判定为缺乏战略防御力
The old building was declared "Strategically vulnerable".

243
00:28:43,550 --> 00:28:45,450
说得真婉转
That's putting it mildly.

244
00:28:45,620 --> 00:28:48,920
他能入侵英国最严密的安全系统
He was able to breach the most secure computer system in Britain.

245
00:28:49,060 --> 00:28:50,820
所以我们要进入战备状态
So we're on war footing now.

246
00:28:51,690 --> 00:28:53,820
这是丘吉尔的防空堡垒
This was part of Churchill's bunker.

247
00:28:54,290 --> 00:28:55,520
这里的隧道
We're still discovering tunnels

248
00:28:55,700 --> 00:28:56,960
能追溯到18世纪
dating back to the 18th Century.

249
00:28:57,130 --> 00:28:59,460
很不错  要是没有老鼠就更好了
Quite fascinating, if it wasn't for the rats.

250
00:28:59,700 --> 00:29:01,100
我什么时候能见到M
When do I see M?

251
00:29:01,230 --> 00:29:03,260
明天  如果你走运的话
Tomorrow you'll see M and Mallory, too,

252
00:29:03,270 --> 00:29:04,670
你能见到M和马洛瑞
if you're lucky.

253
00:29:04,840 --> 00:29:05,960
马洛瑞是谁
Who's Mallory?

254
00:29:06,140 --> 00:29:08,770
他是情报安全委员会主席
The new Chairman of the Intelligence and Security Committee.

255
00:29:08,910 --> 00:29:09,450
很不错的人
Charming man.

256
00:29:09,450 --> 00:29:11,480
你们肯定合得来
I think you and he are really going to hit it off.

257
00:29:13,750 --> 00:29:15,720
欢迎来到新军情六处
Welcome to the new MI6.

258
00:29:32,230 --> 00:29:34,860
我们在试图追踪电脑信息
We've attempted to trace the computer message, but

259
00:29:35,070 --> 00:29:38,000
但信息是由一组不对称的安全运算法则发送
it was sent by an asymmetrical security algorithm,

260
00:29:38,170 --> 00:29:39,660
发送的信号分布在全球
which bounced the signal all over the globe

261
00:29:39,770 --> 00:29:41,740
数以千计的不同服务器
through over a thousand different servers.

262
00:29:41,880 --> 00:29:43,540
而他们既然能破解M的密码
And now that they've accessed M's codes,

263
00:29:43,710 --> 00:29:46,300
那么迟早也能破解名单
it's only a matter of time before they're able to decrypt the list.

264
00:29:46,450 --> 00:29:48,910
军需部正在分析图片  但目前还没有结果
Q-Branch have been analyzing the picture but so far nothing.

265
00:29:49,620 --> 00:29:52,310
应该是她过去认识的人
The general feeling is it's probably someone from her past.

266
00:29:52,450 --> 00:29:54,980
也许是她在香港情报站负责的时候
Perhaps when she was running things in Hong Kong.

267
00:29:55,120 --> 00:29:56,520
她完全不知道是怎么回事
She's no idea what it all means.

268
00:29:56,660 --> 00:29:57,750
你相信吗
You believe that?

269
00:29:57,960 --> 00:29:59,930
事实是  我们不知道是谁拿走了名单
The truth is, we don't have a clue who took the list

270
00:30:01,260 --> 00:30:03,320
也不知道他们要拿名单做什么
or what they plan to do with it.

271
00:30:10,200 --> 00:30:11,470
我们可以回头再做
We can always do this later.

272
00:30:12,370 --> 00:30:15,400
嗯  听你的
You know what? Let's.

273
00:31:22,380 --> 00:31:25,400
我会从一些简单的词汇联想开始
I'd like to start with some simple word associations.

274
00:31:25,550 --> 00:31:27,950
告诉我你第一个想到的单词
Just tell me the first word that pops into your head.

275
00:31:28,110 --> 00:31:30,480
比如  我说"今天"  你会说
For example, I might say "Day" And you might say...

276
00:31:30,650 --> 00:31:31,620
浪费
Wasted.

277
00:31:35,890 --> 00:31:37,190
好吧
All right.

278
00:31:41,590 --> 00:31:42,890
枪
Gun.

279
00:31:44,060 --> 00:31:46,000
-射击  -特工
-Shot. -Agent.

280
00:31:46,170 --> 00:31:47,500
内奸
Provocateur.

281
00:31:47,670 --> 00:31:48,630
女人
Woman.

282
00:31:48,740 --> 00:31:49,790
内奸
Provocatrix.

283
00:31:49,900 --> 00:31:50,890
心脏
Heart.

284
00:31:51,000 --> 00:31:51,970
目标
Target.

285
00:31:53,010 --> 00:31:54,170
鸟
Bird.

286
00:31:54,340 --> 00:31:55,500
天空
Sky.

287
00:31:55,710 --> 00:31:56,700
M
M.

288
00:31:56,880 --> 00:31:57,870
贱人
Bitch.

289
00:32:00,310 --> 00:32:01,370
阳光
Sunlight.

290
00:32:01,550 --> 00:32:02,610
游泳
Swim.

291
00:32:02,750 --> 00:32:04,480
-月光  -跳舞
-Moonlight. -Dance.

292
00:32:04,650 --> 00:32:05,810
谋杀
Murder.

293
00:32:06,050 --> 00:32:07,210
工作
Employment.

294
00:32:07,650 --> 00:32:09,520
-国家  -英国
-Country. -England.

295
00:32:09,690 --> 00:32:11,050
天幕
Skyfall.

296
00:32:16,500 --> 00:32:17,900
天幕
Skyfall.

297
00:32:21,330 --> 00:32:22,560
够了
Done.

298
00:32:28,910 --> 00:32:30,840
进展还真不错
Well, this is going well.

299
00:33:18,730 --> 00:33:20,450
拿去分析
Get these analyzed.

300
00:33:21,390 --> 00:33:23,060
只给她看
For her eyes only.

301
00:33:51,460 --> 00:33:53,080
她在等你
She's ready for you.

302
00:33:53,490 --> 00:33:55,650
抱歉  我们见过吗
I'm sorry, have we met before?

303
00:33:56,500 --> 00:33:58,560
我才该说抱歉
I'm the one who should say "Sorry".

304
00:34:00,870 --> 00:34:02,660
我只断了4跟肋骨
It was only four ribs.

305
00:34:03,000 --> 00:34:05,160
加上一些不要紧的器官
Some of the less vital organs.

306
00:34:06,970 --> 00:34:08,370
没什么大碍
Nothing major.

307
00:34:13,780 --> 00:34:15,340
在伊斯坦布尔不够刺激吗
Not enough excitement in Istanbul?

308
00:34:15,550 --> 00:34:17,070
我被调职了
I've been reassigned.

309
00:34:17,220 --> 00:34:19,280
暂时停止外勤工作
Temporary suspension from field work.

310
00:34:19,450 --> 00:34:20,890
-真的吗  -嗯
-Really? -Mmm.

311
00:34:20,990 --> 00:34:22,580
因为我杀了007
Something to do with killing 007.

312
00:34:23,020 --> 00:34:24,720
你尽力瞄准了
Well, you gave it your best shot.

313
00:34:24,890 --> 00:34:26,590
差得远呢
That was hardly my best shot.

314
00:34:27,060 --> 00:34:29,030
那在你最好状态下我可能就活不了了
I'm not sure I could survive your best.

315
00:34:29,230 --> 00:34:30,960
多半活不了
I doubt you'll get the chance.

316
00:34:31,400 --> 00:34:32,690
你能帮我个忙吗
Well, do me a favor, will you?

317
00:34:32,690 --> 00:34:34,370
如果他们派你回去外勤
If they do ever let you back out there,

318
00:34:36,000 --> 00:34:37,130
先警告我一声
warn me first.

319
00:34:37,840 --> 00:34:40,470
我在过渡阶段协助加雷斯·马洛瑞
I'm assisting Gareth Mallory in the transition,

320
00:34:40,640 --> 00:34:42,470
之后我会重新调回外勤
and then I'll be back in the field.

321
00:34:42,910 --> 00:34:44,310
这是你想要的吗
That's what you want?

322
00:34:44,480 --> 00:34:45,880
当然
Yes, of course.

323
00:34:46,180 --> 00:34:47,650
不是每个人都适合的
It's not for everyone.

324
00:34:47,810 --> 00:34:50,040
007  这边
Ah, 007. It's this way.

325
00:34:50,750 --> 00:34:55,550
为你说句话  移动的目标更难击中
In your defense, a moving target is much harder to hit.

326
00:34:57,490 --> 00:34:59,220
那你最好不要停下来
Then you better keep moving.

327
00:35:09,940 --> 00:35:11,630
整个办公室都被炸了
The whole office goes up in smoke

328
00:35:11,800 --> 00:35:13,530
那玩意还好好的啊
and that bloody thing survives.

329
00:35:14,070 --> 00:35:17,530
谢谢你对室内摆饰的建议  007
Your interior decorating tips have always been appreciated, 007.

330
00:35:18,780 --> 00:35:20,870
007  这位是加雷斯·马洛瑞
007, Gareth Mallory.

331
00:35:21,050 --> 00:35:22,410
希望我没来晚
I hope I haven't missed anything.

332
00:35:22,580 --> 00:35:23,980
一有危机首相就特别啰嗦
The PM does prattle on in a crisis.

333
00:35:24,280 --> 00:35:25,250
邦德
Bond.

334
00:35:25,690 --> 00:35:26,740
马洛瑞
Mallory.

335
00:35:31,760 --> 00:35:34,390
我在看邦德的测试结果
I've just been reviewing Bond's tests.

336
00:35:34,690 --> 00:35:37,990
看来你通过了  差一点点
It seems you've passed... by the skin of your teeth.

337
00:35:38,430 --> 00:35:40,230
你可以恢复工作了
You're back on active service.

338
00:35:41,230 --> 00:35:42,290
恭喜
Congratulations.

339
00:35:42,470 --> 00:35:43,560
谢谢
Thank you.

340
00:35:43,940 --> 00:35:45,400
那个
I'll, um...

341
00:35:45,510 --> 00:35:46,600
我在外面等着
I'll be outside.

342
00:35:46,810 --> 00:35:48,930
我只有一个问题
I only have one question.

343
00:35:49,410 --> 00:35:51,500
为什么要回来
Why not stay dead?

344
00:35:52,880 --> 00:35:56,250
你有个绝佳的机会  过上平静的生活
You have the perfect way out. Go and live quietly somewhere.

345
00:35:56,720 --> 00:35:59,620
能这么全身而退的外勤特工并不多
Not many field agents get to leave this cleanly.

346
00:35:59,920 --> 00:36:01,410
你出过很多外勤吗
Do you get out in the field much?

347
00:36:02,960 --> 00:36:06,120
这明摆着的事实  你不用是个特工也能知道
You don't need to be an operative to see the obvious.

348
00:36:07,060 --> 00:36:08,750
这是年轻人的游戏
It's a young man's game.

349
00:36:09,930 --> 00:36:11,560
听着  你受过很重的伤
Look, you've been seriously injured.

350
00:36:11,660 --> 00:36:13,960
说自己不行了并不丢脸
There's no shame in saying you've lost a step.

351
00:36:14,330 --> 00:36:17,030
唯一丢脸的是你到无法挽回了再承认这点
The only shame would be not admitting it until it's too late.

352
00:36:18,270 --> 00:36:21,140
要我还是不要我  由你决定
Hire me or fire me. It's entirely up to you.

353
00:36:21,940 --> 00:36:24,210
如果他说准备好了  那就是准备好了
If he says he's ready, he's ready.

354
00:36:25,140 --> 00:36:27,810
也许你看不出来  或者是你不想看出来
Perhaps you can't see it, or maybe you won't.

355
00:36:28,010 --> 00:36:29,610
你到底在暗示什么
What exactly are you implying?

356
00:36:30,250 --> 00:36:31,610
你对他太感情用事了
You're sentimental about him.

357
00:36:33,320 --> 00:36:35,270
只要我还是军情六处的负责人
As long as I'm head of this department,

358
00:36:35,270 --> 00:36:36,780
我就能选择自己的特工
I'll choose my own operatives.

359
00:36:39,460 --> 00:36:40,820
好吧
Fair enough.

360
00:36:45,000 --> 00:36:46,990
祝你好运  007
Good luck, 007.

361
00:36:47,970 --> 00:36:49,830
不要搞砸了
Don't cock it up.

362
00:36:55,610 --> 00:36:58,670
我们分析了弹片
We've analyzed the shrapnel fragments.

363
00:36:59,780 --> 00:37:01,040
算你走运不是直接命中
You're lucky it wasn't a direct hit

364
00:37:01,210 --> 00:37:02,510
不然你会被撕成两半
or it would have cut you in half.

365
00:37:02,720 --> 00:37:05,910
那是一种废弃铀弹壳  军用级别
It's a depleted uranium shell. Military grade.

366
00:37:06,950 --> 00:37:08,980
很难取到  非常昂贵
Hard to get, extremely expensive,

367
00:37:09,160 --> 00:37:11,750
只有极少数人才会用
and only used by a select few.

368
00:37:12,730 --> 00:37:14,090
认出来了吗
Recognize anyone?

369
00:37:15,830 --> 00:37:17,020
是他
Him.

370
00:37:18,030 --> 00:37:20,430
好吧  他叫帕特里斯
Okay. Name's Patrice.

371
00:37:20,600 --> 00:37:23,000
他就是个幽灵  出生地和国籍均未知
He's a ghost. No known residence or country of origin.

372
00:37:23,170 --> 00:37:24,690
我们怎么找到他
So how do we find him?

373
00:37:24,870 --> 00:37:28,030
好在我们在中情局有几个熟人
Well, luckily, we still have one or two friends left in the CIA.

374
00:37:28,240 --> 00:37:29,940
他们因为他谋杀了也门大使而追查他
They're after him for the Yemeni ambassador's murder,

375
00:37:30,110 --> 00:37:31,840
他们快查到了
and they're getting close.

376
00:37:32,180 --> 00:37:33,940
情报称他两天后会在上海
Intel is he's going to be in Shanghai

377
00:37:34,110 --> 00:37:35,880
可能有新目标
in two days time, probably on a job.

378
00:37:36,520 --> 00:37:38,610
你要去那里等待进一步指示
You're to go there and await further instructions.

379
00:37:38,880 --> 00:37:40,720
他一出现你就拿下他
If he turns up, he's yours.

380
00:37:40,920 --> 00:37:44,190
查出他为谁卖命  以及名单在谁手上
Find out who he works for and who has the list.

381
00:37:44,590 --> 00:37:46,350
之后  杀了他为隆森报仇
Then terminate him, for Ronson.

382
00:37:46,660 --> 00:37:47,990
乐意至极
With pleasure.

383
00:37:49,160 --> 00:37:50,650
你还有什么要告诉我的吗
Is there anything else you want to tell me?

384
00:37:52,470 --> 00:37:53,430
没有了
No.

385
00:37:54,700 --> 00:37:57,290
去找新的军需官报道要你的文件证明
Report to the new Quartermaster for your documentation.

386
00:37:57,900 --> 00:37:59,340
他还没有办公室
He hasn't set up shop yet,

387
00:37:59,340 --> 00:38:02,010
但谭纳会安排你们见面  好运
but Tanner will put you two together. Good luck.

388
00:38:03,210 --> 00:38:04,230
谢谢
Thank you.

389
00:38:07,450 --> 00:38:08,780
007
007.

390
00:38:11,450 --> 00:38:13,010
你准备好了吗
You are ready for this?

391
00:38:14,120 --> 00:38:15,420
是的  长官
Yes, ma'am.

392
00:38:19,390 --> 00:38:21,520
我不知道邦德通过了测试
I didn't know Bond passed the tests.

393
00:38:21,960 --> 00:38:23,360
他没通过
He didn't.

394
00:38:52,860 --> 00:38:55,330
这总是让我觉得有点伤感
Always makes me feel a little melancholy.

395
00:38:55,700 --> 00:38:59,260
一艘巨大的旧式战舰  可耻地被拖去拆解
A grand old warship being ignominiously hauled away for scrap.

396
00:39:02,640 --> 00:39:04,830
不可避免地被时代抛弃  你觉得呢
The inevitability of time, don't you think?

397
00:39:07,640 --> 00:39:08,830
你看到了什么
What do you see?

398
00:39:10,940 --> 00:39:12,470
一艘大得要命的船
A bloody big ship.

399
00:39:13,680 --> 00:39:14,810
不好意思
Excuse me.

400
00:39:15,310 --> 00:39:16,580
007
007...

401
00:39:18,180 --> 00:39:20,150
我是你的新军需官
I'm your new Quartermaster.

402
00:39:21,720 --> 00:39:23,590
你开玩笑呢吧
You must be joking.

403
00:39:23,990 --> 00:39:25,790
怎么  因为我没穿白大褂吗
Why, because I'm not wearing a lab coat?

404
00:39:25,890 --> 00:39:27,920
因为你脸上还有雀斑
Because you still have spots.

405
00:39:28,960 --> 00:39:30,760
我的肤色和这没有关系
My complexion is hardly relevant.

406
00:39:31,030 --> 00:39:32,830
你的能力有关系
Well, your competence is.

407
00:39:33,830 --> 00:39:35,630
年龄不是效率的保证
Age is no guarantee of efficiency.

408
00:39:35,800 --> 00:39:38,500
而年轻也不是创造性的保证
And youth is no guarantee of innovation.

409
00:39:39,170 --> 00:39:40,640
我敢说我穿着睡衣
I'll hazard I can do more damage

410
00:39:40,810 --> 00:39:42,300
喝掉一杯伯爵茶之前
on my laptop sitting in my pajamas

411
00:39:42,480 --> 00:39:44,030
用电脑所能造成的损害
before my first cup of Earl Grey

412
00:39:44,140 --> 00:39:45,800
也要比你一年外勤多得多
than you can do in a year in the field.

413
00:39:45,950 --> 00:39:47,500
那你为什么还需要我
Oh, so why do you need me?

414
00:39:49,250 --> 00:39:51,180
总得有人扣扳机
Every now and then a trigger has to be pulled.

415
00:39:52,180 --> 00:39:53,780
或是不扣
Or not pulled.

416
00:39:54,490 --> 00:39:57,010
你穿着睡衣可没法知道要怎么做
It's hard to know which in your pajamas.

417
00:40:00,860 --> 00:40:02,590
Q
Q.

418
00:40:02,760 --> 00:40:04,490
007
007.

419
00:40:08,930 --> 00:40:10,230
这是去上海的机票
Ticket to Shanghai.

420
00:40:10,440 --> 00:40:11,560
文件和护照
Documentation and passport.

421
00:40:11,740 --> 00:40:12,900
谢谢
Thank you.

422
00:40:13,070 --> 00:40:14,160
还有这个
And this.

423
00:40:18,440 --> 00:40:20,540
瓦尔特PPK型9毫米手枪
Walther PPK/S 9mm short.

424
00:40:22,080 --> 00:40:24,550
枪柄上有个微型皮肤感应器
There's a micro-dermal sensor in the grip.

425
00:40:25,120 --> 00:40:28,210
加密了你的手掌指纹  只有你能开枪
It's been coded to your palm print so only you can fire it.

426
00:40:28,750 --> 00:40:32,490
比起一把杀人机器  更像是一种个人宣言
Less of a random killing machine, more of a personal statement.

427
00:40:32,990 --> 00:40:33,980
这个呢
And this?

428
00:40:35,630 --> 00:40:37,690
标准无线电发射器
Standard issue radio transmitter.

429
00:40:38,760 --> 00:40:41,700
激活就能知道你的位置
Activate it and it broadcasts your location.

430
00:40:42,230 --> 00:40:43,600
这是求救信号
Distress signal.

431
00:40:45,200 --> 00:40:46,400
就这些
And that's it.

432
00:40:48,940 --> 00:40:50,240
一把枪
A gun...

433
00:40:51,110 --> 00:40:52,410
一个无线电
...and a radio.

434
00:40:54,610 --> 00:40:56,740
不算丰富吧
Not exactly Christmas, is it?

435
00:40:57,450 --> 00:41:00,010
你想要一支爆炸钢笔吗
Were you expecting an exploding pen?

436
00:41:01,450 --> 00:41:03,680
我们不再造那种东西了
We don't really go in for that anymore.

437
00:41:11,460 --> 00:41:13,190
祝你好运
Good luck out there in the field.

438
00:41:13,900 --> 00:41:16,770
拜托你把设备完好归还
And please return the equipment in one piece.

439
00:41:22,170 --> 00:41:23,700
世道变了
Brave new world.

440
00:49:43,480 --> 00:49:44,910
名单在谁手上
Who's got the list?

441
00:49:49,750 --> 00:49:52,150
告诉我  你为谁效力
Tell me! Who are you working for?

442
00:51:21,340 --> 00:51:24,310
谭纳  他已经发出了五个名字
Tanner... He's posted the first five names.

443
00:51:24,740 --> 00:51:27,440
他们暴露了  有危险  赶紧把他们撤出来
Their cover's blown. They're in danger. Get them out now.

444
00:52:07,720 --> 00:52:09,210
客房服务
Room service.

445
00:52:17,900 --> 00:52:20,690
我没有点东西  更没点你
I didn't order anything. Not even you.

446
00:52:21,230 --> 00:52:22,700
我有了新情报
I've got some new information.

447
00:52:23,940 --> 00:52:27,430
你来送情报有点大材小用了吧
Aren't you a little overqualified to be delivering messages?

448
00:52:27,840 --> 00:52:30,210
这都是学习过程
It's all part of the learning curve.

449
00:52:30,810 --> 00:52:32,610
而且Q害怕坐飞机
And Q's afraid of flying.

450
00:52:33,380 --> 00:52:34,810
当然了
Of course he is.

451
00:52:35,250 --> 00:52:38,710
偷走名单的人已经解密了名单
So whoever stole the list has already decrypted it.

452
00:52:39,620 --> 00:52:41,880
他们将头五个名字发在了网上
They posted the first five names on the web.

453
00:52:42,320 --> 00:52:44,250
这只是时间问题
Well, it was only a matter of time.

454
00:52:44,420 --> 00:52:45,820
这只是个开始
Well, that's just the start.

455
00:52:46,090 --> 00:52:48,890
每过一周他们会再发五个
They're posting five more next week, and the week after.

456
00:52:49,860 --> 00:52:51,660
就像是虐待狂的游戏
It's some kind of sadistic game.

457
00:52:56,940 --> 00:52:58,730
用剃须刀刮胡子
Cut-throat razor.

458
00:53:00,110 --> 00:53:02,070
真传统
How very traditional.

459
00:53:03,310 --> 00:53:06,070
有时候我喜欢老派作风
Well, I like to do some things the old-fashioned way.

460
00:53:08,950 --> 00:53:11,350
有时候还是老办法最好
Sometimes the old ways are the best.

461
00:53:22,030 --> 00:53:24,590
你又要把自己的命交到我手里吗
Are you putting your life in my hands again?

462
00:53:27,070 --> 00:53:31,600
名单的事M已经告诉过我了
M's... already briefed me on the list.

463
00:53:32,970 --> 00:53:34,940
所以我不禁好奇
Raising the tantalizing question

464
00:53:35,110 --> 00:53:37,100
你到这里来的真正原因
of what you're really doing here.

465
00:53:38,340 --> 00:53:40,830
官方的指示是要我提供帮助
My official directive was to help...

466
00:53:42,550 --> 00:53:44,610
各种各样的帮助
"In any way I can."

467
00:53:46,150 --> 00:53:48,780
比如帮马洛瑞监视我吗
Like spying for Mallory.

468
00:53:50,760 --> 00:53:53,450
要知道  马洛瑞没你想的这么坏
You know, Mallory's not as bad as you think.

469
00:53:54,660 --> 00:53:56,460
他是个官僚
He's a bureaucrat.

470
00:53:57,230 --> 00:53:59,220
你该做做功课
You should do your homework.

471
00:54:00,000 --> 00:54:02,400
加雷斯·马洛瑞前中校
Gareth Mallory was a Lieutenant Colonel...

472
00:54:02,570 --> 00:54:05,230
曾在北爱尔兰赫尔福德军团服役
Lieutenant Colonel in Northern Ireland, Hereford Regiment.

473
00:54:05,400 --> 00:54:07,840
他被爱尔兰共和军监禁了三个月
Spent three months at the hands of the IRA.

474
00:54:09,540 --> 00:54:12,310
所以他远不止看上去的那样
So there's more to him than meets the eye.

475
00:54:15,010 --> 00:54:16,310
到时就知道了
We'll see.

476
00:54:18,380 --> 00:54:19,650
别动
Keep still.

477
00:54:22,220 --> 00:54:24,150
这里比较难搞
This is the tricky part.

478
00:54:35,770 --> 00:54:37,670
这样好多了
Now that's better.

479
00:54:38,940 --> 00:54:40,030
现在能看出来了
You look the part now.

480
00:54:43,640 --> 00:54:45,440
看出来什么
And what part's that?

481
00:54:47,480 --> 00:54:49,000
老家伙
Old dog,

482
00:54:50,220 --> 00:54:52,010
新花样
new tricks.

483
00:56:03,990 --> 00:56:05,390
晚上好
Good evening.

484
00:56:05,560 --> 00:56:06,960
晚上好
Evening.

485
00:56:07,160 --> 00:56:08,890
不要碰耳朵
Don't touch your ear.

486
00:56:10,300 --> 00:56:12,230
这里有三个出口
I've got three exits,

487
00:56:13,160 --> 00:56:15,060
还有很多盲点
lots of blind spots.

488
00:56:15,670 --> 00:56:17,230
我负责掩护
I've got them covered.

489
00:56:23,580 --> 00:56:25,570
你穿这一身很漂亮
You look beautiful in that dress.

490
00:56:25,740 --> 00:56:27,370
你自己也不赖
You don 't scrub up so bad yourself.

491
00:56:27,510 --> 00:56:30,450
多个帮手的效果总是出人意料
It's amazing what one can do with an extra pair of hands.

492
00:56:30,980 --> 00:56:32,610
你也会说这种话吗
You're telling me.

493
00:56:34,320 --> 00:56:35,980
你赌博吗
Do you gamble?

494
00:56:36,150 --> 00:56:37,820
时不时小赌几把
I like a little flutter now and then.

495
00:56:40,330 --> 00:56:42,920
谁不喜欢冒险呢
Who doesn't like to take chances?

496
00:56:48,330 --> 00:56:50,270
晚上好  先生  有什么事吗
Good evening, sir. How may I help you?

497
00:56:50,440 --> 00:56:52,430
我想要兑成现金  谢谢
I'd like to cash this in, please.

498
00:56:59,040 --> 00:57:00,440
稍等  先生
One moment, sir.

499
00:57:32,980 --> 00:57:34,470
今晚运气不错  先生
Good fortune tonight, sir.

500
00:57:40,720 --> 00:57:42,150
但愿如此
Let's hope so.

501
00:57:51,200 --> 00:57:52,820
我代表赌场祝贺你
With compliments of the house.

502
00:57:53,000 --> 00:57:54,660
谢谢
Thank you.

503
00:58:15,750 --> 00:58:18,350
你能请我喝一杯吗
Now you can afford to buy me a drink.

504
00:58:20,560 --> 00:58:22,860
也许不止一杯
Maybe I'll even stretch to two.

505
00:58:24,130 --> 00:58:26,530
我估计我手上拿着四百万欧元
I'm guessing I've got four million euros in here.

506
00:58:27,030 --> 00:58:29,500
不错  我喜欢这游戏
Not bad. I like this game.

507
00:58:30,200 --> 00:58:31,760
想玩玩看其他的吗
Why don't we play another?

508
00:58:33,140 --> 00:58:34,870
我不赌博
I don't gamble.

509
00:58:38,040 --> 00:58:39,910
我运气不好
I'm not very lucky.

510
00:58:40,080 --> 00:58:42,210
就像我们那位上海的朋友
A little like our friend in Shanghai.

511
00:58:46,280 --> 00:58:49,550
我一直期待着是谁来兑现这些筹码
I've been waiting to see who would redeem the chip.

512
00:58:49,990 --> 00:58:53,450
你的登场方式非常高调
You made such a bold entrance into our little drama.

513
00:58:53,760 --> 00:58:55,850
我把剧情复杂化了吗
Did I over-complicate the plot?

514
00:58:57,230 --> 00:59:00,060
谁不喜欢曲折的剧情呢  怎么称呼
Who doesn't appreciate the occasional twist, Mr...?

515
00:59:00,770 --> 00:59:01,990
邦德
Bond.

516
00:59:02,100 --> 00:59:03,360
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.

517
00:59:04,500 --> 00:59:05,900
我叫塞芙琳
Severine.

518
00:59:06,170 --> 00:59:07,310
邦德先生
So, Mr. Bond,

519
00:59:07,310 --> 00:59:10,730
我们喝完这杯后再谈谈你下一场表演如何
shall we discuss your next performance over that drink?

520
00:59:11,510 --> 00:59:12,910
我很乐意
I'd like that.

521
00:59:15,950 --> 00:59:18,110
你朋友也要一起来吗
Will your friends be joining us?

522
00:59:20,120 --> 00:59:22,920
是的  恐怕不得不来
That, I'm afraid, is inevitable.

523
00:59:26,360 --> 00:59:27,480
她很漂亮
She's pretty.

524
00:59:27,660 --> 00:59:28,820
我知道
Now, now.

525
00:59:29,030 --> 00:59:31,090
如果你喜欢那种类型
If you like that sort of thing.

526
00:59:31,830 --> 00:59:33,490
我会告诉你的
I'll keep you posted.

527
00:59:45,340 --> 00:59:46,440
好极了
Perfect.

528
00:59:49,010 --> 00:59:52,010
你介意我问你个商业问题吗
Would you mind if I asked you a business question?

529
00:59:53,050 --> 00:59:54,640
那要看是什么问题了
Depends on the question.

530
00:59:55,490 --> 00:59:57,850
和死亡有关
It has to do with death.

531
00:59:59,460 --> 01:00:02,190
一个你很精通的话题
A subject in which you're well-versed.

532
01:00:02,560 --> 01:00:04,150
何以见得
And how would you know that?

533
01:00:05,560 --> 01:00:08,360
只有一种女人会穿着露背晚礼服
Only a certain kind of woman wears a backless dress

534
01:00:08,530 --> 01:00:11,700
大腿上还绑着贝雷塔点70手枪
with a Beretta 70 strapped to her thigh.

535
01:00:12,200 --> 01:00:14,900
当一个穿着燕尾服带着瓦尔特手枪的帅哥
One can never be too careful when

536
01:00:15,070 --> 01:00:17,800
和你打交道的时候  你总是要再小心不过
handsome men in tuxedos carry Walthers.

537
01:00:20,380 --> 01:00:23,210
这么说我没猜错  是你杀了帕特里斯吗
I am correct in assuming you killed Patrice?

538
01:00:24,380 --> 01:00:25,640
是的
Yes.

539
01:00:27,520 --> 01:00:29,210
我能问下为什么吗
Might I ask why?

540
01:00:30,590 --> 01:00:32,220
我想要见你的雇主
I want to meet your employer.

541
01:00:44,840 --> 01:00:47,000
小心你想要做的事
Be careful what you wish for.

542
01:00:48,940 --> 01:00:50,130
你害怕了
You're scared.

543
01:00:51,440 --> 01:00:52,910
谢谢你的酒
Thank you for the drink,

544
01:00:55,110 --> 01:00:56,510
邦德先生
Mr. Bond.

545
01:01:04,360 --> 01:01:06,350
你的演技不错
You put on a good show.

546
01:01:08,560 --> 01:01:10,030
但自从我们一坐下来
But ever since we sat down,

547
01:01:10,030 --> 01:01:12,600
你就一直盯着你的保镖看
you haven't stopped looking at your bodyguards.

548
01:01:14,570 --> 01:01:16,590
三个保镖未免也太多了吧
Now, three of them is a bit excessive.

549
01:01:17,470 --> 01:01:20,490
他们在控制你  不是在保护你
They're controlling you. They're not protecting you.

550
01:01:23,040 --> 01:01:25,940
你手腕上的纹身  是澳门性交易的标志
The tattoo on your wrist is Macau sex trade.

551
01:01:26,110 --> 01:01:27,930
你是赌场的人吧
You belonged to one of the houses.

552
01:01:27,940 --> 01:01:30,570
从12岁开始  还是13岁
What were you? 12? 13?

553
01:01:32,420 --> 01:01:34,280
我猜是他帮你赎的身
I'm guessing he was your way out.

554
01:01:35,620 --> 01:01:37,710
也许你觉得你爱他
Perhaps you thought you were in love.

555
01:01:39,490 --> 01:01:41,620
但那是很久以前的事了
But that was a long time ago.

556
01:01:44,060 --> 01:01:46,050
你对我一无所知
You know nothing about it.

557
01:01:46,600 --> 01:01:49,730
我知道一个女人明明很怕却又假装不怕
I know when a woman is afraid and pretending not to be.

558
01:01:53,300 --> 01:01:55,140
你对恐惧有多了解
How much do you know about fear?

559
01:01:56,010 --> 01:01:57,470
我都了解
All there is.

560
01:01:58,980 --> 01:02:00,570
你不了解这种恐惧
Not like this.

561
01:02:03,250 --> 01:02:04,740
你不了解他
Not like him.

562
01:02:06,250 --> 01:02:07,650
我能帮你
I can help you.

563
01:02:08,750 --> 01:02:09,740
算了吧
I don't think so.

564
01:02:09,920 --> 01:02:10,910
让我试试
Let me try.

565
01:02:13,690 --> 01:02:14,750
怎么帮
How?

566
01:02:16,090 --> 01:02:17,580
带我去见他
Bring me to him.

567
01:02:20,530 --> 01:02:21,520
你能杀了他吗
Can you kill him?

568
01:02:21,630 --> 01:02:22,600
是的
Yes.

569
01:02:24,340 --> 01:02:25,300
你会杀了他吗
Will you?

570
01:02:26,040 --> 01:02:27,770
人总免不了一死
Someone usually dies.

571
01:02:32,710 --> 01:02:34,340
也许你能杀了他
Perhaps you can.

572
01:02:42,490 --> 01:02:44,750
我一走  他们就会杀了你
When I leave, they're going to kill you.

573
01:02:45,660 --> 01:02:48,970
要是你没死  来奇美拉号上找我
If you survive, I'm on the Chimera.

574
01:02:48,970 --> 01:02:49,750
北部港口
North harbor.

575
01:02:50,800 --> 01:02:52,350
7号泊位
Berth seven.

576
01:02:53,700 --> 01:02:55,860
我们一小时后开船
We cast off in an hour.

577
01:03:01,340 --> 01:03:03,360
很高兴见到你  邦德先生
Very nice to have met you, Mr. Bond.

578
01:03:05,340 --> 01:03:06,540
祝你好运
Good luck.

579
01:04:32,830 --> 01:04:33,990
用得开心
Good luck with that.

580
01:04:58,690 --> 01:04:59,780
谢谢
Thank you.

581
01:05:04,960 --> 01:05:06,050
都押在红色上
Put it all on red.

582
01:05:08,970 --> 01:05:10,630
这是生命的循环
It's the circle of life.

583
01:05:34,890 --> 01:05:35,920
什么事
Yes!

584
01:05:39,960 --> 01:05:41,690
该开船了
It's time to cast off.

585
01:05:43,630 --> 01:05:44,790
好的
All right.

586
01:06:40,520 --> 01:06:43,220
你喜欢你不带枪的样子
I like you better without your Beretta.

587
01:06:46,700 --> 01:06:48,560
不带枪让我觉得像是没穿衣服
I feel naked without it.

588
01:07:05,950 --> 01:07:06,940
晚上好
Good evening.

589
01:07:07,120 --> 01:07:08,430
围绕国防部的争议
The controversy surrounding

590
01:07:08,430 --> 01:07:10,520
今天又升级了
the Ministry of Defence has escalated today

591
01:07:10,650 --> 01:07:14,280
由于侯赛因被杀的画面一直在被循环播放
as images of the Husein assassination continue to circulate.

592
01:07:14,690 --> 01:07:15,700
我们必须警告你
We should warn you,

593
01:07:15,700 --> 01:07:18,220
这些画面可能会让人不适
some viewers might find these images disturbing.

594
01:07:19,760 --> 01:07:22,930
侯赛因上尉  在中东卧底的军情六处特工
Captain Husein, an MI6 operative embedded in the Middle East,

595
01:07:23,270 --> 01:07:25,000
是五名被暴露的特工之一
was one of the five agents exposed

596
01:07:25,170 --> 01:07:26,900
这起情报泄露事件
in what is now being considered

597
01:07:27,070 --> 01:07:30,560
被认为是现代英国史上最严重的内部安全漏洞
the greatest internal security breach in modern British history.

598
01:07:31,080 --> 01:07:34,740
首相继续公开表示对军情六处的支持
The Prime Minister continues to express public support for MI6

599
01:07:34,910 --> 01:07:36,970
而反对派已经指出
while the opposition has taken the position...

600
01:07:37,350 --> 01:07:39,780
指出我们是一群愚蠢的老古董
Has taken the position we're a bunch of antiquated bloody idiots

601
01:07:39,880 --> 01:07:42,940
在打一场我们不明白也赢不了的战争
fighting a war we don't understand and can't possibly win.

602
01:07:43,420 --> 01:07:45,180
听着  我已经死了三个特工了
Look, three of my agents are dead already.

603
01:07:45,360 --> 01:07:47,150
现在别和我扯政治问题
Don't embroil me in politics now.

604
01:07:47,660 --> 01:07:50,590
首相要求召开质询会  到时你必须出席
The Prime Minister's ordered an inquiry. You'll have to appear.

605
01:07:50,800 --> 01:07:52,850
大白天在大庭广众下露面吗
Oh, standing in the stocks at midday?

606
01:07:52,850 --> 01:07:54,030
到底谁是老古董
Who's antiquated now?

607
01:07:54,270 --> 01:07:56,390
天啊  你这是什么话  我们是民主国家
For Christ's sake, listen to yourself. We're a democracy,

608
01:07:56,500 --> 01:07:59,090
我们要对这个国家的人民负责
accountable to the people we're trying to defend.

609
01:07:59,200 --> 01:08:01,090
我们不能一直在阴影下工作
We can't keep working in the shadows.

610
01:08:01,090 --> 01:08:02,300
现在已经没有阴影了
There are no more shadows.

611
01:08:02,710 --> 01:08:04,200
你还是不明白吧
You don't get this, do you?

612
01:08:05,710 --> 01:08:08,680
不管幕后黑手是谁  他一定很了解我们
Whoever's behind this, whoever's doing it, he knows us.

613
01:08:09,010 --> 01:08:10,390
他是我们的一员
He's one of us.

614
01:08:10,390 --> 01:08:12,040
他和邦德都来自同一个地方
He comes from the same place as Bond.

615
01:08:12,620 --> 01:08:14,170
那个地方在你看来不存在了
The place you say doesn't exist.

616
01:08:15,490 --> 01:08:16,980
阴影
The shadows.

617
01:08:54,560 --> 01:08:57,350
现在后悔还不算晚
It's not too late. We could turn back now.

618
01:09:03,960 --> 01:09:05,860
我可不这么想
I wouldn't be so sure.

619
01:09:43,600 --> 01:09:46,000
所有人一夜之间都逃走了
They abandoned it almost overnight.

620
01:09:47,140 --> 01:09:50,410
他让他们以为这里的化工厂发生了泄露
He made them think there was a leak at the chemical plant.

621
01:09:52,180 --> 01:09:55,110
想不到只用一台电脑就能制造一场恐慌
It's amazing the panic you can cause with a single computer.

622
01:09:56,650 --> 01:10:00,140
他想要这座岛  岛就是他的了
He wanted the island, so he took it.

623
01:10:01,790 --> 01:10:04,310
他总能得到他想要的东西吗
Does he always get what he wants?

624
01:10:05,130 --> 01:10:06,750
你想象不到
More than you know.

625
01:10:10,000 --> 01:10:11,120
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.

626
01:10:39,890 --> 01:10:41,950
你好  詹姆斯  欢迎
Hello, James. Welcome.

627
01:10:43,220 --> 01:10:44,850
你喜欢这座岛吗
Do you like the island?

628
01:10:48,100 --> 01:10:49,720
我奶奶以前有座岛
My grandmother had an island.

629
01:10:50,200 --> 01:10:51,730
没什么了不起
Nothing to boast of.

630
01:10:51,730 --> 01:10:53,400
你用一个小时就可以逛一圈
You could walk around it in an hour.

631
01:10:53,770 --> 01:10:56,570
但那里仍是我们曾经的天堂
But still, it was, it was a paradise for us.

632
01:10:57,440 --> 01:10:59,670
有一年夏天我们去那岛上
One summer, we went for a visit

633
01:10:59,870 --> 01:11:03,810
发现岛上都是老鼠
and discovered the place had been infested with rats!

634
01:11:04,250 --> 01:11:08,410
渔船把它们带上岛  靠吃椰子为生
They'd come on a fishing boat and gorged themselves on coconut.

635
01:11:08,750 --> 01:11:11,240
怎样消灭岛上的老鼠呢
So how do you get rats off an island? Hmm?

636
01:11:12,050 --> 01:11:13,920
我奶奶给我上了一课
My grandmother showed me.

637
01:11:14,860 --> 01:11:17,550
我们在地下埋了一个油桶  装上铰链盖
We buried an oil drum and hinged the lid,

638
01:11:17,730 --> 01:11:19,920
然后在盖子上用椰子作诱饵
then wired coconut to the lid as bait.

639
01:11:20,200 --> 01:11:22,060
老鼠们会来吃椰子
And the rats would come for the coconut and...

640
01:11:23,930 --> 01:11:25,700
然后就会掉进桶里
...they would fall into the drum.

641
01:11:26,470 --> 01:11:29,930
1个月后所有老鼠都落入圈套
And after a month, you have trapped all the rats.

642
01:11:30,940 --> 01:11:32,600
然后该怎么做
But what do you do then?

643
01:11:33,710 --> 01:11:35,570
是把桶扔到大海里
Throw the drum into the ocean?

644
01:11:36,480 --> 01:11:38,540
还是烧了  不
Burn it? No.

645
01:11:38,910 --> 01:11:40,940
你就把桶放在那里
You just leave it.

646
01:11:41,980 --> 01:11:44,280
老鼠们越来越饿
And they begin to get hungry.

647
01:11:45,150 --> 01:11:46,880
然后一个接一个
And one by one...

648
01:11:49,220 --> 01:11:50,920
他们开始吃同伴
...they start eating each other

649
01:11:51,160 --> 01:11:54,390
最后只剩下两只幸存者
until there are only two left. The two survivors.

650
01:11:55,130 --> 01:11:57,190
然后呢  杀了它们吗  不
And then what? Do you kill them? No.

651
01:11:57,970 --> 01:12:01,130
你把它们放回树林
You take them and release them into the trees.

652
01:12:01,600 --> 01:12:04,300
但现在它们不再吃椰子了
But now they don't eat coconut anymore.

653
01:12:04,670 --> 01:12:06,970
只吃老鼠
Now they only eat rat.

654
01:12:08,610 --> 01:12:10,980
你已经改变了它们的天性
You have changed their nature.

655
01:12:13,010 --> 01:12:14,350
两个幸存者
The two survivors,

656
01:12:15,250 --> 01:12:16,840
这是她造就的我们
this is what she made us.

657
01:12:19,650 --> 01:12:21,650
这是我自己的选择
I made my own choices.

658
01:12:21,960 --> 01:12:24,020
你这么以为而已
You think you did.

659
01:12:25,260 --> 01:12:26,590
她最擅长这个
That's her genius.

660
01:12:29,030 --> 01:12:32,520
你是香港情报站的吧
Station H. Am I right? Hong Kong.

661
01:12:34,300 --> 01:12:36,460
从86年到97年
'86 to '97.

662
01:12:37,210 --> 01:12:39,400
当时我可是她的最爱
Back then, I was her favorite.

663
01:12:39,610 --> 01:12:43,070
我可以说  你和我当年没法比
And you're not nearly the agent I was, I can tell you that.

664
01:12:44,780 --> 01:12:45,910
看看现在的你
Just look at you,

665
01:12:45,910 --> 01:12:49,240
靠药物和酒精在勉强支撑
barely held together by your pills and your drink.

666
01:12:49,380 --> 01:12:51,110
别忘了我那可怜的爱国心
Don't forget my pathetic love of country.

667
01:12:53,490 --> 01:12:56,820
你还是对那个老女人这么忠诚
You're still clinging to your faith in that old woman.

668
01:12:57,290 --> 01:12:59,660
-而她却一直在骗你  -她没骗过我
-When all she does is lie to you. -She never lied to me.

669
01:12:59,760 --> 01:13:01,350
-没有吗  -没有
-No? -No.

670
01:13:01,800 --> 01:13:03,890
你的射击测验得了多少分
What did you score in your marksmanship evaluation?

671
01:13:04,070 --> 01:13:05,260
70分
70.

672
01:13:06,730 --> 01:13:08,000
40分
40.

673
01:13:10,040 --> 01:13:12,440
她还说你的心理测试通过了吗
Did she tell you the psychologist cleared you for duty?

674
01:13:12,570 --> 01:13:14,870
-对  -不  没有
-Yes. -No. No.

675
01:13:23,420 --> 01:13:25,600
医学鉴定  不合格
Medical evaluation: Fail.

676
01:13:25,600 --> 01:13:27,790
身体机能鉴定  不合格
Physical evaluation: Failed.

677
01:13:28,160 --> 01:13:29,770
心理学鉴定
Psychological evaluation:

678
01:13:29,770 --> 01:13:32,620
有滥用酒精和药物倾向
"Alcohol and substance addiction indicated."

679
01:13:35,400 --> 01:13:37,800
由于童年时期的创伤
"Pathological rejection of authority

680
01:13:37,970 --> 01:13:40,370
而在病理上排斥权威
"Based on unresolved childhood trauma."

681
01:13:46,240 --> 01:13:48,680
被鉴定者不被批准进行外勤任务
"Subject is not approved for field duty

682
01:13:48,840 --> 01:13:51,870
并且建议立即停止其特工工作
"And immediate suspension from service advised."

683
01:13:52,210 --> 01:13:54,240
这还不算是背叛吗
What is this if not betrayal?

684
01:13:54,420 --> 01:13:56,950
她明知道你不行
She sent you after me knowing you're not ready,

685
01:13:56,950 --> 01:13:58,350
却还派你来送死
knowing you'll likely die.

686
01:13:58,590 --> 01:14:01,050
妈咪可真坏
Mommy was very bad!

687
01:14:24,910 --> 01:14:26,900
看看她都对你做了什么
See what she's done to you?

688
01:14:28,250 --> 01:14:30,910
至少她没把我绑在椅子上
Well, she never tied me to a chair.

689
01:14:31,250 --> 01:14:32,690
她的损失
Her loss.

690
01:14:36,620 --> 01:14:38,750
你确定你是在针对M吗
Are you sure this is about M?

691
01:14:38,930 --> 01:14:40,190
是针对她...
It's about her.

692
01:14:41,330 --> 01:14:43,420
还有你和我
And you, and me.

693
01:14:44,670 --> 01:14:47,430
我们是最后幸存的两只老鼠
You see, we are the last two rats.

694
01:14:47,840 --> 01:14:49,860
我们要么吃了对方
We can either eat each other...

695
01:14:56,610 --> 01:14:58,480
要么就去吃别人
...or eat everyone else.

696
01:15:01,280 --> 01:15:04,770
开始试图回想之前的训练了吗
How you're trying to remember your training now.

697
01:15:06,290 --> 01:15:08,720
现在的情况该怎么办
What's the regulation to cover this?

698
01:15:12,490 --> 01:15:15,590
凡是总得有第一次  是吧
Well, first time for everything. Yes?

699
01:15:18,700 --> 01:15:21,640
你怎么知道这是我第一次
What makes you think this is my first time?

700
01:15:22,840 --> 01:15:24,900
哎呀  邦德先生
Oh, Mr. Bond!

701
01:15:27,340 --> 01:15:31,300
那些体力活都太无聊了
All that physical stuff... So dull, so dull.

702
01:15:34,150 --> 01:15:35,380
追逐间谍
Chasing spies...

703
01:15:35,720 --> 01:15:37,550
太老派了
so old-fashioned!

704
01:15:40,990 --> 01:15:42,820
你的膝盖肯定疼得要命
Your knees must be killing you.

705
01:15:47,630 --> 01:15:48,930
英格兰
England.

706
01:15:49,500 --> 01:15:51,830
大英帝国  军情六处
The Empire! MI6!

707
01:15:52,400 --> 01:15:54,270
你也和我一样生活在一片废墟中
You're living in a ruin as well,

708
01:15:54,600 --> 01:15:56,130
只是你还没有发现
you just don't know it yet.

709
01:15:57,570 --> 01:16:00,840
至少我这里没有老女人发号施令
At least here there are no old ladies giving orders

710
01:16:00,840 --> 01:16:01,980
也没有那些
and no little...

711
01:16:03,110 --> 01:16:04,100
怎么说
Bip!

712
01:16:04,210 --> 01:16:06,680
军需部的蠢货给你的小玩意
Gadgets from those fools in Q-Branch.

713
01:16:09,750 --> 01:16:13,240
如果你愿意  你可以自己选择任务
If you wanted, you could pick your own secret missions.

714
01:16:13,240 --> 01:16:14,210
就像我一样
As I do.

715
01:16:16,760 --> 01:16:17,950
随便你选
Name it.

716
01:16:18,860 --> 01:16:20,020
随你高兴
Name it.

717
01:16:22,930 --> 01:16:25,760
通过操纵股市整垮跨国公司
Destabilize a multinational by manipulating stocks...

718
01:16:25,970 --> 01:16:26,930
容易
Bip. Easy.

719
01:16:28,270 --> 01:16:31,360
阻截侦查喀布尔的间谍卫星信号
Interrupt transmissions from a spy satellite over Kabul...

720
01:16:31,670 --> 01:16:32,640
小菜一碟
Done.

721
01:16:33,240 --> 01:16:35,090
操纵乌干达的选举
Hmm. Rig an election in Uganda.

722
01:16:35,090 --> 01:16:37,300
出价最高的候选人胜出
All to the highest bidder.

723
01:16:37,880 --> 01:16:40,010
或者在伦敦制造瓦斯爆炸
Or a gas explosion in London.

724
01:16:41,280 --> 01:16:42,720
只需动一动鼠标
Just point and click.

725
01:16:43,120 --> 01:16:44,810
每个人都有点小爱好
Well, everybody needs a hobby.

726
01:16:50,690 --> 01:16:52,490
那你的爱好是什么
So what's yours?

727
01:16:55,200 --> 01:16:56,720
重生
Resurrection.

728
01:17:00,570 --> 01:17:02,330
我带你去看点东西
Let me show you something.

729
01:17:14,920 --> 01:17:16,910
你能想象吧
Tells a story, doesn't it?

730
01:17:21,120 --> 01:17:22,850
他们跑得这么匆忙
They left the island so quickly,

731
01:17:23,020 --> 01:17:24,750
都不知道该带走什么好
they couldn't decide what to take,

732
01:17:25,060 --> 01:17:26,960
也不知道什么东西重要
what to leave, what was important.

733
01:17:27,300 --> 01:17:31,200
这提醒我要集中精力在最重要的东西上
And seeing this every day reminds me to focus on the essentials.

734
01:17:31,430 --> 01:17:35,100
我的人生中没有多余的东西
There's nothing...nothing superfluous in my life.

735
01:17:35,400 --> 01:17:38,930
多余的东西都被我毁掉了
When a thing is redundant, it is eliminated.

736
01:17:49,250 --> 01:17:51,280
50年的麦卡伦威士忌
50-year-old Macallan.

737
01:17:51,850 --> 01:17:54,720
我知道这是你的最爱
A particular favorite of yours, I understand.

738
01:17:56,660 --> 01:17:59,290
那么  要敬给谁呢
So, what's the toast?

739
01:18:02,100 --> 01:18:03,890
敬我们爱的女人
"To the women we love"?

740
01:18:14,840 --> 01:18:16,140
亲爱的
Darling.

741
01:18:17,040 --> 01:18:19,810
亲爱的  你的情人们来了
Darling, your lovers are here.

742
01:18:25,350 --> 01:18:26,790
不不不
No, no, no, no.

743
01:18:27,390 --> 01:18:29,360
站直了别动
Stand up straight. Keep still.

744
01:18:30,990 --> 01:18:33,120
不管做什么  头不要动
And whatever you do, don't lose your head.

745
01:18:33,330 --> 01:18:34,690
头
Don't lose...

746
01:18:35,160 --> 01:18:36,360
千万别动
your head.

747
01:18:38,900 --> 01:18:40,960
千万别动
Don't lose your head.

748
01:18:41,900 --> 01:18:44,770
该为你的射击分数一雪前耻了
Time to redeem your marksmanship scores.

749
01:18:46,370 --> 01:18:47,670
让我们看看
Let's see.

750
01:18:48,410 --> 01:18:52,680
谁先能打中她头上的杯子
Who can be the first to knock the glass from her head?

751
01:18:58,750 --> 01:19:01,520
发扬运动精神  我让你先打
And just to be sporting, I'll let you go first.

752
01:19:19,740 --> 01:19:22,000
看看我们谁能占"上"风
Let's see who ends up on top.

753
01:19:35,060 --> 01:19:36,890
真不敢相信
Oh, I can't believe it.

754
01:19:37,260 --> 01:19:40,660
难以置信  你那天真的死了吗
I can't believe it! Did you really die that day?

755
01:19:41,700 --> 01:19:45,500
你还是过去的那个007吗
Is there any, any of the old 007 left?

756
01:19:54,110 --> 01:19:55,410
轮到我了
My turn.

757
01:19:59,080 --> 01:20:01,910
我赢了  对此你有什么高见
I win. What do you say to that?

758
01:20:04,790 --> 01:20:06,690
白白浪费了那么好的威士忌
It's a waste of good Scotch.

759
01:20:18,130 --> 01:20:19,670
现在你要怎么办
What are you going to do now?

760
01:20:19,670 --> 01:20:21,620
把我交给她吗  你就一个人
Take me back to her? All on your own?

761
01:20:22,340 --> 01:20:24,070
谁说就我一个人
Who says I'm on my own?

762
01:20:43,090 --> 01:20:45,420
军需部的最新产品
It's the latest thing from Q-Branch.

763
01:20:45,990 --> 01:20:47,930
这叫无线电
It's called a radio.

764
01:21:08,820 --> 01:21:11,150
好吧  该和他打声招呼了
All right, time to say hello.

765
01:21:43,920 --> 01:21:46,150
你比我记忆中的要瘦小
You're smaller than I remember!

766
01:21:47,250 --> 01:21:49,150
但我几乎不记得你什么样了
Whereas I barely remember you at all.

767
01:21:49,620 --> 01:21:52,680
奇怪  我觉得就像昨天刚发生的事
Strange. For me, it feels just like yesterday.

768
01:21:54,760 --> 01:21:56,060
你惊讶吗
Are you surprised?

769
01:21:56,400 --> 01:21:59,590
不很惊讶  但你总是这么狡猾
Not particularly. But then you always were a slippery one.

770
01:21:59,970 --> 01:22:02,060
所以你才会这么喜欢我吧
Maybe that's why you liked me so much.

771
01:22:02,470 --> 01:22:03,900
你太看得起自己了
You flatter yourself.

772
01:22:04,070 --> 01:22:05,540
你毫不后悔
No remorse.

773
01:22:07,940 --> 01:22:10,070
就和我想的一样
Just as I had imagined.

774
01:22:10,910 --> 01:22:12,380
外行才会后悔
Regret is unprofessional.

775
01:22:19,390 --> 01:22:20,680
外行才会后悔
"Regret is unprofessional."

776
01:22:20,820 --> 01:22:24,500
他们把我关在密闭的房间里好几个月
They kept me for five months in a room with no air.

777
01:22:24,500 --> 01:22:25,850
他们折磨我
They tortured me.

778
01:22:26,490 --> 01:22:29,050
我一直没有供出机密  就为了保护你
And I protected your secrets. I protected you.

779
01:22:30,430 --> 01:22:33,460
但他们不断折磨我  让我痛苦万分
But they made me suffer. And suffer.

780
01:22:35,300 --> 01:22:37,030
生不如死
And suffer.

781
01:22:38,170 --> 01:22:40,040
直到我明白
Until I realized...

782
01:22:41,310 --> 01:22:43,570
其实是你背叛了我
...it was you who betrayed me.

783
01:22:45,180 --> 01:22:46,580
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.

784
01:22:47,850 --> 01:22:50,980
所以  我只剩下一样东西
So, I had only one thing left.

785
01:22:52,990 --> 01:22:56,390
我左边臼齿里藏着的氰化物胶囊
My cyanide capsule in my back left molar.

786
01:22:56,590 --> 01:22:59,060
你还记得吧
You remember, right?

787
01:23:02,700 --> 01:23:05,220
所以我弄碎那颗牙
So I broke the tooth and...

788
01:23:05,830 --> 01:23:07,730
咬开胶囊
...bit into the capsule.

789
01:23:08,540 --> 01:23:09,760
然后...
And it...

790
01:23:13,210 --> 01:23:15,900
我的口腔都被烧坏了
It burned all my insides.

791
01:23:16,480 --> 01:23:18,140
但我活了下来
But I didn't die.

792
01:23:21,380 --> 01:23:24,080
想死都死不掉
Life clung to me like a disease.

793
01:23:28,660 --> 01:23:29,750
之后
And then...

794
01:23:30,020 --> 01:23:33,760
我明白  为什么我能活下来
I understood why I had survived.

795
01:23:36,300 --> 01:23:39,930
我要最后再注视一次你的双眼
I needed to look in your eyes one last time.

796
01:23:43,540 --> 01:23:44,970
我希望这是值得的
Well, I hope it was worth it.

797
01:23:47,680 --> 01:23:50,970
席尔瓦先生  你将被转送至贝尔马什监狱
Mr. Silva, you're going to be transferred to Belmarsh Prison

798
01:23:51,550 --> 01:23:53,950
你将会被拘留候审
where you'll be remanded in custody

799
01:23:54,080 --> 01:23:55,780
直到皇家检察署
until the Crown Prosecution Service

800
01:23:55,950 --> 01:23:57,680
认为你可以接受审讯...
deem you fit to stand trial for...

801
01:23:57,850 --> 01:23:59,950
说我的名字  说出来
Say my name. Say it.

802
01:24:00,420 --> 01:24:02,120
我的真名
My real name.

803
01:24:03,090 --> 01:24:04,680
我知道你还记得
I know you remember it.

804
01:24:06,160 --> 01:24:08,130
你的名字被刻在那座
Your name is on the memorial wall

805
01:24:08,300 --> 01:24:10,290
你炸毁的建筑的纪念墙上
of the very building you attacked.

806
01:24:11,170 --> 01:24:12,790
我会将它抹掉
I will have it struck off.

807
01:24:13,430 --> 01:24:17,730
到时  你的过去就会像未来一样一片空白
Soon your past will be as nonexistent as your future.

808
01:24:18,610 --> 01:24:20,670
我不会再见到你
I'll never see you again.

809
01:24:23,540 --> 01:24:25,480
你知道那东西有多大威力吗
Do you know what it does to you?

810
01:24:27,880 --> 01:24:29,910
氢化氰
Hydrogen cyanide?

811
01:24:42,560 --> 01:24:45,000
看看你干的好事
Look upon your work,

812
01:24:46,100 --> 01:24:47,330
妈妈
Mother.

813
01:25:25,840 --> 01:25:27,970
破解他的电脑  一有发现就告诉我
Let me know what you recover from his computer.

814
01:25:28,140 --> 01:25:29,640
看看他是否已经把名单外泄
Has he transmitted the lists?

815
01:25:29,640 --> 01:25:30,850
如果外泄了  泄露给了谁
If so, to whom?

816
01:25:30,850 --> 01:25:31,540
我要这件事尽快解决
I want this resolved.

817
01:25:31,680 --> 01:25:32,700
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.

818
01:25:39,190 --> 01:25:41,590
他叫蒂亚戈·罗德里格斯
His name is Tiago Rodriguez.

819
01:25:42,290 --> 01:25:43,760
曾经是个出色的特工
He was a brilliant agent.

820
01:25:44,760 --> 01:25:47,920
但后来他越来越出格  他攻击了中国网络
But he started operating beyond his brief, hacking the Chinese.

821
01:25:48,630 --> 01:25:51,560
当时正值香港回归  他们盯上了他
The handover was coming up and they were onto him,

822
01:25:51,560 --> 01:25:52,660
所以我把他交了出来
so I gave him up.

823
01:25:52,830 --> 01:25:55,930
换回了六个我们的特工  和平稳的回归
I got six agents in return and a peaceful transition.

824
01:25:56,340 --> 01:25:59,170
我们得走了  夫人  质询会半小时后开始
We should go, ma'am. Board of Inquiry begins in 30 minutes.

825
01:25:59,610 --> 01:26:01,670
我要知道他电脑里有什么
I want to know what's on that computer.

826
01:26:14,520 --> 01:26:16,990
这是席尔瓦的电脑
Now, looking at Silva's computer,

827
01:26:17,520 --> 01:26:21,430
看来他搞了点不一般的把戏
it seems to me he's done a number of slightly unusual things.

828
01:26:21,530 --> 01:26:23,150
他设定了故障保护协议
He's established failsafe protocols

829
01:26:23,150 --> 01:26:24,500
如果企图打开特定文件
to wipe the memory

830
01:26:24,670 --> 01:26:27,160
电脑就会自动清空内存
if there's any attempt to access certain files.

831
01:26:28,040 --> 01:26:29,420
世界上大概只有六个人
Only six people in the world

832
01:26:29,420 --> 01:26:30,700
能设计出这样的保护程序
could program safeguards like that.

833
01:26:30,870 --> 01:26:32,840
当然  你能搞定它吗
Of course there are. Can you get past them?

834
01:26:33,710 --> 01:26:35,170
这就是我发明的
I invented them.

835
01:26:38,550 --> 01:26:39,670
好了
Right, then.

836
01:26:41,350 --> 01:26:44,180
看看你都有什么  席尔瓦先生
Let's see what you've got for us, Mr. Silva.

837
01:26:46,590 --> 01:26:47,990
进去了
We're in.

838
01:26:54,430 --> 01:26:56,920
长官  这是什么东西
Sir, what do you make of this?

839
01:27:02,100 --> 01:27:03,760
这是他设计的欧米茄程序
It's his Omega site.

840
01:27:04,840 --> 01:27:06,470
最高级别的加密程序
Most encrypted level he has.

841
01:27:08,440 --> 01:27:12,140
看着像是用模糊的代码来隐藏他的真正目的
Looks like obfuscated code to conceal its true purpose.

842
01:27:13,510 --> 01:27:15,610
隐藏式保全法
Security through obscurity.

843
01:27:17,520 --> 01:27:20,040
女士们先生们  请注意
Ladies and gentlemen, if I might have order?

844
01:27:21,260 --> 01:27:22,810
质询会现在开始
I'd like to begin the proceedings.

845
01:27:25,030 --> 01:27:27,690
今天我们聚集在此讨论关乎
We're gathered today to address important issues

846
01:27:27,830 --> 01:27:30,320
未来国家安全的重要事宜
concerning the future of our national security.

847
01:27:36,440 --> 01:27:38,000
你要出去吗
Going somewhere?

848
01:27:40,470 --> 01:27:43,740
所以你相信  经过近期的危机之后
So you believe your stewardship of MI6 during the recent crisis

849
01:27:43,880 --> 01:27:45,170
你仍能胜任军情六处的管理工作
has been up to scratch?

850
01:27:45,610 --> 01:27:48,640
我相信我们已经逮捕袭击案的凶手
Well, I believe we have apprehended the responsible party

851
01:27:48,820 --> 01:27:50,510
并且会采取一切必要措施
and are taking all necessary steps

852
01:27:50,680 --> 01:27:53,350
确保关乎国家安全的敏感信息不被泄露
to ensure that the sensitive information is contained.

853
01:27:54,890 --> 01:27:56,480
做得真不错啊
so it's a job well done.

854
01:27:56,660 --> 01:27:58,320
我并不是说我们做得完美无缺  但...
I'm not saying it's gone perfectly, but...

855
01:27:58,530 --> 01:28:01,120
原谅我没给你送面锦旗
You'll forgive me for not putting up the bunting.

856
01:28:01,660 --> 01:28:03,490
我只是觉得我实在没法忽略
I find it rather difficult to overlook monumental

857
01:28:03,660 --> 01:28:05,530
如此严重的安全漏洞
security breaches and dead operatives

858
01:28:05,700 --> 01:28:08,460
还有因你的失误而死的那些特工
for which you are almost single-handedly responsible.

859
01:28:11,370 --> 01:28:13,840
他运用多形态引擎来变换代码
He's using a polymorphic engine to mutate the code.

860
01:28:14,010 --> 01:28:16,170
我一试图进入  代码就会自动改变
Whenever I try to gain access, it changes.

861
01:28:16,910 --> 01:28:19,380
就像在解一个会反击的魔方
It's like solving a Rubik's cube that's fighting back.

862
01:28:25,550 --> 01:28:26,540
停一下
Stop.

863
01:28:28,320 --> 01:28:29,690
看那里
Go in on that.

864
01:28:36,400 --> 01:28:37,390
格兰伯格
Granborough.

865
01:28:38,100 --> 01:28:39,070
格兰伯格路
Granborough Road.

866
01:28:39,070 --> 01:28:41,860
之前是大都会线上的地铁站
It's an old Tube station on the Metropolitan Line.

867
01:28:42,040 --> 01:28:43,630
已经停用多年
Been closed for years.

868
01:28:45,710 --> 01:28:47,230
从这点破解
Use that as a key.

869
01:28:58,220 --> 01:29:00,240
这是张地图
Oh, look, it's a map!

870
01:29:02,560 --> 01:29:03,580
是伦敦
It's London.

871
01:29:04,730 --> 01:29:06,990
伦敦地下网络
Subterranean London.

872
01:29:08,600 --> 01:29:10,760
怎么了  怎么门都打开了
What's going on? Why are the doors open?

873
01:29:21,310 --> 01:29:22,280
哦不
Oh, no.

874
01:29:22,380 --> 01:29:24,570
谁能告诉我他到底怎么会侵入到我们的系统
Can someone tell me how the hell he got into our system?

875
01:29:28,820 --> 01:29:30,220
可恶
Oh, shit.

876
01:29:30,380 --> 01:29:33,350
可恶可恶可恶
Oh, shit, shit, shit.

877
01:29:35,160 --> 01:29:36,280
他黑了我们的系统
He hacked us.

878
01:29:43,960 --> 01:29:45,360
不
Oh, no.

879
01:29:53,510 --> 01:29:54,700
Q
Q.

880
01:29:55,340 --> 01:29:56,540
他逃走了
He's gone.

881
01:30:06,150 --> 01:30:08,090
我在囚室下面的楼梯井
I'm in a stairwell below isolation.

882
01:30:08,460 --> 01:30:09,820
你能听到吗  Q
Do you read me, Q?

883
01:30:09,990 --> 01:30:11,480
能  我在给你定位
I can hear you. I'm looking for you.

884
01:30:22,500 --> 01:30:23,730
找到你了  开始追踪你的位置
Got you. Tracking your location.

885
01:30:24,540 --> 01:30:25,970
一直往前走
Just keep moving forward.

886
01:30:26,470 --> 01:30:28,570
从你右手边下一个检修门进去
Enter the next service door on your right.

887
01:30:35,450 --> 01:30:37,420
穿过那道门你就该进地铁隧道了
If you're through that door, you should be in the Tube.

888
01:30:38,220 --> 01:30:39,650
我进隧道了
I'm in the Tube.

889
01:30:41,320 --> 01:30:44,310
邦德  这不是逃跑  他策划了好几年
Bond, this isn't an escape. This was years in the planning.

890
01:30:44,490 --> 01:30:45,770
他故意让我们抓住他
He wanted us to capture him,

891
01:30:45,770 --> 01:30:47,050
然后让我们进入他的电脑
he wanted us to access his computer.

892
01:30:47,160 --> 01:30:48,750
一切都是计划好的
It was all planned.

893
01:30:48,860 --> 01:30:52,350
他先炸毁总部  他知道紧急预案
Blowing up HQ. Knowing the emergency protocols.

894
01:30:52,530 --> 01:30:54,190
也知道我们会搬到这里
Knowing we'd retreat down here.

895
01:30:54,670 --> 01:30:55,770
这我都知道了
I've got all that.

896
01:30:55,770 --> 01:30:58,700
我在意的是他之后的计划
It's what he's got planned next that worries me.

897
01:30:59,240 --> 01:31:00,590
那是离你最近的地铁站
District Line is the closest.

898
01:31:00,590 --> 01:31:02,270
左边有个检修门
There's a service door on your left.

899
01:31:03,840 --> 01:31:04,970
看到了
Got it.

900
01:31:08,750 --> 01:31:09,910
打不开
It won't open.

901
01:31:10,080 --> 01:31:11,280
肯定能打开  使点劲
Of course it will. Put your back into it.

902
01:31:11,420 --> 01:31:13,820
你怎么不下来使点劲
Why don't you come down here and put your back into it?

903
01:31:17,590 --> 01:31:19,180
不行  卡住了
No, it's stuck.

904
01:31:20,230 --> 01:31:22,560
这下好了  地铁来了
Oh, good. There's a train coming.

905
01:31:27,630 --> 01:31:29,400
糟糕了
Hmm. That's vexing.

906
01:31:42,550 --> 01:31:43,710
我过去了
I'm through.

907
01:31:44,590 --> 01:31:46,050
我就说可以的
Told you.

908
01:31:46,220 --> 01:31:48,150
我们触发了警报  警察就要来了
We alerted security. Police are on their way.

909
01:32:25,730 --> 01:32:26,950
你在哪里
Where are you now?

910
01:32:27,130 --> 01:32:28,360
神殿地铁站
Temple Tube station.

911
01:32:28,700 --> 01:32:30,130
和一半伦敦人挤在一起
Along with half of London.

912
01:32:34,970 --> 01:32:36,270
我看到你了
Oh, I see you. There you are.

913
01:32:36,900 --> 01:32:40,530
我知道自己在哪  Q  问题是他在哪
I know where I am, Q. Where's he?

914
01:32:40,840 --> 01:32:42,600
稍等  我在找
Give us a second. I'm looking for him.

915
01:32:42,780 --> 01:32:44,210
小心缝隙
Mind the gap.

916
01:32:51,150 --> 01:32:53,020
人太多了  我看不到他
There's too many people. I can 't see him.

917
01:32:53,290 --> 01:32:55,260
欢迎来到高峰时段的伦敦地铁站
Welcome to rush hour on the Tube.

918
01:32:55,920 --> 01:32:57,510
你没怎么体验过吧
Not something you'd know much about.

919
01:32:58,030 --> 01:33:00,080
小心缝隙
Mind the gap.

920
01:33:08,440 --> 01:33:11,130
地铁要开了  我要不要上车
The train's leaving. Do I get on the train?

921
01:33:11,770 --> 01:33:14,400
先别上去  我不确定他在不在上面  等一下
Don't get on. I'm not sure he's on it. Give us a minute.

922
01:33:17,240 --> 01:33:18,230
我到底要不要上车
Do I get on the train?

923
01:33:24,220 --> 01:33:25,180
邦德
Bond.

924
01:33:25,350 --> 01:33:27,150
-什么  -上车
-What? -Get on the train.

925
01:33:41,570 --> 01:33:42,930
他真急着回家
He's keen to get home.

926
01:33:43,840 --> 01:33:45,170
请打开门
Will you open the door, please?

927
01:33:47,840 --> 01:33:49,780
开门
Open the door.

928
01:33:52,880 --> 01:33:54,940
卫生部的  您继续
Health and Safety. Carry on.

929
01:34:01,760 --> 01:34:02,780
你在哪
Where are you?

930
01:34:03,020 --> 01:34:04,960
你猜呀  Q
Take a wild guess, Q.

931
01:34:05,390 --> 01:34:07,720
他乔装成警察了
He's in disguise, dressed as a policeman.

932
01:34:07,930 --> 01:34:09,360
当然了
Of course he is.

933
01:34:30,520 --> 01:34:33,180
他到底要去哪
Where's he going? Where's he going?

934
01:34:40,630 --> 01:34:43,390
他的目标是M  让谭纳带她离开
He's going for M. Tell Tanner. Get her out of there.

935
01:34:43,860 --> 01:34:45,050
你忽视
You've overlooked,

936
01:34:45,050 --> 01:34:47,270
或是故意忽视确凿的证据
or chosen to ignore, hard evidence

937
01:34:48,200 --> 01:34:51,030
而且自始至终  近乎固执地
and consistently, almost obstinately...

938
01:34:51,410 --> 01:34:53,700
席尔瓦逃走了  邦德在追他
Silva's escaped. Bond's in pursuit.

939
01:34:54,040 --> 01:34:56,530
我们得立即把您送到安全的地方
We need to get you to a secure location immediately.

940
01:34:56,710 --> 01:34:58,540
我现在不能就这么走掉
I'll be damned if I'm gonna show her my back.

941
01:34:59,280 --> 01:35:00,770
我们让你觉得不耐烦了吗
Are we straining your attention?

942
01:35:01,620 --> 01:35:04,680
没有  部长阁下  请您继续
No. Please, Minister, proceed.

943
01:35:12,990 --> 01:35:14,190
借过
Excuse me.

944
01:35:32,810 --> 01:35:33,800
让开
Move! Move!

945
01:36:37,440 --> 01:36:39,380
你似乎坚持以为
It's as if you insist on pretending

946
01:36:39,550 --> 01:36:41,510
我们仍处在谍战的黄金时期
we still live in a golden age of espionage

947
01:36:41,950 --> 01:36:44,470
而情报是我们唯一的资源
where human intelligence was the only resource available.

948
01:36:45,050 --> 01:36:47,320
而我认为这种过时的观念
Well, I find this rather old-fashioned belief

949
01:36:47,490 --> 01:36:49,750
导致了你那不计后果地忽视...
demonstrates a reckless disregard for...

950
01:36:49,920 --> 01:36:52,150
不好意思  部长阁下  无意打断
Excuse me, Minister, I don't mean to interrupt,

951
01:36:52,290 --> 01:36:54,350
但考虑到多方取证的原则
but just for the sake of variety,

952
01:36:54,790 --> 01:36:56,820
我们也许该听听证人的意见
might we actually hear from the witness?

953
01:36:58,870 --> 01:37:00,060
当然
Of course.

954
01:37:03,440 --> 01:37:04,530
谢谢
Thank you.

955
01:37:33,230 --> 01:37:34,960
下一枪我不会打偏  席尔瓦先生
I won't miss next time, Mr. Silva.

956
01:37:35,440 --> 01:37:38,770
不错啊  詹姆斯  对个残废来说不错了
Not bad. Not bad, James, for a physical wreck.

957
01:37:39,340 --> 01:37:41,330
谢谢
Oi. Thank you.

958
01:37:41,640 --> 01:37:42,770
你抓到我了
You caught me.

959
01:37:44,740 --> 01:37:47,610
现在得奖励你一下
Now, here's your prize.

960
01:37:47,910 --> 01:37:51,280
我们那边玩具店里的新玩具
The latest thing from my local toy store.

961
01:37:51,790 --> 01:37:53,950
叫无线电
It's called radio.

962
01:38:02,530 --> 01:38:04,220
真心希望那一下砸得不是我
I do hope that wasn't for me.

963
01:38:04,930 --> 01:38:05,960
不是
No.

964
01:38:06,700 --> 01:38:07,930
这下才是
But that is.

965
01:38:59,420 --> 01:39:00,720
主席阁下  诸位部长
Chairman, Ministers.

966
01:39:01,090 --> 01:39:03,320
今天我不止一次听到这种说法
Today I've repeatedly heard how

967
01:39:03,490 --> 01:39:05,720
说我的部门变得多么无足轻重
irrelevant my department has become.

968
01:39:05,990 --> 01:39:07,930
我们为什么还需要那些00级特工
Why do we need agents? The Double-O section?

969
01:39:08,090 --> 01:39:10,030
不是都过时了吗
Isn't it all rather quaint?

970
01:39:11,900 --> 01:39:14,660
我想是因为我看到的世界同你们不一样
Well, I suppose I see a different world than you do.

971
01:39:16,270 --> 01:39:19,400
而事实上  正是我所看到的世界令我恐惧
And the truth is that what I see frightens me.

972
01:39:21,370 --> 01:39:25,170
我恐惧的是我们的敌人不再身在明处
I'm frightened because our enemies are no longer known to us.

973
01:39:25,850 --> 01:39:27,610
他们不在地图上
They do not exist on a map.

974
01:39:27,710 --> 01:39:30,180
没有国籍  独立行动
They're not nations. They are individuals.

975
01:39:33,490 --> 01:39:35,010
看看你们周围  你们害怕的是谁
Look around you. Who do you fear?

976
01:39:36,220 --> 01:39:38,920
你能看到他们的长相  制服和旗帜吗  不能
Can you see a face? A uniform? A flag? No.

977
01:39:40,260 --> 01:39:42,420
我们生存的世界早已不再透明
Our world is not more transparent now.

978
01:39:42,600 --> 01:39:44,190
而是一片浑浊
It's more opaque.

979
01:39:44,530 --> 01:39:45,930
我们生活在阴影下
It's in the shadows.

980
01:39:47,430 --> 01:39:49,430
而我们正是在阴影下战斗
That's where we must do battle.

981
01:39:50,570 --> 01:39:53,510
请各位放下对我们的成见  扪心自问
So, before you declare us irrelevant, ask yourselves,

982
01:39:54,940 --> 01:39:57,380
你们感到安全吗
how safe do you feel?

983
01:40:01,820 --> 01:40:03,680
还有一件事
I've just one more thing to say.

984
01:40:04,150 --> 01:40:06,740
我那位已故的丈夫爱好诗歌
My late husband was a great lover of poetry.

985
01:40:07,050 --> 01:40:08,350
还有
And, um...

986
01:40:09,060 --> 01:40:12,750
我想是受到了一些耳濡目染  尽管这并非我初衷
I suppose some of it sunk in, despite my best intentions.

987
01:40:13,630 --> 01:40:16,520
而现在的情形  让我想起了
And here today I remember this,

988
01:40:16,520 --> 01:40:17,960
丁尼生的一首诗
I think from Tennyson:

989
01:40:20,430 --> 01:40:23,600
昔日开天辟地
"We are not now that strength,

990
01:40:23,900 --> 01:40:26,600
而今英勇不复
"Which in old days Moved earth and heaven;

991
01:40:28,070 --> 01:40:30,270
已成今日这般
"That which we are, we are;

992
01:40:31,110 --> 01:40:34,100
昔日雄心壮志
"One equal temper of heroic hearts,

993
01:40:34,780 --> 01:40:39,280
亦被岁月磨平
"Made weak by time and fate,

994
01:40:40,150 --> 01:40:42,120
然则猛志犹在
"But strong in will

995
01:40:42,690 --> 01:40:46,760
拼搏上下求索
"To strive, to seek, to find

996
01:40:47,090 --> 01:40:49,080
永不屈服
"And not to yield."

997
01:42:11,180 --> 01:42:12,470
快走
Go, go, go, go!

998
01:42:12,610 --> 01:42:13,580
快走
Move!

999
01:42:14,050 --> 01:42:15,540
快走  快走
Move! Go! Move!

1000
01:42:56,060 --> 01:42:59,080
007  你到底在干什么  要绑架我吗
007, what the hell are we doing? Are you kidnapping me?

1001
01:42:59,290 --> 01:43:00,920
也可以这么说吧
That would be one way of looking at it.

1002
01:43:04,060 --> 01:43:06,190
因我而死的人太多了
Too many people are dying because of me.

1003
01:43:06,500 --> 01:43:08,590
他要想对付你  就得亲自来找你
If he wants you, he'll have to come and get you.

1004
01:43:08,770 --> 01:43:11,170
我们一开始就被席尔瓦牵着鼻子走
We've been one step behind Silva from the start.

1005
01:43:11,270 --> 01:43:13,400
是时候扭转战局了
It's time to get out in front, change the game.

1006
01:43:14,410 --> 01:43:15,570
你要拿我做诱饵吗
And I'm to be the bait?

1007
01:43:18,580 --> 01:43:21,740
好吧  只有我们  不要别人
All right. But just us. No one else.

1008
01:43:23,350 --> 01:43:25,610
Q  帮我个忙
Q? I need help.

1009
01:43:25,920 --> 01:43:27,780
我在追踪你的车  你要去哪
I'm tracking the car. Where are you going?

1010
01:43:27,950 --> 01:43:29,850
我和M在一起  我们要消失
I've got M. We're about to disappear.

1011
01:43:30,390 --> 01:43:31,410
什么
What?

1012
01:43:31,690 --> 01:43:33,360
我要你留下一道足迹
I need you to lay a trail of breadcrumbs

1013
01:43:33,360 --> 01:43:35,280
确保除了席尔瓦以外没人能察觉
impossible to follow for anyone except Silva.

1014
01:43:35,290 --> 01:43:36,120
你能做到吗
Think you can do it?

1015
01:43:38,130 --> 01:43:40,100
我猜这不是官方的命令吧
I'm guessing this isn't strictly official.

1016
01:43:40,200 --> 01:43:41,290
完全不是
Not even remotely.

1017
01:43:41,630 --> 01:43:44,540
看来我的大好间谍生涯要完蛋了
So much for my promising career in espionage.

1018
01:43:53,310 --> 01:43:55,750
不管你有什么高明计划  反正我不要躲在这里  
I'm not hiding in there, if that's your brilliant plan.

1019
01:43:55,850 --> 01:43:57,540
我们换辆车
We're changing vehicles.

1020
01:43:58,420 --> 01:44:01,790
现在的公家车都有追踪器
Trouble with company cars is they have trackers.

1021
01:44:11,460 --> 01:44:14,430
这车真是太低调了
Oh, and I suppose that's completely inconspicuous.

1022
01:44:15,230 --> 01:44:16,290
上车
Get in.

1023
01:44:39,190 --> 01:44:41,020
坐着不太舒服啊
It's not very comfortable, is it?

1024
01:44:43,060 --> 01:44:45,030
你要一直抱怨吗
Are you gonna complain the whole way?

1025
01:44:45,200 --> 01:44:47,190
按吧  把我弹出去  我又不在乎
Oh, go on then, eject me. See if I care.

1026
01:44:50,500 --> 01:44:51,490
我们去哪
Where are we going?

1027
01:44:53,470 --> 01:44:54,740
回到过去
Back in time.

1028
01:44:55,840 --> 01:44:58,140
去到我们的主场
Somewhere we'll have the advantage.

1029
01:44:59,950 --> 01:45:01,350
这个界限很难把握
It's a fine line.

1030
01:45:01,510 --> 01:45:03,980
线索太模糊  他会跟丢
Make the breadcrumb too small and he might miss it.

1031
01:45:04,280 --> 01:45:06,310
要是太明显  席尔瓦又会起疑心
Too big and Silva will smell a rat.

1032
01:45:06,790 --> 01:45:09,080
但你认为就算是席尔瓦也能察觉到吗
But do you think even Silva will be able to spot that?

1033
01:45:09,860 --> 01:45:11,690
只有他能察觉到
He's the only one who could.

1034
01:45:14,130 --> 01:45:15,190
长官
Sir.

1035
01:45:18,300 --> 01:45:19,490
你们干什么呢
What are you doing?

1036
01:45:19,670 --> 01:45:20,890
我们在监视
We're just...monitoring.

1037
01:45:21,070 --> 01:45:23,660
制造虚假信号把席尔瓦引过去
Creating a false tracking signal for Silva to follow.

1038
01:45:24,600 --> 01:45:26,500
-那个  长官  -不是
-Well, sir, um... -Well, no.

1039
01:45:26,740 --> 01:45:28,600
好想法  孤立他
Excellent thinking. Get him isolated.

1040
01:45:28,780 --> 01:45:30,680
让他走A9公路  那是条直达路线
Send him on the A9. It's the direct route.

1041
01:45:30,810 --> 01:45:32,900
你能更加精确地监视他的行动
You can monitor his progress more accurately

1042
01:45:33,080 --> 01:45:34,880
用交通摄像头来确认
and confirm it with the traffic cameras.

1043
01:45:35,150 --> 01:45:37,140
可要是首相发现了怎么办
But what if the PM finds out?

1044
01:45:38,450 --> 01:45:40,040
那我们就都死定了
Then we're all buggered.

1045
01:45:40,820 --> 01:45:42,120
继续
Carry on.

1046
01:46:24,430 --> 01:46:26,230
你就是在这里长大的吗
Is this where you grew up?

1047
01:46:30,540 --> 01:46:32,370
他们过世的时候你多大
How old were you when they died?

1048
01:46:36,110 --> 01:46:38,170
你明明知道
You know the answer to that.

1049
01:46:40,510 --> 01:46:42,610
你什么都知道
You know the whole story.

1050
01:46:50,490 --> 01:46:53,080
孤儿总是特工的最佳人选
Orphans always make the best recruits.

1051
01:46:59,300 --> 01:47:00,860
暴风雨要来了
Storm's coming.

1052
01:48:00,890 --> 01:48:02,050
老天
Christ.

1053
01:48:04,700 --> 01:48:06,690
难怪你从不回来
No wonder you never came back.

1054
01:49:00,490 --> 01:49:01,890
詹姆斯
James.

1055
01:49:02,150 --> 01:49:03,880
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.

1056
01:49:04,160 --> 01:49:05,150
老天爷
Good God.

1057
01:49:06,930 --> 01:49:08,260
你还活着
Are you still alive?

1058
01:49:10,000 --> 01:49:11,730
我也很高兴见到你
It's nice to see you, too.

1059
01:49:14,130 --> 01:49:16,500
M  这是金凯德
M, this is Kincade.

1060
01:49:17,000 --> 01:49:18,800
我小时候他就是这里的猎场看守
Gamekeeper here since I was a boy.

1061
01:49:19,340 --> 01:49:20,400
很高兴见到你  爱玛
Pleased to meet you, Emma.

1062
01:49:20,570 --> 01:49:21,630
你好  金凯德先生
Mr. Kincade.

1063
01:49:23,640 --> 01:49:25,110
你来晚了  他们把这房子卖了
You're a tad late. They've sold the place,

1064
01:49:25,540 --> 01:49:26,770
他们以为你死了
when they thought you were dead.

1065
01:49:26,880 --> 01:49:28,510
看来他们错了
It seems they were wrong.

1066
01:49:29,820 --> 01:49:31,110
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?

1067
01:49:31,520 --> 01:49:33,180
有人要来杀我们
Some men are coming to kill us.

1068
01:49:34,890 --> 01:49:36,010
但我们要先杀了他
But we're gonna kill them first.

1069
01:49:38,020 --> 01:49:39,420
那我们得做好准备
Then we'd better get ready.

1070
01:49:41,830 --> 01:49:43,420
枪械室还在吗
Do we still have a gun room?

1071
01:49:47,170 --> 01:49:51,540
都卖给了爱达荷还是什么地方的一个收藏家
They sold the lot to a collector from Idaho or some such place.

1072
01:49:52,000 --> 01:49:54,100
几周前就运走了
They were shipped out weeks ago.

1073
01:49:54,670 --> 01:50:00,200
只剩下你爸的猎枪
There's just... your father's old hunting rifle.

1074
01:50:01,350 --> 01:50:03,140
我们不舍得卖
We couldn't let that go.

1075
01:50:09,160 --> 01:50:10,520
我们只有这个了
And this is what we've got.

1076
01:50:12,220 --> 01:50:15,190
采石场可能还有点炸药
There might be a couple of sticks of dynamite from the quarry.

1077
01:50:15,590 --> 01:50:17,860
但这些要是都不好用
But if all else fails,

1078
01:50:18,330 --> 01:50:22,560
有时候还是老办法最好
sometimes the old ways are the best.

1079
01:50:28,570 --> 01:50:31,070
我们的对手是谁
So who is it we're supposed to be fighting?

1080
01:50:31,440 --> 01:50:33,710
不是我们  金凯德
No "We" In it, Kincade.

1081
01:50:34,250 --> 01:50:35,800
这事跟你无关
This is not your fight.

1082
01:50:35,950 --> 01:50:39,040
来阻止我看看啊  你这自大的臭小子
Try and stop me, you jumped-up little shit.

1083
01:50:40,720 --> 01:50:44,120
想想我怎么教你的  别被顶到左边
Now, remember what I taught you. Don't let it pull to the left.

1084
01:50:45,590 --> 01:50:47,390
我尽力吧
I'll do my best.

1085
01:50:56,200 --> 01:50:58,140
你之前说你是干什么的来着
What did you say you did for a living?

1086
01:51:13,890 --> 01:51:15,150
艾玛
Emma!

1087
01:51:15,960 --> 01:51:17,550
我给你拿了点东西
I brought you some things.

1088
01:51:20,830 --> 01:51:22,920
这里晚上可冷了
The nights get cold here.

1089
01:51:23,430 --> 01:51:25,360
谢谢  金凯德先生
Thank you, Mr. Kincade.

1090
01:51:26,800 --> 01:51:27,790
这老房子真漂亮
It's a beautiful old house.

1091
01:51:27,970 --> 01:51:28,990
她是很美
She is.

1092
01:51:29,970 --> 01:51:34,870
就和那些伟大的女性一样  她也有自己的秘密
And like all great ladies, she still has her secret ways.

1093
01:51:35,410 --> 01:51:36,500
我带你看看
Let me show you this.

1094
01:51:41,810 --> 01:51:42,940
牧师洞
Priest's hole?

1095
01:51:43,250 --> 01:51:45,620
宗教改革时期的
Yeah, from Reformation times.

1096
01:51:46,150 --> 01:51:48,280
隧道一直通到荒野
The tunnel leads under the moor.

1097
01:51:48,450 --> 01:51:50,580
你一有危险就躲进这里面
If you get in danger, this is the place to come.

1098
01:51:51,290 --> 01:51:54,450
我告诉他父母过世的时候
The night I told him his parents had died,

1099
01:51:54,450 --> 01:51:56,560
他在这里面躲了两天
he hid in here for two days.

1100
01:51:59,030 --> 01:52:00,160
等到他出来的时候
When he did come out...

1101
01:52:00,870 --> 01:52:02,490
他就不再是孩子了
he wasn't a boy anymore.

1102
01:52:04,070 --> 01:52:06,260
我们开工吧
Eh. Must get on.

1103
01:54:06,730 --> 01:54:08,630
我搞砸了吧
I fucked this up, didn't I?

1104
01:54:10,360 --> 01:54:11,490
没有
No.

1105
01:54:13,430 --> 01:54:15,130
你尽了职责
You did your job.

1106
01:54:20,270 --> 01:54:21,900
我看了你写的讣告
I read your obituary of me.

1107
01:54:23,710 --> 01:54:24,800
怎么样
And?

1108
01:54:24,980 --> 01:54:26,070
真吓人
Appalling.

1109
01:54:26,950 --> 01:54:28,410
你就知道你不会喜欢
Yeah, I knew you'd hate it.

1110
01:54:30,580 --> 01:54:33,050
我把你称为"坚韧不拔的英国精神楷模"
I did call you "An exemplar of British fortitude".

1111
01:54:33,950 --> 01:54:35,580
这点算没说错吧
That bit was all right.

1112
01:54:40,830 --> 01:54:41,920
准备好了吗
You ready?

1113
01:54:42,560 --> 01:54:45,590
你还没出生我就准备好了  小子
I was ready before you were born, son.

1114
01:56:04,940 --> 01:56:06,380
苏格兰欢迎你们
Welcome to Scotland.

1115
01:57:23,290 --> 01:57:24,310
你掉了东西
You dropped something.

1116
01:57:50,850 --> 01:57:51,870
你受伤了吗
You hurt?

1117
01:57:52,790 --> 01:57:55,080
自尊心受伤了  我枪法一直不好
Only my pride. I never was a good shot.

1118
01:58:01,130 --> 01:58:02,180
他不在
He's not here.

1119
01:58:02,960 --> 01:58:04,050
他不在这里
He's not here.

1120
01:58:38,630 --> 01:58:40,430
总是喜欢高调登场
Always got to make an entrance.

1121
01:58:42,030 --> 01:58:44,060
你们两个快去厨房
You two, go to the kitchen. Now.

1122
01:59:08,260 --> 01:59:09,230
躲到拱门后面
Get behind the arch!

1123
01:59:52,740 --> 01:59:54,230
走隧道去礼拜堂
Go to the chapel. Use the tunnel.

1124
02:01:16,190 --> 02:01:20,390
都听好了  不许碰她  她是我的
Everyone, listen to me! Don't you dare touch her. She's mine.

1125
02:01:37,440 --> 02:01:38,740
你就不能让她出来打个招呼吗
Can your friend come out and say hello?

1126
02:02:46,750 --> 02:02:48,800
走吧  这边
Come on. This way.

1127
02:03:46,670 --> 02:03:48,700
我一直讨厌这个地方
I always hated this place.

1128
02:03:59,120 --> 02:04:00,550
你感觉暖和了吗
Are you getting warm?

1129
02:05:29,540 --> 02:05:31,670
找到邦德的尸体
Just make sure Bond's dead!

1130
02:05:35,080 --> 02:05:37,240
现在只剩下我和她了
Now it's me and her.

1131
02:07:35,400 --> 02:07:38,840
我们费这么大劲是为了什么  邦德先生
You see what comes of all this running around, Mr. Bond?

1132
02:07:40,040 --> 02:07:42,270
又是跑又是打
All this jumping and fighting.

1133
02:07:42,440 --> 02:07:44,310
累死人了
It's exhausting!

1134
02:07:47,510 --> 02:07:48,950
放松
Relax.

1135
02:07:50,650 --> 02:07:52,340
你要放松
You need to relax.

1136
02:08:11,200 --> 02:08:13,970
妈妈在叫我了
Ah, well... Mother's calling.

1137
02:08:15,610 --> 02:08:17,700
我会替你向她道个吻别
I'll give her a goodbye kiss for you.

1138
02:08:37,130 --> 02:08:39,150
我的天啊
Oh, my God.

1139
02:10:36,850 --> 02:10:38,680
当然了
Of course.

1140
02:10:39,150 --> 02:10:40,710
必须是在这里
It had to be here.

1141
02:10:43,150 --> 02:10:44,710
必须是这种方式
It had to be this way.

1142
02:10:46,220 --> 02:10:47,660
谢谢
Thank you.

1143
02:10:47,830 --> 02:10:49,490
-我找不到  -别动
-I can't find it no... -Don't.

1144
02:10:53,460 --> 02:10:56,020
拜托  别动
Please. Don't.

1145
02:11:11,380 --> 02:11:13,750
你受伤了  受伤了
You're hurt. You're hurt.

1146
02:11:18,060 --> 02:11:19,920
他们对你做了什么
What have they done to you?

1147
02:11:20,530 --> 02:11:22,580
他们对你做了什么
What have they done to you?

1148
02:11:55,130 --> 02:11:56,620
让我们解脱吧
Free both of us.

1149
02:11:57,130 --> 02:11:58,790
让我们解脱
Free both of us...

1150
02:12:00,160 --> 02:12:01,390
就用这一发子弹
with the same bullet.

1151
02:12:03,170 --> 02:12:04,290
开枪
Do it.

1152
02:12:04,940 --> 02:12:06,030
开枪啊
Do it.

1153
02:12:08,170 --> 02:12:09,330
只有你能做到
Only you can do it.

1154
02:12:10,170 --> 02:12:11,400
开枪
Do it.

1155
02:12:54,450 --> 02:12:56,180
我是那最后一只老鼠
Last rat standing.

1156
02:13:06,500 --> 02:13:09,470
007  你怎么这么慢
007. What took you so long?

1157
02:13:09,800 --> 02:13:12,700
我掉进深水里了
Well, I got into some deep water.

1158
02:13:28,750 --> 02:13:30,810
我想
I suppose it's...

1159
02:13:31,260 --> 02:13:33,550
现在已经来不及了吧
too late to make a run for it?

1160
02:13:39,760 --> 02:13:41,660
只要你说来得及就来得及
Well, I'm game if you are.

1161
02:13:52,110 --> 02:13:54,410
我至少做对了这一件事
I did get one thing right.

1162
02:15:21,270 --> 02:15:23,390
我都不知道还能到这上面来
I didn't even know you could come up here.

1163
02:15:24,770 --> 02:15:26,570
不想浪费这么好的景色
Hate to waste a view.

1164
02:15:26,970 --> 02:15:28,630
确实
I can see why.

1165
02:15:30,470 --> 02:15:33,310
我以为你重新调回外勤了
I thought you were going back out on active service.

1166
02:15:34,850 --> 02:15:36,610
我拒绝了
I declined.

1167
02:15:38,320 --> 02:15:39,650
你对我说过
You said it yourself,

1168
02:15:40,280 --> 02:15:41,980
不是人人都适合出外勤的
fieldwork's not for everyone.

1169
02:15:42,990 --> 02:15:45,820
如果这么说有用  我感觉安心很多
If it helps, I feel a lot safer.

1170
02:15:51,160 --> 02:15:52,990
她的遗嘱今天公布了
Her will was read today.

1171
02:15:53,970 --> 02:15:55,430
她给你留了这个
She left you this.

1172
02:16:07,710 --> 02:16:10,550
也许她是想告诉你回去做内勤
Maybe it was her way of telling you to take a desk job.

1173
02:16:11,480 --> 02:16:13,180
刚好相反
Just the opposite.

1174
02:16:16,420 --> 02:16:17,680
谢谢
Thank you.

1175
02:16:36,670 --> 02:16:39,170
我们还没正式介绍过
You know, we've never formally been introduced.

1176
02:16:42,880 --> 02:16:44,310
我叫伊芙
Well, my name's Eve.

1177
02:16:45,120 --> 02:16:46,520
伊芙·梦妮佩妮
Eve Moneypenny.

1178
02:16:47,490 --> 02:16:50,050
梦妮佩妮小姐  很期待能与你共事
Well, I look forward to our time together, Miss Moneypenny.

1179
02:16:50,590 --> 02:16:54,720
我也是  我肯定我们还能冒那么一两次险
Me, too. I'm sure we'll have one or two close shaves.

1180
02:16:57,130 --> 02:16:58,120
早安  007
Morning, 007.

1181
02:16:58,300 --> 02:16:59,320
早安  谭纳
Good morning, Tanner.

1182
02:16:59,760 --> 02:17:00,730
他在等你
He'll see you now.

1183
02:17:16,210 --> 02:17:17,480
你的胳膊怎么样了  长官
How's the arm, sir?

1184
02:17:18,220 --> 02:17:20,620
什么  没事了
What? Oh, it's fine.

1185
02:17:20,790 --> 02:17:21,980
会好起来的
It'll get better.

1186
02:17:22,150 --> 02:17:25,020
对一个坐久办公室的人来说有点太伤筋动骨了
All pretty shocking for someone unused to fieldwork.

1187
02:17:28,060 --> 02:17:31,500
那么  007  我们有很多工作要做
So, 007... Lots to be done.

1188
02:17:35,700 --> 02:17:37,600
你准备好回归了吗
Are you ready to get back to work?

1189
02:17:39,540 --> 02:17:41,600
乐意至极  M
With pleasure, M.

1190
02:17:43,870 --> 02:17:45,840
我乐意至极
With pleasure.

